Steh nicht einfach nur da. Hilf mir mit dem Baldachin.
Don't just stand there.
Give me a hand with the canopy.
ただそこに立ってないで。天蓋を開けるのを手伝って。
- Mary? Merriman? Bist du bereit?
- Mary? Merriman? Are you ready?
- Mary?
- メアリー？メリマン？準備はいい？ - メアリー？
Ja, Herr Burkett.
Yes, Mr. Burkett.
はい、バーケットさん。
Alles ist bereit, Mylady.
Everything's ready, milady.
準備はすべて整いました、お嬢様。
- Ich glaube, sie klopft. - Na, dann schau, was sie will.
- I think she's knocking.
- Well, see what she wants.
- 彼女がノックしていると思う。 - まあ、彼女が何を望んでいるか見てみよう。
Ich kann dieses elende Ding nicht öffnen.
I can't open this wretched thing.
このひどいものを開けることができません。
Ich schätze, wir sollten besser aufhören.
I suppose we'd better stop.
もうやめたほうがいいと思います。
Ich kriege dieses Oberteil nicht aus.
I can't get this top off.
このトップを脱ぐことができません。
Hallo. Alles in Ordnung?
Hello. Is everything alright?
こんにちは。大丈夫ですか？
Geht es dir gut?
Are you OK?
大丈夫ですか？
- Bin ich was? - Uns geht es gut, danke.
- Am I what?
- We're alright, thank you.
- 私は何ですか？ - 大丈夫ですよ、ありがとう。
Ist das Lady Trentham? Lady Trentham.
Is that Lady Trentham?
Lady Trentham.
あれはトレンサム夫人ですか？トレンサム夫人です。
Es ist, ähm... ich bin William McCordles Cousin, Ivor.
It's, uh...
I'm William McCordle's cousin, Ivor.
えーと…私はウィリアム・マコードルのいとこ、アイヴァーです。
- Ivor Novello. - Ja, natürlich.
- Ivor Novello.
- Yes, of course.
- アイヴァー・ノヴェロ。 - はい、もちろんです。
Darf ich einen Freund von mir aus Kalifornien vorstellen?
May I introduce a friend of mine from California?
カリフォルニアの友達を紹介してもよろしいでしょうか？
- Herr Morris Weissman. - Hallo.
- Mr. Morris Weissman.
- Hello.
- モリス・ワイスマンさん。 - こんにちは。
Hallo.
Hi.
こんにちは。
Äh, wir haben uns nur gefragt, ob wir in die gleiche Richtung gehen.
Uh, we were just wondering if we were headed in the same direction.
えっと、私たちは同じ方向に向かっているかどうか気になっていたんです。
Ich wage zu behaupten, dass das der Fall sein könnte.
I daresay we might be.
おそらくそうなるでしょう。
Also, wenn... wenn alles in Ordnung zu sein scheint...
Well, if... if everything seems to be alright...
まあ、もし...もしすべてが順調に思えるなら...
Tschüss.
Bye.
さよなら。
Können wir weitermachen, bevor ich erfriere?
Could we get on before I freeze to death?
凍死する前に乗ってもいいですか？
- War das wirklich Ivor Novello? - Ja. Können wir weitermachen?
- Was that really Ivor Novello?
- Yes. Could we get on?
- それは本当にアイヴァー・ノヴェロですか？ - はい。乗ってもいいですか？
Oh, hallo. Schönes Haus. Gefällt mir.
Oh, hello. Nice house. I like it.
ああ、こんにちは。素敵な家ですね。気に入りました。
- Oh, hallo, Ivor. - Willkommen zurück, Euer Gnaden.
- Oh, hello, Ivor.
- Welcome back, Your Ladyship.
- ああ、こんにちは、アイヴァー。 - おかえりなさいました、お嬢様。
Constance, willkommen.
Constance, welcome.
コンスタンスさん、ようこそ。
Hallo, Liebling. Wenn er mich bei meinem Vornamen nennen muss,
Hello, dear.
If he has to call me by my Christian name,
こんにちは、愛しい人。もし彼が私を洗礼名で呼ばなければならないなら、
warum kann er es nicht „Tante Constance“ nennen? why can't he make it "Aunt Constance"?
なぜ「コンスタンスおばさん」にできないのでしょうか?
Ich bin nicht das Zimmermädchen im Obergeschoss.
I'm not the upstairs maid.
私は2階のメイドではありません。
Wie ich sehe, hat er immer noch diesen widerlichen kleinen Hund.
He's still got that vile little dog, I see.
彼はまだあの意地悪な小さな犬を飼っているのですね。
Ja, die, die wir hassen, bleiben ewig. Hatten Sie eine schreckliche Reise?
Yes, the ones we hate last forever.
Did you have a horrid journey?
はい、憎むものは永遠に残ります。あなたはひどい旅をしましたか?
Ja, ziemlich schrecklich.
Yes, fairly horrid.
はい、かなりひどいです。
Fahren Sie zum Ausladen mit dem Auto nach hinten.
Take the car around the back to unload it.
車を後ろに回して荷物を降ろしてください。
Folgen Sie ihm besser. Mrs. Wilson wird sich um Sie kümmern.
You better follow it.
Mrs. Wilson will look after you.
それに従ったほうがいいですよ。ウィルソン夫人があなたの面倒を見ますよ。
Euer Gnaden.
Your Ladyship.
奥様。
- Euer Lordschaft. - Mm-hmm.
- Your Lordship.
- Mm-hmm.
- 閣下。 - ええ。
- Louisa. - Wilhelm.
- Louisa.
- William.
- ルイザ。 - ウィリアム。
Raymond, es stehen viele gute Schüsse bevor.
Raymond. Lots of good shooting coming.
レイモンド。良い撮影がたくさん来るよ。
Dafür sind wir hier.
That's what we're here for.
それが私たちがここにいる理由です。
Lassen Sie einfach alles auf einem Haufen dort um die Ecke liegen.
Just leave everything in one pile around the corner there.
角を曲がったところに、すべてをまとめて置いておきます。
Stellen Sie sicher, dass es richtig beschriftet ist. Es wird mit dem Gepäckaufzug nach oben transportiert.
Make sure it's properly labeled.
It'll go up in the luggage lift.
きちんとラベルが貼ってあることを確認してください。荷物リフトで上がります。
Das sind die Waffen. Wo ist der Waffenraum?
These are the guns.
Where's the gun room?
これが銃です。銃室はどこですか?
Dort unten rechts. Suchen Sie Mr. Strutt, den Wärter.
Down there on the right.
Find Mr. Strutt, the keeper.
右下にいます。管理人のストラットさんを探してください。
- Er wird Ihnen zeigen, was zu tun ist. - Ich weiß, was zu tun ist.
- He'll show you what to do.
- I know what to do.
- 彼が何をすべきか教えてくれるよ。 - 私は何をすべきか知っている。
Ellen, was denkst du, machst du da drüben?
Ellen, what do you think you're doing over there?
エレン、あそこで何をしているつもりですか？
Entfernen Sie den Regen von den Koffern, bevor Sie sie hochheben.
Take that rain off those cases before you take them up.
ケースを取り出す前に雨を拭き取ってください。
Das sind Mr. Novellos Taschen. Sehen Sie sie nicht?
These are Mr. Novello's bags.
Can't you see?
これらはノヴェロさんのバッグです。見えませんか？
- Wer sind Sie? - Ich bin der Mann von Herrn Weissman.
- Who are you?
- I'm Mr. Weissman's man.
- あなたは誰ですか？ - 私はワイスマン氏の部下です。
- Die Gräfin von Trentham. - Ja.
- The Countess of Trentham.
- Yes.
- トレンサム伯爵夫人。 - はい。
Stellen Sie sicher, dass sie richtig beschriftet sind. Legen Sie sie dort hin.
Make sure they're properly labeled.
Put them down there.
きちんとラベルが貼ってあるか確認して、そこに置いてください。
- Wo bin ich? - Im Stallblock bei den Pferdepflegern.
- Where am I?
- In the stable block with the grooms.
- ここはどこ？ - 厩務員たちと一緒に馬小屋にいる。
Ihre Ladyschaft ist im chinesischen Zimmer. Elsie! Elsie!
Her Ladyship is in the Chinese room.
Elsie! Elsie!
奥様は中国風の部屋にいらっしゃいます。エルシー！エルシー！
Du bist beim Oberhausmädchen. Sie zeigt dir, wo alles ist.
You'll be with the head housemaid.
She'll show you where everything is.
あなたはメイド長と一緒にいます。彼女がすべての場所を案内してくれます。
Elsie, das ist Miss Trentham.
Elsie, this is Miss Trentham.
エルシー、こちらはトレンサムさんです。
- Mrs. Wilson … Entschuldigen Sie, Ma’am … - Kümmern Sie sich bitte um sie, ja?
- Mrs. Wilson... Excuse me, ma'am...
- Take care of her, will you?
- ウィルソン夫人... すみません... - 彼女の面倒を見てもらえませんか？
Mein Name ist Mary. Mary Maceachran.
My name's Mary.
Mary Maceachran.
私の名前はメアリー。メアリー・マケアクラン。
Nicht Mary, das ist es nicht. Es ist Trentham.
Not Mary, it's not. It's Trentham.
メアリーじゃない。違う。トレンサムだ。
Lord Stockbridge, Waffen.
Lord Stockbridge, guns.
ストックブリッジ卿、銃。
- Dort unten rechts. - Mein Name ist Parks. Robert Parks.
- Down there on the right.
- The name's Parks. Robert Parks.
- 右下にいます。 - 名前はパークスです。ロバート・パークスです。
Herr Parks?
Mr. Parks?
パークスさん？
Ähm, Mr. Parks, unten an der Treppe wird man Sie als Mr. Stockbridge kennen.
Erm, Mr. Parks, below stairs you'll be known as Mr. Stockbridge.
えーと、パークスさん、階下ではストックブリッジさんとして知られています。
Ich kannte einen Mr. Parks, der in Norwich im Dienst war.
I knew a Mr. Parks who was in service in Norwich.
私はノリッジで奉仕していたパークス氏を知っていました。
- Ist er mit Ihnen verwandt? - Nein.
- Is he any relation of yours?
- No.
- 彼はあなたの親戚ですか? - いいえ。
In London geboren und aufgewachsen.
London born and bred.
ロンドン生まれロンドン育ち。
Was soll ich mit den Juwelen Ihrer Ladyschaft machen?
What should I do with Her Ladyship's jewels?
陛下の宝石はどうすればいいでしょうか？
Hier entlang. George ist für den Safe zuständig.
It's this way.
George is in charge of the safe.
こちらです。ジョージが金庫を担当しています。
Er ist der erste Diener, und man sollte darauf achten, wohin er seine Hände legt.
He's the first footman, and you wanna watch where he puts his hands.
彼は最初の従者なので、彼がどこに手を置くかに注目してください。
Sie ist neu?
She's new?
彼女は新人ですか？
Hast du die für heute Abend?
Have you got the ones for tonight?
今夜の分はもう手に入れましたか？
Oh, Entschuldigung.
Oh, sorry.
ああ、ごめんなさい。
Bringen Sie für die erste Nacht immer eine separate Kiste mit. Das erspart Ihnen Ärger.
Always bring a separate box for the first night. It saves bother.
最初の夜は必ず別の箱を持ってきてください。面倒が省けます。
Freddie, warte.
Freddie, do wait.
フレディ、待っててね。
Um Himmels willen, Mabel, was ist es diesmal?
For goodness sake, Mabel. what is it this time?
おい、メイベル。今度は何なんだ？
- Sieht mein Haar gut aus? - Es sieht gut aus.
- Does my hair look alright?
- It looks fine.
- 私の髪は大丈夫ですか？ - 大丈夫そうです。
Wo zum Teufel warst du?
Where the hell were you?
一体どこにいたんだ？
Wir sind nicht zu spät. Freddie, hör bitte auf, so weiterzumachen.
We're not late.
Freddie, do please stop going on.
遅刻してませんよ。フレディ、もうやめてください。
Isobel?
イザベル？
- Hallo. - Hallo, Isobel.
- Hello.
- Hello, Isobel.
- こんにちは。 - こんにちは、イザベル。
Liebling, wir sehen uns dort.
Darling, I'll see you in there.
ダーリン、そこで会おうね。
Es gibt da nur etwas, das ich Ihnen schon lange sagen wollte.
There's just been something
I've been meaning to say to you.
あなたに伝えたいことがあったんです。
Haben Sie, ähm... haben Sie mit Ihrem Vater gesprochen?
Have you, uh...
Have you spoken to your father?
えーと...お父さんと話しましたか？
NEIN.
No.
いいえ。
Was soll das heißen, nein? Hey, du hast es versprochen.
What do you mean, no?
Hey, you promised.
いや、どういう意味？ ねえ、約束したでしょ。
Ich habe es nie versprochen. Ich sagte, ich würde mein Bestes geben.
I never promised.
I said I'd do my best.
約束したわけではありません。最善を尽くすと言っただけです。
- Du bist so schön, wenn du mir widerstehst. - Hör auf.
- You're so beautiful when you resist me.
- Stop it.
- 私に抵抗するときの君はとても美しい。 - やめて。
Ich werde ihn heute Abend fragen.
I'll ask him tonight.
今夜彼に聞いてみます。
Na, das ist verdammt nochmal das Beste.
Well, you bloody well better.
まあ、そうしたほうがいいですよ。
Man sollte sich nicht so an Leute heranschleichen.
You shouldn't sneak up on people like that.
そんなふうに人に忍び寄るべきじゃないよ。
- Keine Sorge. Er ist ein Niemand. - Tut mir leid, Miss Isobel.
- Don't worry. He's nobody.
- Sorry, Miss Isobel.
- 心配しないでください。彼は誰でもないんです。 - 申し訳ありません、イソベルさん。
Glauben Sie, dass Sie heute Abend Gelegenheit haben werden, mit ihm zu sprechen?
Do you think you'll have a chance to speak to him tonight?
今夜彼と話す機会はあると思いますか？
- Würdest du aufhören, immer wieder davon zu reden? - Izzy, das ist alles schön und gut ...
- Would you stop going on about it?
- Izzy, that's all very well...
- もうそれについてはやめてくれないか？ - イジー、それは結構だよ...
Also, ich finde das lächerlich. Ich bin hier, um zu schießen.
Well, I think it's ridiculous.
I'm here to shoot.
まあ、それはばかげていると思います。私は撮影するためにここにいます。
Liebling, es ist eine Erleichterung für mich, neben jemandem zu sitzen, der auf einem Ohr nicht taub ist.
Darling, it's a relief to me to sit next to someone who isn't deaf in one ear.
ダーリン、片耳が聞こえない人の隣に座ると、私はほっとします。
Es tut mir Leid?
I'm sorry?
ごめんなさい？
Liebling, was meinst du mit „lass es“?
Darling, what do you mean,
"leave it"?
ダーリン、「放っておく」ってどういう意味ですか?
Nun, ich meinte nur, lass es natürlich kommen. Versuche nicht, das Gespräch zu lenken.
Well, I just meant let it come naturally.
Don't try and steer the conversation.
まあ、ただ自然に任せればいいって言ってるだけ。会話を誘導しようとしないで。
- Du klingst so verzweifelt. - Also, ich bin verdammt verzweifelt.
- It makes you sound so desperate.
- Well, I am fucking desperate.
- すごく必死に聞こえますね。 - ええ、私もすごく必死なんです。
Hallo, Raymond. Hier ist mein Schwager, Lord Stockbridge.
Hello, Raymond. This is my brother-in-law, Lord Stockbridge.
こんにちは、レイモンド。私は義理の弟、ストックブリッジ卿です。
Hallo. Ich bin Morris Weissman.
Hello.
I'm Morris Weissman.
こんにちは。モリス・ワイスマンです。
- Wer? - Morris Weissman.
- Who?
- Morris Weissman.
- 誰ですか？ - モリス・ワイスマン。
- Weissman, ja. - Hallo.
- Weissman, yes.
- Hello.
- ワイスマンさん、はい。 - こんにちは。
Oh, Elsie? Elsie, das ist Lord Stockbridges Kammerdiener.
Oh, Elsie? Elsie, this is Lord Stockbridge's valet.
ああ、エルシー？エルシー、こちらはストックブリッジ卿の従者です。
Er ist neu im Haus, also zeig ihm alles, ja?
He's new to the house, so show him around, will you?
彼はこの家に来たばかりなので、案内してあげませんか？
Sie werden mit dem Mann von Herrn Weissman teilen.
You'll be sharing with
Mr. Weissman's man.
ワイスマン氏の部下とシェアすることになります。
- Ist das Gepäck Seiner Lordschaft aufgetaucht? - Angeblich.
- Has His Lordship's luggage gone up?
- Supposedly.
- 閣下の荷物は上がってしまったのですか？ - おそらく。
Er ist im Wandteppichraum, wo auch immer der ist.
He's in the Tapestry room, wherever that is.
彼はタペストリーの部屋にいます。それがどこなのかはわかりません。
Oh, also, da sind wir schon wieder.
Oh, well, here we go again.
ああ、また始まった。
Das ist es ja. Ich habe noch nie eine Hausparty veranstaltet, nicht einmal richtig.
That's just it. I've never done a house party before, not properly.
まさにその通りです。私はこれまできちんとしたホームパーティーをしたことがありません。
Wie kam es, dass Sie als Kammerzofe einer Gräfin eingestellt wurden ...
How come you got taken on as a countess lady's maid...
どうして伯爵夫人の侍女として雇われたのか…
wenn Sie keine Erfahrung haben? if you've got no experience?
経験がない場合は？
Sie möchte mich ausbilden. Sie sagte, Erfahrung sei ihr egal.
She wants to train me.
She said she didn't care about experience.
彼女は私を訓練したいそうです。経験は気にしないと言っていました。
Sie wollte nicht dafür bezahlen, meinen Sie.
She didn't want to pay for it, you mean.
つまり、彼女はそれを支払いたくなかったということですね。
Es ist kalt hier drin.
It's cold in here.
ここは寒いですね。
Sie sollten wissen, dass Sie Ihre Wollsachen einpacken müssen, wenn Sie in dieses Haus kommen.
You should know to pack your woolies when you come to this house.
この家に来るときはウール製品を用意しておくように注意してください。
Hier sind wir.
Here we are.
ここです。
- Alles in Ordnung, Elsie? - Gut, Miss Lewis. Danke.
- Is everything alright, Elsie?
- Fine, Miss Lewis. Thanks.
- 大丈夫ですか、エルシー？ - 大丈夫です、ルイスさん。ありがとう。
Das dort ist dein Bett.
That's your bed there.
そこがあなたのベッドです。
- Das ist gut? Ja, das ist lecker. - Sehr lecker.
- That's good? Yeah, that's tasty.
- Very tasty.
- 美味しいですか？ええ、美味しいです。 - とても美味しいです。
Ich glaube, ich werde ... ich werde in die Bibliothek gehen.
I think I'll...
I shall go in the library.
図書館に行こうかな。
Hier bist du, Pip-Pip.
Here you are, Pip-Pip.
こちらです、ピップピップ。
Ich bitte um Entschuldigung, Sir. Ich dachte, ich nehme die Times einfach mit nach oben
I beg your pardon, sir. I thought
I'd just take the Times up with me
すみません、タイムズを持って行こうと思ったのですが
falls Sie es beim Anziehen lesen möchten. in case you'd like to read it when you're dressing.
服を着ているときに読みたい場合に備えて。
Danke, Probert. Pass auf Pip auf, ja?
Thank you, Probert.
Look after Pip for me, will you?
ありがとう、プロバート。ピップの面倒を見てくれる？
- Natürlich, Sir. - Guter Junge.
- Of course, sir.
- Good boy.
- もちろんです、先生。 - いい子ですね。
Ich muss in ein paar Stunden nach Kalifornien telefonieren.
I have to make a telephone call to California in a couple of hours.
数時間以内にカリフォルニアに電話をかけなければなりません。
- Ich kann kein Telefon finden. - Hier links ist eins.
- I can't find a telephone.
- There's one here on the left.
- 電話が見つかりません。 - ここの左側に電話があります。
Oh, wunderbar. Danke. Natürlich werde ich die Gebühren stornieren.
Oh, wonderful. Thank you.
Of course, I'll reverse the charges.
ああ、素晴らしい。ありがとう。もちろん、請求を取り消します。
- Ja. - Es gibt ein neues Restaurant im Strand.
- Yes.
- There's a new restaurant in the Strand.
- はい。 - ストランドに新しいレストランがあります。
Es ist ein automatisches Restaurant.
It's an automatic restaurant.
自動レストランです。
Es ist rund um die Uhr geöffnet. Sie können zu jeder Tages- und Nachtzeit hineingehen.
It's open 24 hours a day.
You can go in any time day or night.
24時間営業ですので、昼夜問わずいつでもご入店いただけます。
Also, wer ist der lustige kleine Amerikaner?
So, who's the funny little American?
それで、その面白いアメリカ人は誰ですか?
- Morris Weissman. Er ist ein Freund von Ivor. - Oh.
- Morris Weissman. He's a friend of Ivor.
- Oh.
- モリス・ワイスマン。アイヴァーの友人です。 - ああ。
Er macht Filme in Hollywood.
He makes films in Hollywood.
彼はハリウッドで映画を作っています。
Ivor fragte, ob er ihn mitbringen könne. Ich sah keinen Grund, warum nicht.
Ivor asked if he could bring him along.
I didn't see why not.
アイヴァーは彼を連れて行ってもいいかと尋ねた。なぜダメなのか私には分からなかった。
Ich dachte, er könnte sich für Waffen und Schießen interessieren.
I thought he might be interested in guns and shooting.
彼は銃や射撃に興味があるかもしれないと思いました。
Na ja, egal. Er trägt zum Glamour der Versammlung bei.
Oh, well, never mind.
He adds to the glamor of the gathering.
ああ、まあ、気にしないでください。彼は集まりに華やかさを加えてくれます。
Ich hatte nicht einmal halb so viel Exotisches erwartet.
I didn't expect anything half as exotic.
これほどエキゾチックなものは期待していませんでした。
Oh nein, nicht für mich. Du weißt, dass ich Whisky hasse.
Oh, no, not for me. You know that I hate drinking whisky.
ああ、いいえ、私には無理です。私がウイスキーを飲むのが嫌いなのはご存知でしょう。
Na los, trink es. Tut dir gut.
Go on, drink it. Do you good.
さあ、飲んでください。体にいいですよ。
Mach weiter.
Go on.
続けてください。
Ach, wirklich, Bill? Du hast so einen schlechten Einfluss.
Oh, really, Bill?
You are such a bad influence.
ああ、本当ですか、ビル？あなたは本当に悪い影響を与えています。
Geben Sie mir keine Schuld, wenn ich anfange, mich schlecht zu benehmen.
Well, don't blame me if I start misbehaving.
まあ、私が行儀が悪くなっても責めないでください。
Ich weiß nicht, wie beeindruckt Ihr Mann von unseren Hollywood-Leuten ist.
I don't know how impressed your husband is with our Hollywood folk.
あなたのご主人が私たちのハリウッドの人々にどれほど感銘を受けているかはわかりません。
Oh, du kennst Raymond. Er fühlt sich nur in Gesellschaft seinesgleichen sicher.
Oh, you know Raymond.
He only feels safe with his own kind.
ああ、レイモンドを知ってるでしょ。彼は同類と一緒にいる時だけ安心するんです。
Rechnung!
Bill!
請求書！
Ich dachte, Zofen trügen nie Schürzen.
I thought ladies' maids never wore aprons.
メイドさんはエプロンを着けないものだと思っていました。
Ihre Ladyschaft hatte früher ein französisches Dienstmädchen, das ein schwarzes Kleid wie dieses trug.
Her Ladyship used to have a French maid who wore a black one like this.
彼女の夫人は、このような黒い服を着たフランス人のメイドを雇っていました。
- Sie findet, es hat ein bisschen Stil. - Das glaube ich.
- She thinks it's got a bit of style.
- I bet she does.
- 彼女はそれがちょっとおしゃれだと思っている。 - きっとそうだと思うよ。
Und ich wette, sie hat es auch von Ihrem Lohn abgezogen.
And I bet she took it out of your wages, too.
そして彼女はあなたの給料からもそれを差し引いたに違いない。
- Sie mag es, wenn alles genau so ist, wie es ist. - Mmm, ist das nicht bei allen so?
- She likes to have everything just so.
- Mmm, don't they all?
- 彼女はすべてをきちんと整えるのが好きなんです。 - うーん、みんなそうじゃない？
- Das ist er. - Wer?
- That's him.
- Who?
- それが彼です。 - 誰ですか?
Ivor Novello.
アイヴァー・ノヴェロ。
Auf dem Weg hierher kam er heute an uns vorbei und sprach mit mir.
He passed us on the road today on his way here, and he spoke to me.
彼は今日ここに来る途中に道で私たちとすれ違い、私に話しかけました。
Nun, er hat mit Ihrer Ladyschaft gesprochen, aber ich habe geantwortet.
Well, he spoke to Her Ladyship, but I answered.
まあ、彼は女主人に話しかけましたが、私が答えました。
Ich habe es nur für Garbo ausgeschnitten. Ich bevorzuge die amerikanischen Stars.
I only cut it out for Garbo.
I prefer the American stars.
ガルボのためだけにカットしました。私はアメリカのスターの方が好きです。
- Ich finde, die haben mehr Pep. - Weiter!
- I think they've got more oomph.
- Go on!
- 彼らの方が勢いがあると思うよ。 - 続けて！
- Ist er wirklich Sir Williams Cousin? - Jep.
- Is he really Sir William's cousin?
- Yep.
- 彼は本当にウィリアム卿のいとこですか? - ええ。
Stellen Sie sich vor, Sie hätten einen Filmstar in der Familie.
Imagine having a film star in the family.
家族の中に映画スターがいると想像してみてください。
– Lady Sylvia muss begeistert sein. – Oh, das glaube ich nicht.
- Lady Sylvia must be thrilled.
- Oh, I don't think.
- シルビア夫人は大喜びでしょうね。 - ああ、そうは思わない。
Warum sollte sie das nicht sein?
Why wouldn't she be?
なぜ彼女はそうではないのでしょうか?
Weil sie eine versnobte Kuh ist. Weil sie ...
'Cause she's a snobbish cow.
'Cause she...
彼女は気取った女だから。彼女は...
Sie blickt auf jeden herab, der es mit Verstand und harter Arbeit an die Spitze geschafft hat.
She looks down on anyone who got to the top with brains and hard work.
彼女は、頭脳と努力でトップに上り詰めた人を軽蔑している。
Genauso wie sie auf ihren Mann herabblickt.
Just like she looks down on her husband.
まるで夫を見下しているようだ。
Außer wenn es an der Zeit ist, die Rechnungen zu bezahlen, und dann streckt sie ihre Hand aus, in Ordnung.
Except when it's time to foot the bills, and then she's got her hand out, alright.
ただし、請求書を支払う時だけは、彼女は手を差し伸べるのです。
- Was war denn ihre Familie? - Was hast du wirklich erwartet?
- What was her family, then?
- What'd you expect, really?
- では、彼女の家族は何だったのですか？ - 本当は何を期待していたのですか？
Hochnäsig und nutzlos. Ihr Vater war der Earl of Carton.
Toffee-nosed and useless.
Her father was the Earl of Carton.
鼻高々で役立たず。彼女の父親はカートン伯爵。
Klingt gut, nur dass er keinen Topf zum Reinpinkeln hatte.
Sounds good, except he didn't have a pot to piss in.
いいですね、でも彼には小便をする壺がなかったんです。
- Wie ist es, für sie zu arbeiten? - Sie ist schrecklich. Aber er ist...
- What's she like to work for?
- She's horrible. But he's...
- 彼女の仕事はどんな感じ？ - 彼女はひどい。でも彼は...
Ihm geht es gut. Komm, wir sollten uns besser an die Arbeit machen.
He's OK.
Come on, we better get cracking.
彼は大丈夫だ。さあ、急いで行動しよう。
- Hallo, ich bin Ivor. - Ich weiß, wer du bist.
- Hello, I'm Ivor.
- I know who you are.
- こんにちは、アイヴァーです。 - 私はあなたが誰なのか知っています。
- Mabel Nesbitt. - Hallo, Mabel.
- Mabel Nesbitt.
- Hello, Mabel.
- メイベル・ネスビット。 - こんにちは、メイベル。
- Wie geht es Ihnen? - Sehr gut, danke.
- How are you?
- Very well, thank you.
- お元気ですか？ - 非常に元気です、ありがとう。
- Oh! Ich rauche nicht. Danke. - Nein?
- Oh! I don't smoke. Thank you.
- No?
- ああ！私はタバコを吸いません。ありがとう。 - いや？
Mrs. Nesbitt hat nur ein Kleid.
Mrs. Nesbitt's only got one dress.
ネスビット夫人はドレスを1着しか持っていません。
Sie sagt, ihr Mann habe sie beim Packen gehetzt.
Says her husband rushed her when she was packing.
荷造りをしているときに夫が急かしたと彼女は言う。
Kümmern Sie sich immer um Besucher, wenn diese kein Zimmermädchen haben?
Do you always look after visitors if they haven't got a maid?
メイドさんがいない訪問者の世話をいつもしてくれるんですか？
Manchmal hilft Dorothy, aber warum Mrs. Wilson
Sometimes Dorothy helps, though why Mrs. Wilson
ドロシーが助けてくれることもあるが、なぜウィルソン夫人は
Was das Zimmermädchen dazu bringt, ist mir ein Rätsel. makes the still room maid do it beats me.
まだ部屋のメイドにそれをやらせるのは私を打ち負かす。
Ich glaube, sie tut es nur, um Mrs. Croft zu ärgern.
I think she only does it to annoy Mrs. Croft.
彼女はクロフト夫人を困らせるためだけにそうしているだけだと思います。
- Wem ist Dorothy gegenüber rechenschaftspflichtig? - Beiden. Das ist das Problem.
- Which one does Dorothy answer to?
- Both. That's the problem.
- ドロシーはどちらに答えますか? - 両方です。それが問題です。
Sie ist schon ganz außer sich. Bist du bald fertig?
She's rushed off her feet as it is.
Are you nearly done there?
彼女はすでに忙しくて足が回らない。もうすぐ終わりですか？
- Ja. - Hier ist sie ... Miss Bossy.
- Yes.
- Here she is... Miss Bossy.
- はい。 - 彼女がここにいます...ミス・ボッシー。
Sagen Sie mir, wie war Greta Garbo wirklich?
Tell me, what was Greta Garbo really like?
教えてください、グレタ・ガルボは実際どんな人だったのですか？
- Haben Sie sie kennengelernt? - Ja, das habe ich tatsächlich.
- Did you get to know her?
- Yes, I did, actually.
- 彼女と知り合いになりましたか? - ええ、実は知り合いました。
Sie kommt nächsten Monat zu mir.
She's coming to stay with me next month.
彼女は来月私のところに泊まりに来る予定です。
Sag mir, wie lange willst du noch weitermachen... und Filme machen?
Tell me, how much longer are you going to go on... making films?
教えてください、あなたはあとどれくらい映画を作り続けるつもりですか？
Ich nehme an, das hängt eher davon ab
I suppose that rather depends on
それはむしろ
wie lange das Publikum mich noch darin sehen will. how much longer the public want to see me in them.
世間が私をどれだけ長く見たいと思っているか。
Ja, es muss schwer sein zu wissen, wann es Zeit ist, das Handtuch zu werfen.
Yes, it must be hard to know when it's time to throw in the towel.
そうですね、いつ諦めるべきかを知るのは難しいでしょうね。
Schade um dein letztes. Wie hieß es noch gleich?
What a pity about that last one of yours.
What was it called?
最後のやつは残念ですね。何という名前でしたっけ？
- „Der Dodger.“ – „Der Untermieter.“
- "The Dodger."
- "The Lodger."
- 「ドジャー」 - 「下宿人」
„Der Untermieter.“
"The Lodger."
「下宿人」
Und es muss so enttäuschend sein
And it must be so disappointing
それはとても残念なことだろう
wenn etwas einfach so ein Flop ist. when something just, you know, flops like that.
何かが、ああいうふうに失敗した時。
Ja, das ist es … ziemlich enttäuschend.
Yes, it is... rather disappointing.
はい、それは…かなり残念です。
Schauen Sie sich das an. Maschinengefertigte Spitze.
Look at this. Machine-made lace.
これを見てください。機械で作られたレースです。
- Hören Sie sie an. - Also, ich hasse billige Kleidung.
- Hark at her.
- Well, I hate cheap clothes.
- 彼女の言うことを聞いて。 - まあ、私は安物の服が嫌いなんです。
Sie machen doppelte Arbeit und sehen nie so gut aus.
They're twice the work, and they never look as good.
作業は2倍かかるし、見た目も決して良くありません。
Ich werde diesen Hund eines Tages umbringen. Sieh dir das an. Überall auf seiner Weste.
I'll murder that dog one day.
Look at that. All over his waistcoat.
いつかあの犬を殺すつもりだ。あれを見て。チョッキ一面に。
Was erwarten Sie von einer Frau ohne eigene Zofe?
What do you expect from a woman without her own maid?
専属メイドのいない女性に何を期待するのですか?
Lady Lavinia sagt, eine Frau, die ohne Dienstmädchen reist, habe ihren Selbstrespekt verloren.
Lady Lavinia says a woman who travels with no maid has lost her self-respect.
ラビニア夫人は、メイドなしで旅をする女性は自尊心を失っていると言います。
- Sie nennt es "nachgeben". - Ich habe kein Dienstmädchen. Ich habe nicht nachgegeben.
- She calls it "giving in."
- I don't have a maid. I haven't given in.
- 彼女はそれを「屈服」と呼んでいます。 - 私にはメイドはいません。屈服していません。
- Das ist anders. - Warum?
- That's different.
- Why?
- それは違います。 - なぜですか?
- Wie heißen Sie? - Ich glaube, hier heiße ich Trentham.
- What's your name?
- I think here I'm called Trentham.
- お名前は何ですか？ - ここではトレンサムと呼ばれていると思います。
Nein, ich meinte deinen richtigen Namen.
No, I meant your real name.
いいえ、あなたの本名を言いたかったのです。
Oh. Mary. Mary Maceachran.
Oh. Mary.
Mary Maceachran.
ああ。メアリー。メアリー・マケアクラン。
Meine Güte! Wie nennt Ihre Ladyschaft Sie?
Blimey! What does Her Ladyship call you?
あらまあ！女主人はあなたを何と呼ぶのですか？
Nun, sie sollte mich Maceachran nennen, jetzt bin ich eine Zofe.
Well, she should call me Maceachran, now I'm a lady's maid.
まあ、彼女は私をマケアクランと呼ぶべきです。今私は女中のメイドですから。
Das sagt meine Mutter.
That's what my mother says.
それは私の母が言うことです。
Aber Ihre Ladyschaft kann es nicht aussprechen, also nennt sie mich Mary.
But Her Ladyship can't pronounce it, so she calls me Mary.
しかし、女王陛下は発音できないので、私をメアリーと呼ぶのです。
Ich mache ihr keine Vorwürfe.
I don't blame her.
私は彼女を責めません。
Sylvia...
シルビア…
Ich meine es ernst. Es darf keinen weiteren Unsinn geben.
I'm serious.
There mustn't be anymore nonsense.
本気です。これ以上ナンセンスなことはやめてください。
Ich weiß nicht, wovon Sie reden.
I don't know what you're talking about.
何を言っているのか分かりません。
- Haben Sie dieses Jahr viel gedreht? - Ziemlich viel.
- Done much shooting this year?
- Quite a lot.
- 今年はたくさん撮影しましたか？ - かなりたくさん。
- Hallo. - Geht Louisa immer mit dir aus?
- Hello.
- Does Louisa always go out with you?
- こんにちは。 - ルイザはいつもあなたと出かけますか？
- Normalerweise. - Das ist sehr nett von ihr.
- Usually.
- It's very good of her.
- たいていは。 - 彼女はとても良い人です。
- Hast du eine Minute Zeit? - Tu das nicht! Das ist schlecht für ihn!
- Do you have a minute?
- Don't do that! That's bad for him!
- ちょっと時間ありますか？ - そんなことしないで！彼にとって良くないよ！
Lass ihn runter.
Put him down.
彼を降ろしてください。
Ja. Langweilt mich zu Tode.
Yeah. Bores me stiff.
うん。本当に退屈だよ。
- Alles klar, Pip. - William ist so ein schlechter Schütze.
- Alright, Pip.
- William's such a rotten shot.
- オーケー、ピップ。 - ウィリアムは本当に射撃が下手だ。
Normalerweise versuche ich, mich davor zu drücken, besonders in Schottland.
I usually try and duck out of it, particularly in Scotland.
私は通常、特にスコットランドでは、それを避けようとします。
Ich mag Schottland ziemlich gern.
I'm rather fond of Scotland.
私はスコットランドがかなり好きです。
Also gut, machen Sie mit Ihrer Arbeit weiter. Ja?
Alright, get on with your work.
Yes?
よし、仕事を続けろ。はい？
- Ah, Mr. Weissman. Da sind Sie ja. - Ich kümmere mich darum.
- Ah, Mr. Weissman. There you are.
- I'm dealing with this.
- ああ、ワイスマンさん。そこにいたんですね。 - これに対処します。
- Was ist los, Mr. Weissman? - Also, zunächst einmal: Mein Name ist Denton.
- What is it, Mr. Weissman?
- Well, to start with, my name is Denton.
- ワイスマンさん、どうしました？ - ええと、まず、私の名前はデントンです。
- Henry Denton. - Sie sind hier als Kammerdiener von Mr. Weissman.
- Henry Denton.
- You're here as valet to Mr. Weissman.
- ヘンリー・デントン。 - あなたはワイスマン氏の従者としてここにいらっしゃいます。
Das bedeutet, dass Sie unter der Treppe als Mr. Weissman bekannt sein werden
That means you'll be known as Mr. Weissman below stairs
つまり、あなたは階下でワイスマン氏として知られることになるのです
für die Dauer Ihres Aufenthaltes. for the duration of your stay.
ご滞在期間中。
Wir halten hier an den alten Gepflogenheiten fest. Das erspart Verwirrung.
We stick to the old customs here.
It saves confusion.
ここでは古い慣習に固執しています。混乱を避けるためです。
- Es geht um die Diät von Herrn Weissman. - Ja?
- It's about Mr. Weissman's diet.
- Yes?
- ワイスマン氏の食事についてです。 - はい？
Er ist Vegetarier.
He's a vegetarian.
彼はベジタリアンです。
- Ein was? - Ein Vegetarier.
- A what?
- A vegetarian.
- 何ですか？ - ベジタリアンです。
Er isst kein Fleisch. Er isst Fisch, aber kein Fleisch.
He doesn't eat meat.
He eats fish, but not meat.
彼は肉を食べません。魚は食べますが、肉は食べません。
Also, ich nie! Isst kein Fleisch?
Well, I never!
Doesn't eat meat?
えっと、絶対食べないです！肉は食べないんですか？
Er kommt zu einer Jagdgesellschaft und isst kein Fleisch.
He's coming for a shooting party, and he doesn't eat meat.
彼は射撃パーティーに来て、肉を食べません。
Herr Weissman hat nicht die Absicht zu schießen.
Mr. Weissman doesn't intend to shoot.
ワイズマン氏は発砲するつもりはない。
Ich glaube, er möchte einfach mit ihnen rausgehen und ein bisschen frische Luft schnappen.
I think he just wants to walk out with them, get a bit of air.
彼はただ彼らと一緒に外に出て、ちょっと空気を吸いたいだけだと思う​​。
Ein bisschen frische Luft schnappen?
Get a bit of air?
ちょっと空気を吸ってみませんか？
Ja, danke. Wir kümmern uns um alles Nötige.
Yes, thank you.
We'll make the necessary arrangements.
はい、ありがとうございます。必要な手配をさせていただきます。
Jetzt schlage ich vor, dass Sie sich von einem der Bediensteten nach oben bringen lassen.
Now I suggest you get one of the servants to take you upstairs.
では、召使の一人に上階へ連れて行ってもらうことをお勧めします。
Herr Weissman ist im grünen Schlafzimmer,
Mr. Weissman is in the Green bedroom,
ワイズマン氏はグリーンの寝室にいます。
und Sie werden mit Lord Stockbridges Kammerdiener teilen … and you'll be sharing with Lord Stockbridge's valet...
そして、あなたはストックブリッジ卿の従者とシェアすることになります...
Robert Parks.
ロバート・パークス。
Er ist sehr von sich eingenommen, muss ich sagen. „Isst kein Fleisch.“
He's very full of himself, I must say.
"Doesn't eat meat."
彼はとても自信過剰だと言わざるを得ません。「肉を食べない」
Nun, nun, Mrs. Croft, wir möchten doch nicht als unkultiviert gelten, oder?
Now, now, Mrs. Croft, we don't want to be thought unsophisticated, do we?
さて、クロフトさん、私たちは素朴な人間だと思われたくないですよね？
Herr Weissman ist Amerikaner. Dort laufen die Dinge anders.
Mr. Weissman's an American.
They do things differently there.
ワイスマン氏はアメリカ人です。そこでは物事のやり方が違います。
Guter Junge. Und jetzt gib Louisa einen Kuss von mir.
Good boy.
Now, Give Louisa a kiss from me.
いい子だね。さあ、ルイザに私からのキスをあげて。
Liebling, das tut mir leid.
Darling, I'm sorry about that.
ダーリン、ごめんなさい。
Ich hätte sagen sollen, dass Morris einfach nicht schießt.
I should have said that Morris just doesn't shoot.
モリスはただ撃たないだけだと言うべきだった。
Keine Sorge. William macht nur Aufhebens. Er hat diese lächerliche Idee
Don't worry. William's just making a fuss. He has this ridiculous idea
心配しないで。ウィリアムはただ騒いでいるだけ。彼はこんな馬鹿げた考えを持っている
dass alle Amerikaner mit Waffen unter ihren Kissen schlafen. that Americans all sleep with guns under their pillows.
アメリカ人は皆、枕の下に銃を置いて寝ている。
Das tun sie, aber sie sind mehr füreinander da als für das Töten von Vögeln.
They do, but they're more for each other than for killing birds.
確かにそうだが、彼らは鳥を殺すためというよりは、お互いのためにやっているのだ。
Erinnere mich. In welcher genauen Beziehung stehen Sie zu William?
Remind me. How are you related to William exactly?
思い出してください。ウィリアムとあなたは具体的にどのような関係ですか?
Unsere Mütter waren Cousinen ersten Grades.
Our mothers were first cousins.
私たちの母親は従姉妹同士でした。
Ich glaube nicht, dass ich Williams Mutter jemals getroffen habe.
Don't believe
I ever met William's mother.
ウィリアムの母親に会ったことはないと思う。
Hat sie nicht etwas ziemlich Originelles getan?
Didn't she do something rather original?
彼女はかなり独創的なことをしたんじゃないの？
Nun, sie war Lehrerin.
Well, she was a teacher.
まあ、彼女は教師でした。
Und bei mir war es auch so.
And so was mine.
私のもそうでした。
- Das ist wunderbar, nicht wahr? - Sylvia ist so klug.
- That's marvelous, isn't it?
- Sylvia is so clever.
- それは素晴らしいですね。 - シルビアはとても賢いです。
Sie findet immer so wundervolle Diener.
She always finds such wonderful servants.
彼女はいつもそんな素晴らしい召使いを見つけます。
Ich weiß nicht, wie sie das schafft. Ich lerne gerade ein neues Dienstmädchen ein.
I don't know how she manages.
I'm breaking in a new maid.
彼女がどうやってやっているのか分からない。新しいメイドを訓練しているところ。
Ich bin davon einfach erschöpft.
I'm simply worn out with it.
もう疲れてしまったんです。
Eigentlich gibt es nichts Anstrengenderes, oder?
Actually, there's nothing more exhausting, is there?
実際、これ以上に疲れるものはないですよね？
- Ich habe keine Zofe. - Oh ... Oh, hallo.
- I don't have a lady's maid.
- Oh... Oh, hello.
- メイドさんはいません。 - ああ...ああ、こんにちは。
Ich habe der lieben Mabel gerade von meinem neuen Dienstmädchen erzählt.
I was just telling dear Mabel here about my new maid.
私はちょうどここで愛しいメイベルに私の新しいメイドについて話していました。
Ehrlich gesagt, für das, was ich für sie tun muss, sollte sie mir auch bezahlen.
Honestly, the amount I have to do for her, she should be paying me.
正直に言うと、私が彼女のためにしなければならないことの分は、彼女が私に支払うべきです。
Sie scheint ziemlich jung zu sein.
She does seem rather young.
彼女は確かにかなり若く見える。
Nun, natürlich ist sie, meine Liebe, wunderbar billig.
Well, of course, what she is, my dear, is wonderfully cheap.
まあ、もちろん、彼女は、私の愛しい人よ、驚くほど安いのです。
Mabel, wo gehst du hin? Das Zimmer ist hier entlang.
Mabel, where are you going?
The room's this way.
メイベル、どこへ行くの？部屋はこっちだよ。
Warum zum Teufel mussten Sie erwähnen, dass Sie kein Dienstmädchen haben?
Why the hell did you have to mention you don't have a maid?
メイドがいないなんて、一体なぜ言わなければならなかったんだ？
Warum um Himmels willen erwähnen Sie, dass Sie kein Dienstmädchen haben?
Why would you mention you didn't have a maid, for God's sake?
一体なぜメイドがいないと言うのですか？
Sie werden feststellen, dass die Reinigung viel einfacher ist, wenn Sie zuerst die Bäume hineinlegen.
You'd find it a lot easier to clean them if you put the trees in first.
最初に木を入れれば、掃除がずっと簡単になります。
Das wollte ich gerade tun.
I was just about to do that.
まさにそれをやろうとしていたところだった。
- Sind das die Schuhe von Herrn Novello? - Ja.
- Are these Mr. Novello's shoes?
- Yes.
- これはノヴェロさんの靴ですか？ - はい。
- Leben Sie wirklich in Hollywood? - Ja.
- Do you really live in Hollywood?
- I do.
- あなたは本当にハリウッドに住んでいるのですか？ - そうです。
Hmm. Wie bist du dorthin gekommen? Wo hast du angefangen?
Hmm. How did you get there?
Where did you start from?
うーん。どうやってそこにたどり着いたのですか？どこから始めたのですか？
Wo sonst, glauben Sie? Schottland.
Where else do you think?
Scotland.
他にどこだと思いますか？スコットランド。
Waren Sie immer im Dienst?
Were you always in service?
あなたはいつも奉仕していたのですか?
Haben Sie während Ihres Aufenthalts dort jemals daran gedacht, ins Filmgeschäft einzusteigen?
Did you ever think of trying to get into films while you were there?
在学中に映画に出演しようと思ったことはありますか？
Ich wollte einmal Schauspieler werden ... als ich klein war.
I wanted to be an actor once... when I was little.
小さい頃は俳優になりたかったんです。
Ich nehme an, die alte Mutter Trentham wird ihre Bettelschale herausholen, während sie hier ist.
I suppose old Mother Trentham will have her begging bowl out while she's here.
おそらく、老いたマザー・トレンサムはここにいる間、物乞いの鉢を出して待っているのだろう。
Sie wird Ihren Arbeitgeber mit Sicherheit nicht belästigen.
She won't be bothering your employers, that's certain.
彼女があなたの雇用主に迷惑をかけることはないでしょう、それは確かです。
Warum nicht?
Why not?
なぜだめですか？
Weil Lady Lavinia Meredith keinen Penny hat, mit dem sie sich segnen könnte.
Because Lady Lavinia Meredith hasn't got a penny to bless herself with.
レディ・ラヴィニア・メレディスには自分を祝福するお金が一銭もないからです。
Und wessen Schuld ist das?
And whose fault is that?
それは誰のせいですか?
Mit dem Kommandanten ist alles in Ordnung. Er hatte nur ein bisschen Pech.
There's nothing wrong with the commander.
He's just been a bit unfortunate.
司令官には何の問題もありません。ただちょっと運が悪かっただけです。
Ich sage mal, ich finde ihn erbärmlich.
I'll say. I think he's pathetic.
そうですね。彼は哀れだと思います。
Dann kündigen Sie doch einfach.
Then why don't you hand in your notice?
じゃあ退職届を出したらどうですか？
Nun, die anderen beiden Schwestern fielen auf ihre Füße.
Well, the other two sisters fell on their feet.
さて、他の二人の姉妹も驚きました。
Es hilft, dass sie beide gut aussehen.
It helps that they're both good-looking.
二人とも見た目が良いのも助けになります。
- Lady Sylvia ist reizend. - Finden Sie?
- Lady Sylvia's lovely.
- You think so?
- シルビア夫人は素敵ですね。 - そう思いますか？
Sie hätte es vielleicht wirklich etwas besser machen können.
She might have done a bit better for herself, really.
実際のところ、彼女は自分のためにもう少し頑張れたかもしれない。
Wie bitte? Lord Carton wollte Sir William
I beg your pardon?
Lord Carton wanted to have Sir William
すみません？カートン卿はウィリアム卿に
für einen der beiden Ältesten. Mir wurde gesagt, er hätte es sich aussuchen können. for either of the two eldest.
I was told he could have had his pick.
上の二人のどちらかに。彼は自分で選ぶことができたと言われた。
- Warum war Lord Carton so begeistert? - Was glauben Sie, warum?
- Why was Lord Carton so keen?
- Why do you think?
- カートン卿はなぜそんなに熱心だったのですか？ - なぜだと思いますか？
Wer, glauben Sie, bezahlt ihn dafür, dass er in Biarritz herumstolziert?
Who do you suppose pays for him to swan around Biarritz
ビアリッツを優雅に散策するのに誰がお金を払っていると思う？
sechs Monate im Jahr? for six months of the year?
一年のうち6か月間ですか?
Und wenn wir schon dabei sind: Wer sorgt dafür, dass Mama Trentham Strümpfe trägt und Gin isst?
Come to that, who keeps Ma Trentham in stockings and gin?
ところで、マ・トレンサムにストッキングとジンを着せているのは誰ですか?
Alte Geldsäcke, das ist wer.
Old money bags, that's who.
それは昔の金持ちたちだ。
Ich finde es abstoßend, wie sie ihn alle ausnutzen.
I think it's disgusting the way they all use him.
みんなが彼を利用するやり方はうんざりだと思う。
Keiner von ihnen ist intelligent genug, um den Preis für eine Packung Tee zu verdienen.
None of them has got the brains to make the price of a packet of tea.
彼らのうち誰も、お茶一箱分の値段を稼ぐだけの知恵を持っていない。
- Sind Sie fertig, Elsie? - Ja, Mrs. Wilson.
- Are you finished, Elsie?
- Yes, Mrs. Wilson.
- 終わりましたか、エルシー？ - はい、ウィルソンさん。
- Ich muss nur noch diesen Saum machen. - Wie ist Lord Stockbridge?
- I've just got this hem to do.
- What's Lord Stockbridge like?
- 裾上げをしなきゃいけないんだ。 - ストックブリッジ卿ってどんな人？
Er hält sich für den allmächtigen Gott. Das glauben alle.
He thinks he's God Almighty.
They all do.
彼は自分が全能の神だと思っている。みんなそう思っている。
Warum geht diese Gabel nach rechts?
Why does this fork go on the right?
このフォークはなぜ右側に行くのでしょうか?
Denn den Fisch essen sie zu zweit.
Because they eat the fish with two of them.
二人で魚を食べるからです。
- Eine in jeder Hand. - Warum ist das dann so?
- One in each hand.
- Why is that, then?
- 両手に1つずつ。 - では、それはなぜですか?
- Durchsuche mich. - Was machst du hier?
- Search me.
- What are you doing here?
- 私を捜してください。 - ここで何をしているのですか?
- Ich schaue mich nur um. - Mr. Jennings kommt gleich hoch.
- Just looking around.
- Mr. Jennings will be up in a minute.
- ただ見回っているだけです。 - ジェニングスさんはもうすぐ来ます。
Ich an deiner Stelle würde mich woanders umsehen.
If I were you,
I'd go and look around somewhere else.
もし私があなただったら、どこか他の場所に行って探してみると思います。
- Würden Sie das tun? - Genau das würde ich tun.
- Is that what you'd do?
- That's exactly what I would do.
- それがあなたならするんですか? - それがまさに私ならするでしょう。
Dann werde ich das tun.
Then that's what I'll do.
じゃあそうします。
- Irgendwas ist komisch an diesem Kerl. - Zum Beispiel sein Akzent.
- Something funny about that bloke.
- His accent for a start.
- あの男には何かおかしいところがある。 - まず第一に彼のアクセント。
- Was denkst du, ist sein Spiel? - Ich weiß es nicht.
- What do you think his game is?
- I don't know.
- 彼のゲームは何だと思いますか？ - 分かりません。
Bist du fertig? Was ist mit Lord Rupert Standish und Mr. Blond?
Are you finished? What about
Lord Rupert Standish and Mr. Blond?
もう終わりましたか？ルパート・スタンディッシュ卿とブロンド氏はどうですか？
Ihre Ladyschaft sagte, wir sollten nicht für sie liegen.
Her Ladyship said not to lay for them.
夫人は彼らに賭けないようにと言った。
Wenn sie pünktlich kommen, ist alles vorbereitet. Wir können im Handumdrehen zwei zusätzliche Plätze anlegen.
Stuff's all ready if they turn up on time.
We can stick on two extra places in a jiffy.
彼らが時間通りに来れば、準備はすべて整っています。すぐに 2 つの追加場所を確保できます。
Wenn sie ankommen, werden Sie Mr. Blond anziehen, Arthur.
When they arrive, you'll be dressing Mr. Blond, Arthur.
彼らが到着したら、あなたはブロンドさんに服を着せることになるでしょう、アーサー。
- Herr Blond? - Ja, Herr Blond.
- Mr. Blond?
- Yes, Mr. Blond.
- ブロンドさん？ - はい、ブロンドさん。
George, du bekommst Lord Rupert.
George, you'll have Lord Rupert.
ジョージ、ルパート卿があなたのところに来ますよ。
Wenn sie sehr spät kommen, können sie sich selbst umziehen,
If they're very late, they can change by themselves,
非常に遅れた場合は、自分で変更することができます。
und Sie können aufräumen, wenn sie unten sind. and you can tidy up when they're downstairs.
彼らが階下にいる間に片付けができます。
- Ist Mr. Nesbitt zufrieden? - Ich werde ihn jetzt erledigen, Sir.
- Is Mr. Nesbitt settled?
- I'll go and finish him off now, sir.
- ネスビットさんは落ち着きましたか? - 今から彼を仕留めに行きます、先生。
- Und, ähm ... Mr. Novello? - Mr. Weissmans Mann wird sich um ihn kümmern.
- And, um... Mr. Novello?
- Mr. Weissman's man will attend to him.
- それで、あの...ノヴェロさんは？ - ワイスマンさんの部下が対応します。
Richtig! Wenn Sie fertig sind,
Right! After you're finished,
そうです！終わったら、
Kommen Sie mit den Getränken zu mir ins Wohnzimmer. join me in the drawing room with the drinks.
飲み物を持って応接室に来てください。
- Was ist los mit dir? - Nichts.
- What's the matter with you?
- Nothing.
- どうしたの？ - 何でもないよ。
Nur dachte ich, ich würde Mr. Novello spielen, das ist alles.
Only I thought I'd be doing
Mr. Novello, that's all.
ただ、私はノヴェロ氏をやるつもりだっただけです。
Jetzt werden Sie ihn nicht mehr in seiner Unterhose sehen.
Now you won't get to see him in his under drawers.
これからは彼の下着姿を見ることはできなくなります。
Macht nichts. Nächstes Mal mehr Glück.
Never mind. Better luck next time.
気にしないでください。次回はもっと幸運を祈ります。
Sie sind eher ein gemischter Haufen.
They're rather a mixed bunch.
彼らはむしろ雑多な集団です。
Dieser Herr Weissman ist sehr seltsam. Anscheinend produziert er Filme.
That Mr. Weissman's very odd.
Apparently, he produces motion pictures.
ワイズマン氏はとても変わっている。どうやら彼は映画をプロデュースしているらしい。
Die Charlie Chan-Krimis. Oder führt er selbst Regie?
The Charlie Chan mysteries.
Or does he direct them?
チャーリー・チャンのミステリー。それとも彼が監督するのでしょうか?
Ich erkenne den Unterschied nie.
I never know the difference.
違いが分からない。
- Wirklich? Die gefallen mir, Mylady. - Ja... Mary.
- Really? I enjoy those, milady.
- Ye... Mary.
- 本当ですか？私はそれが好きです、お嬢様。 - ええ…メアリー。
Ich nehme an, es macht Spaß, einen Filmstar bei sich zu haben.
I suppose it's fun having a film star staying.
映画スターが泊まるのは楽しいでしょうね。
Nach der ersten Welle der Anerkennung gibt es immer so wenig zu besprechen.
There's always so little to talk about after the first flush of recognition.
最初に認識が広がった後は、話すことがほとんどありません。
Und warum hat Freddie Nesbitt seine schreckliche, gewöhnliche kleine Frau mitgebracht?
And why has Freddie Nesbitt brought that awful, common little wife of his?
そして、フレディ・ネスビットはなぜ、あのひどく平凡な小さな妻を連れてきたのでしょうか?
Ich meine, Isobel hat ihn nur gefragt, weil eine Waffe herausgefallen ist.
I mean, Isobel only asked him because a gun dropped out.
つまり、銃が落ちたからイザベルが彼に尋ねただけなのです。
Das ist keine Entschuldigung dafür, sie uns allen aufzudrängen.
That's no excuse to inflict her on us all.
それは彼女を私たち全員に押し付ける言い訳にはなりません。
Maria!
Mary!
メアリー！
Also, was gibt es Neues im Dienstbotensaal?
So, what's the gossip in the servants' hall?
それで、使用人の間での噂は何ですか?
- Hmm? - Ähm ... nichts, Mylady.
- Hmm?
- Um... nothing, milady.
- ふーむ？ - えーと…何でもありません、お嬢様。
Unsinn. Komm schon, raus damit.
Nonsense. Come on, out with it.
ナンセンスだ。さあ、言ってみろ。
Stimmt es, dass Sir William Lady Stockbridge hätte heiraten können?
Well, is it true that Sir William could have married Lady Stockbridge,
さて、ウィリアム卿がストックブリッジ夫人と結婚したというのは本当でしょうか、
wenn er gewollt hätte? if he'd wanted to?
もし彼が望んでいたなら？
Ist es das, was sie sagen?
Is that what they're saying?
彼らはそう言っているのですか？
Nur dass Lord Carton Sir William wegen eines von ihnen verfolgte,
Only that Lord Carton was after Sir William for one of them,
ただカートン卿はそのうちの一人を狙ってウィリアム卿を追っていた。
aber es war ihm egal, welches. but he didn't care which.
しかし、彼はどちらでも構わなかった。
Was würden Sie sagen, wenn ich Ihnen sagen würde ...
What would you say if I told you...
私があなたにこう言ったら何と言うでしょうか...
...sie haben Karten für ihn geschnitten?
...they cut cards for him?
...彼らは彼のためにカードを切ったのですか？
William, Lewis sagte, du wolltest mich.
William, Lewis said you wanted me.
ウィリアム、ルイスがあなたが私を欲しがっていると言っていました。
- Wer sitzt beim Abendessen neben mir? - Ach, du weißt schon.
- Who's next to me at dinner?
- Oh, you know.
- 夕食の時、私の隣に座るのは誰ですか？ - ああ、知ってるよ。
Tante Constance und Lavinia.
Aunt Constance and Lavinia.
コンスタンスおばさんとラビニア。
Warum muss ich die ganze Zeit diese verdammte Forelle essen?
Why do I have to have that bloody old trout all the time?
どうしていつもあの古いマスを食べなきゃいけないの？
Ich will Louisa.
I want Louisa.
ルイザが欲しい。
Muss ich die Rangfolge nochmal erklären?
Do I have to explain the table of precedence again?
優先順位表をもう一度説明する必要がありますか?
Der Vorrang ist mir scheißegal!
I don't give a shit about precedence!
優先順位なんて気にしないよ！
Du beschwerst dich immer, dass die Leute auf dich herabsehen,
You always complain that people look down on you,
あなたはいつも人々があなたを見下していると不平を言います、
und dann benimmst du dich wie ein Bauer. and then you behave like a peasant.
そして農民のように振る舞うのです。
Morgen früh werde ich ... im Bett frühstücken,
Now, tomorrow morning,
I'll... I'll breakfast in bed,
さて、明日の朝、私はベッドで朝食をとります。
und dann direkt in den Tweed steigen. and then get straight up into the tweeds.
そしてすぐにツイードに入ります。
- Welches Hemd hast du mitgebracht? - Ähm, das grüne mit dem rosa Streifen.
- What shirt have you brought?
- Um, the green with the pink stripe.
- 何のシャツを持ってきましたか？ - えーと、緑の地にピンクのストライプのシャツです。
Oh nein, Liebling. Nein, das ist völlig falsch.
Oh, no, dear. No, that's quite wrong.
ああ、いや、それはまったく間違っています。
Nein, immer etwas ganz Schlichtes für den Landsport.
No, always something very plain for country sports.
いいえ、田舎のスポーツでは常に非常に平凡なものになります。
Das, was ich heute anhatte, reicht aus.
The one I had on today will do.
今日着ていたもので大丈夫です。
- Aber es ist schmutzig. - Ja, du kannst es doch waschen, oder?
- But it's soiled.
- Yeah, well, you can wash it, can't you?
- でも、汚れてるよ。 - うん、まあ、洗えるよね？
Gott, ich hasse Schießen.
God, I hate shooting.
ああ、射撃は嫌いだ。
Warum muss man diese Dinge tun?
Why does one have to do these things?
なぜこんなことをしなくてはならないのでしょうか？
Hat Constance schon um Geld gebeten?
Has Constance asked for money, yet?
コンスタンスはまだお金を要求しましたか?
NEIN.
No.
いいえ。
Raymond erzählt mir, dass sie sich beschwert hat, dass ihr Taschengeld nicht ausreicht.
Raymond tells me she's been complaining that her allowance isn't big enough.
レイモンドは、彼女がお小遣いが足りないと不満を言っていると私に話しました。
Guter Gedanke, damit ganz aufzuhören.
Good mind to stop it completely.
それを完璧に止めるのは良い考えです。
- Ich dachte, es wäre für ihr ganzes Leben. - Nein, nein.
- I thought it was for her lifetime.
- No, no.
- それは彼女の一生だと思っていた。 - いいえ、違います。
- Ist das alles, Sir? - Mmm.
- Will that be all, sir?
- Mmm.
- これで全部ですか？ - うーん。
Ich wünschte, Anthony wäre nicht hier.
I do wish that Anthony wasn't here.
アンソニーがここにいなかったらよかったのに。
Sorgen Sie dafür, dass ich nicht mit ihm allein bin.
Make sure I'm not left alone with him.
彼と二人きりにならないように気をつけてください。
- Warum? - Ich ziehe mich aus seinem Plan zurück.
- Why?
- I'm pulling out of his scheme.
- なぜですか？ - 私は彼の計画から撤退します。
- Oh. Hast du es ihm gesagt? - Nein, und ich werde es auch nicht tun.
- Oh. Have you told him?
- No, and I'm not going to, either.
- ああ。彼には言いましたか？ - いいえ、私も言うつもりはありません。
Louisa sagte, ich solle es bis nächste Woche aufschieben.
Louisa said I should leave it till next week.
ルイザは来週まで残しておいた方がいいと言った。
Lass ihn in Ruhe schluchzen.
Let him sob in private.
彼を人知れず泣かせてやりなさい。
- Geh und grüß deine Mama. Mach schon. - Es liegt mir fern, Louisa zu widersprechen.
- Go, say hello to your mommy. Go on.
- Far be it from me to contradict Louisa.
- 行って、ママに挨拶して。続けて。 - ルイザに反対するなんて私には無理だ。
- Sonst noch etwas, Sir? - Holen Sie einfach Pip.
- Anything else, sir?
- Just get Pip.
- 他に何かありますか？ - ピップを連れてきてください。
- Er könnte die Treppe herunterfallen. - Wo ist er hin?
- He might fall down the stairs.
- Where is he gone?
- 階段から落ちたかもしれない。 - 彼はどこへ行ったの？
Hey, hey, komm her! Komm her.
Hey, hey, come here!
Come here.
おい、おい、こっちへ来い！こっちへ来い。
Danke, Elsie. Halte ihn fest.
Thank you, Elsie.
You keep hold of him.
ありがとう、エルシー。彼を抱きしめておいて。
- Ist alles in Ordnung? - Billiges Kleid, falsche Schuhe.
- Is everything alright?
- Cheap dress, wrong shoes.
- 大丈夫ですか？ - 安いドレス、間違った靴。
Ich mache Ziegel ohne Stroh, Mr. Probert, wirklich.
I'm making bricks without straw,
Mr. Probert, really.
プロバートさん、私は本当にわらなしでレンガを作っているんです。
Sie haben keine Haarnadeln übrig, oder?
You don't have any spare hairpins, do you?
予備のヘアピンはないんですか？
Ja. Ich versuche kurz, ins Zimmer zurückzukommen, kann es aber nicht finden.
Yeah. I'm trying to get back to the room for a second, and I can't find it.
ええ。ちょっと部屋に戻ろうとしたんですが、見つかりません。
Es ist die Treppe am Ende des Korridors.
It's the staircase at the end of the corridor.
廊下の端にある階段です。
- Oh, danke. - Ah!
- Oh, thank you.
- Ah!
- ああ、ありがとう。 - ああ！
Oh, Pip. Oh, danke, Elsie.
Oh, Pip.
Oh, thank you, Elsie.
ああ、ピップ。ああ、ありがとう、エルシー。
Danke. Oh! Du hast Haare auf deinem Kleid.
Thank you. Oh!
You've got some hair on your dress.
ありがとう。ああ！ドレスに髪の毛がついてるよ。
- Danke, Sir. - Ja.
- Thank you, sir.
- Yes.
- ありがとうございます。 - はい。
Halt die Klappe, Mabel! Zwischen mir und Isobel läuft nichts.
Shut up, Mabel! There is nothing going on between me and Isobel.
黙って、メイベル！私とイザベルの間には何も起こってない。
Kannst du mir nicht einfach die Wahrheit sagen? Du bist ein Lügner, Freddie.
Can't you just tell me the truth?
You're a liar, Freddie.
本当のことを言ってくれませんか？あなたは嘘つきです、フレディ。
- Da ist nichts... - Du bist ein Lügner!
- There is nothing...
- You are a liar!
- 何もないよ... - あなたは嘘つきだ！
Nenn mich nicht einen Lügner!
Don't you call me a liar!
私を嘘つきと呼ばないで！
Ich habe einige Nadeln von Lady Trenthams Zofe gefunden, Madam.
I found some pins, madam, from Lady Trentham's maid.
奥様、トレンサム夫人のメイドからもらったピンバッジをいくつか見つけました。
Rechts.
Right.
右。
- Wir sollten schon unten sein. - Also, mach du weiter.
- We're supposed to be downstairs already.
- Well, you go on.
- もう階下に下りているはずだよ。 - じゃあ、続けて。
Ich bin gleich unten.
I'll be down in a minute.
すぐに降りてきます。
Versuchen Sie, ihr ein respektables Aussehen zu verleihen.
Try and make her look respectable.
彼女を立派な人間に見せるよう努力してください。
Oh, danke.
Oh, thank you.
ああ、ありがとう。
Nun, ein Versuch kann nicht schaden.
Well, there's no harm in trying.
まあ、試してみるのに害はないよ。
Nun, vielen Dank, Mr. Jennings.
Well, thank you very much,
Mr. Jennings.
そうですね、ジェニングスさん、どうもありがとうございました。
- Nur Jennings, Sir. - In Ordnung.
- Just Jennings, sir.
- Alright.
- ジェニングスだけです、先生。 - 分かりました。
Nur Jennings.
Just Jennings.
ただのジェニングス。
Ach ja, ich habe übrigens einen Telefonanruf nach Kalifornien gebucht,
Oh, by the way, I've booked a telephone call to California,
ところで、カリフォルニアへの電話を予約しました。
und ich wäre Ihnen dankbar, wenn Sie mich erreichen würden, sobald es eintrifft. and I'd appreciate it if you would get me as soon as it comes through.
届き次第ご連絡いただければ幸いです。
- Sehr gut, Sir. - Danke, Jennings.
- Very good, sir.
- Thank you, Jennings.
- 非常によかったです。 - ありがとう、ジェニングス。
Sie werden nicht für Unterhaltung sorgen?
You're not gonna provide entertainment?
娯楽を提供しないんですか？
So haben Sie Ihre Einladung erhalten.
That's how you got your invitation.
そうやってあなたは招待状を受け取ったのです。
Oh nein, steh nicht auf. Bitte mach weiter.
Oh, no, don't get up. Please, go on.
ああ、起きないで。続けてください。
Sie sehen in diesem Kleid wunderschön aus, wenn ich das sagen darf.
You look lovely in that dress, if I may say so.
言ってもよろしいでしょうか、そのドレスを着てあなたは素敵に見えます。
Danke schön.
Thank you.
ありがとう。
Was ist das? Ich erkenne es nicht.
What is it? I don't recognize it.
それは何？ 分かりません。
Eine Kleinigkeit, an der ich arbeite.
A little something I'm working on.
私が取り組んでいるちょっとしたこと。
Ich kann mir nicht vorstellen, wie man jemals eine Melodie erfindet.
I can't imagine how one ever goes about inventing a tune.
一体どうやって曲を発明するのか想像もつきません。
- Wo fangen Sie an? - Das ist ziemlich schwer zu sagen.
- Where do you start?
- It's rather difficult to say.
- どこから始めますか？ - なかなか難しいですね。
Nun, ich glaube, Sie sind zu schlau für Worte.
Well, I think you're too clever for words.
まあ、あなたは言葉では言い表せないほど賢いと思います。
- Guten Abend. - Hallo.
- Good evening.
- Hello.
- こんばんは。 - こんにちは。
- Schönes Kleid. - Danke.
- Lovely dress.
- Thank you.
- 素敵なドレスですね。 - ありがとう。
Hallo.
Hi.
こんにちは。
Wie schaffen Sie es, diese Leute zu ertragen?
How do you manage to put up with these people?
どうやってこれらの人々に我慢しているのですか?
Nun, Sie vergessen, dass ich meinen Lebensunterhalt damit verdiene, mich als sie auszugeben.
Well, you forget I earn my living by impersonating them.
まあ、私が彼らの真似をして生計を立てていることを忘れているでしょう。
Kann ich Ihnen helfen?
Can I help you?
いかがなさいましたか？
Wissen Sie, mir gefällt Ihre Arbeitsweise wirklich, Mr. Jennings.
You know, I really enjoy the way you do things, Mr. Jennings.
ジェニングスさん、あなたのやり方は本当に気に入っています。
Wie bitte?
I beg your pardon?
何とおっしゃいましたか？
- Was ist los, Henry? - Nichts.
- What is it, Henry?
- Nothing.
- ヘンリー、どうしたの？ - 何でもないよ。
Ich wollte nur sicher sein, dass Sie alles haben, was Sie brauchen, Sir.
I just wanted to be sure you had everything you need, sir.
必要なものがすべて揃っているかどうか確認したかっただけです、旦那様。
Ja, das tue ich. Danke.
Yes, I do. Thank you.
はい、そうです。ありがとうございます。
Es ist wunderbar, einen Diener zu finden, der wirklich Interesse zeigt.
It's wonderful to find a servant who really shows an interest.
本当に興味を示してくれる使用人を見つけるのは素晴らしいことです。
- Finden Sie nicht? - Sir.
- Don't you think?
- Sir.
- そう思いませんか？ - 先生。
Kommt, Mädels. Setzt euch. Macht's gut, wir haben 20 Minuten.
Come on, girls. Sit down.
Tuck in, we've got 20 minutes.
さあ、女の子たち。座って、ご飯を食べなさい。あと20分あります。
Schlurfen Sie weiter. Da kommt er.
Shuffle along. Here he comes.
よろよろ歩いてください。彼が来ます。
- Alles zufriedenstellend, Mr. Jennings? - Ja, danke, Dorothy.
- Everything satisfactory, Mr. Jennings?
- Yes, thank you, Dorothy.
- すべて満足ですか、ジェニングスさん？ - はい、ありがとう、ドロシー。
Sie haben ihre Getränke. Ich denke, wir können alle nehmen
They have their drinks.
I think we can all take
飲み物はみんな飲んでるよ。みんなで飲んでもいいと思う
unsere Freizeit für etwa eine halbe Stunde. our leisure for half an hour or so.
30分ほどの自由時間です。
Was ist das?
What's this?
これは何ですか？
Ich glaube, das ist mein Platz, Mr. Jennings.
I believe this is my place,
Mr. Jennings.
ここが私の居場所だと信じています、ジェニングスさん。
Oh ... und seit wann steht eine Baronin im Rang über einer Gräfin?
Oh... and since when did a baroness outrank a countess?
ああ...いつから男爵夫人が伯爵夫人より地位が高くなったのですか?
Miss Trentham, würden Sie bitte den Ehrenplatz einnehmen?
Miss Trentham, would you take the place of honor, please?
トレンサムさん、名誉ある席に着いていただけますか？
Fräulein Trentham?
Miss Trentham?
トレンサムさん？
Mir geht es gut, Mr. Jennings. Danke.
I'm alright here,
Mr. Jennings. Thank you.
大丈夫ですよ、ジェニングスさん。ありがとう。
Los, lass ihn nicht warten.
Go on. Don't keep him waiting.
続けてください。彼を待たせないでください。
Ah, Miss Meredith. Würden Sie bitte zu mir kommen und sich links neben mich setzen?
Ah, Miss Meredith.
Would you come and sit on my left?
ああ、メレディスさん。私の左側に座っていただけますか？
Natürlich bin ich nichts, wenn Besuch im Haus ist.
Naturally, I'm nothing when there are visitors in the house.
当然ですが、家にお客さんがいるときは私は何者でもありません。
- Macht nichts, ich bin daran gewöhnt. - Guten Abend, Mrs. Wilson.
- Never mind, I'm used to it.
- Good evening, Mrs. Wilson.
- 気にしないでください。慣れています。 - こんばんは、ウィルソンさん。
Guten Abend.
Good evening.
こんばんは。
Möge der Herr uns für das, was wir erhalten werden, wahrhaft dankbar machen.
For what we are about to receive, may the Lord make us truly thankful.
私たちがこれから受け取るものに対して、主が私たちに心から感謝させてくださいますように。
Richtig! Fangen Sie an, sobald Sie es bekommen. Keine Zeit zum Herumtrödeln.
Right! Start when you get it.
No time for loitering.
そうです！ 理解したら始めましょう。 ぶらぶらしている時間はありません。
Ich serviere heute Abend doch nicht, Mr. Jennings, oder?
I'm not serving tonight,
Mr. Jennings, am I?
ジェニングスさん、私は今夜は勤務しませんよね？
Nicht heute Abend, Elsie, aber wahrscheinlich morgen.
Not tonight, Elsie, but probably tomorrow.
今夜ではないよ、エルシー、でもおそらく明日だ。
- Wo ist Mrs. Croft? - Isst immer mit ihrem eigenen Personal.
- Where is Mrs. Croft?
- Always eats with her own staff.
- クロフト夫人はどこにいますか? - いつも自分のスタッフと一緒に食事をします。
Nimmt sie ihren Pudding mit auf Mrs. Wilsons Zimmer? Das macht unsere Köchin.
Does she take her pudding to Mrs. Wilson's room? Our cook does that.
彼女はプリンをウィルソン夫人の部屋に持っていくのですか? うちの料理人がそうします。
Keine Chance. Sie hassen sich gegenseitig.
Fat chance. They hate each other.
そんなわけない。彼らはお互いを憎んでいる。
- Darf ich eine Frage stellen? - Natürlich, Herr Weissman.
- Can I ask a question?
- Certainly, Mr. Weissman.
- 質問してもいいですか? - もちろんです、ワイスマンさん。
Und wie können wir Ihnen helfen?
And how can we help you?
どのようにお手伝いできますか?
Ich habe mich nur gefragt, wie viele Leute hier Eltern im Dienst hatten?
I just wondered, how many people here had parents in service?
ちょっと気になったんですが、ここにいる人のうち、親が軍隊にいた人は何人いるんですか？
Und war das der Grund, warum sie sich dafür entschieden haben?
And was that why they chose to go into it?
そして、それが彼らがそれに入ることを選んだ理由ですか?
Was für eine interessante Frage,
What an interesting question,
興味深い質問ですね。
und eine, ähm, auf die ich, fürchte ich, keine Antwort geben kann. and one, um, to which, I'm afraid,
I cannot provide the answer.
そして、うーん、残念ながら、私には答えることができない質問が 1 つあります。
Alle, deren Eltern im Dienst waren, heben die Hand.
All of you whose parents were in service, raise your hand.
両親が軍務に就いていた人、手を挙げてください。
- Mein Vater war. - Beides ... Kindermädchen und Bräutigam.
- My father was.
- Both... nanny and groom.
- 私の父はそうでした。 - 乳母と花婿の両方でした。
- Nicht Sie, Dorothy? - Mein Vater war Bauer, Mr. Jennings.
- Not you, Dorothy?
- My father was a farmer, Mr. Jennings.
- ドロシー、君じゃないの？ - 私の父は農家だったんだよ、ジェニングスさん。
Ein Pächter von Lord Carton.
A tenant of Lord Carton's.
カートン卿の借家人。
- Mr. Meredith? - Fabrikarbeiter, beide.
- Mr. Meredith?
- Factory hands, both of them.
- メレディスさん？ - 二人とも工場労働者です。
Und wenn Sie mich fragen, ging es ihnen besser.
And if you ask me, they were better off.
そして私に言わせれば、彼らの方が幸せだった。
Was ist mit Ihnen, Mr. Stockbridge?
What about you, Mr. Stockbridge?
あなたはどうですか、ストックブリッジさん？
Was ist los? Weißt du es nicht?
What's the matter?
Don't you know?
どうしたの？知らないの？
Ja, ich weiß, was sie getan haben.
Yeah, I know what they did.
ええ、彼らが何をしたかは知っています。
Aber es hatte keinerlei Auswirkungen auf mich oder meine Berufswahl.
But it didn't have any effect on me or my choice of work.
しかし、それは私や私の仕事の選択に何の影響も与えませんでした。
- Und warum ist das so? - Weil ich in einem Waisenhaus aufgewachsen bin.
- And why's that?
- Because I grew up in an orphanage.
- それはなぜですか？ - 私は孤児院で育ったからです。
Vielen Dank, Herr Weissman,
Thank you, Mr. Weissman,
ありがとう、ワイスマンさん。
dafür, dass Sie uns allen etwas zum Nachdenken gegeben haben. for giving us all a little something to think about.
私たち全員に少し考えさせてくれるものを与えてくれてありがとう。
Oh, Ihre Ladyschaft.
Oh, Her Ladyship.
ああ、女主人様。
Oh, es tut mir so leid, Sie zu stören.
Oh, I'm so sorry to disturb you.
ああ、邪魔してすみません。
Bitte setzen Sie sich und essen Sie Ihr Abendessen zu Ende.
Please, do sit down and finish your supper.
どうぞ座って夕食をお召し上がりください。
Frau Wilson, es ist eine große Krise entstanden. Ich habe gerade erfahren,
Mrs. Wilson, a major crisis has arisen.
I have just found out
ウィルソンさん、大きな危機が起こっています。私は今、
dass Herr Weissman kein Fleisch isst und ich nicht weiß, was ich tun soll. that Mr. Weissman won't eat meat, and I don't know what to do.
ワイズマンさんは肉を食べないので、どうしたらいいのかわかりません。
Ich kann es Mrs. Croft nicht sagen. Ich traue mich einfach nicht.
I can't tell Mrs. Croft.
I simply don't dare.
クロフト夫人には言えません。勇気がないんです。
Alles ist unter Kontrolle, Euer Ladyschaft.
Everything's under control,
Your Ladyship.
すべては順調です、お嬢様。
Der Diener von Herrn Weissman teilte uns gleich nach seiner Ankunft mit,
Mr. Weissman's valet informed us as soon as he arrived,
ワイズマン氏の従者は到着するとすぐに私たちに知らせた。
deshalb haben wir eine besondere Version der Suppe zubereitet. so we've prepared a special version of the soup.
そこで、特別バージョンのスープを用意しました。
Er kann den Fisch und die Vorspeisen essen,
He can eat the fish and the hors d'oeuvres,
彼は魚やオードブルを食べることができます、
und als Wildgericht gibt es ein Welsh Rarebit. and we'll have a Welsh rarebit for the game course.
ゲームコースにはウェルシュ・レアビットを用意します。
Ich weiß noch nichts über die Vorspeise, aber uns wird schon etwas einfallen.
I don't know about the entree, but we'll think of something.
メインディッシュについては分かりませんが、何か考えます。
Vielen Dank, Mrs. Wilson. Wie immer zehn Schritte voraus.
Thank you, Mrs. Wilson.
Ten steps ahead as usual.
ありがとう、ウィルソンさん。いつものように10歩先を進んでいます。
Wer von Ihnen ist Mr. Weissmans Kammerdiener?
Which one of you is Mr. Weissman's valet?
あなたたちのうち誰がワイスマン氏の従者ですか?
Das bin ich, Euer Gnaden.
I am, Your Ladyship.
はい、女将様。
Bist du das wirklich? Ja, Himmel.
Are you, indeed? Yes, heavens.
本当にそうでしょうか？ ええ、そうです。
Ähm, danke für Ihre … Effizienz.
Um, thank you for your... efficiency.
えーと、あなたの...効率の良さに感謝します。
- Dann sind Sie fertig. - Ja, George?
- You're all set, then.
- Yes, George?
- それで準備は完了です。 - はい、ジョージ？
Nichts, Sir.
Nothing, sir.
何もございません。
Das will ich hoffen. Ich habe großen Hunger.
I should hope not.
I'm very hungry.
そうではないことを祈ります。とてもお腹が空いています。
Ich habe mich gefragt, William,
I was, uh, wondering, William,
ウィリアム、私は疑問に思っていたんだ
wenn ich nach dem Abendessen kurz mit Ihnen allein sprechen könnte. if I could have a word with you alone after dinner.
夕食後にあなたと二人きりで少しお話ができればと思います。
Ich kann meine Gäste doch nicht allein lassen, oder?
I can't leave my guests, can I?
ゲストを置いていくわけにはいかないですよね？
Du machst den Hund krank.
You'll make that dog sick.
その犬は病気になってしまうよ。
Isobel, wusstest du, dass William und ich
Isobel, did you know that William and I
イザベル、ウィリアムと私が
gehen Sie gemeinsam in den Sudan? are going into business together in the Sudan?
スーダンで一緒にビジネスを始めませんか?
- Nein, das wusste ich nicht. - Es ist ziemlich aufregend. Ähm ...
- No, I didn't know that.
- It's quite exciting. Erm...
- いいえ、知りませんでした。 - かなり興奮しています。えーと...
Was passiert ist, ist anscheinend
What's happened is, apparently,
どうやら何が起こったかというと、
Es gibt Hunderte und Aberhunderte einheimischer sudanesischer Soldaten, there are hundreds and hundreds of Sudanese native soldiers,
何百人ものスーダン人兵士がいて、
ganze Regimenter zogen durch die Wüste, entire regiments wandering around the desert,
連隊全体が砂漠をさまよい、
wohl oder übel, ohne etwas an den Füßen, willy-nilly, without anything on their feet,
足元に何も履かずに、
was, wie ich mir vorstelle, einige Schwierigkeiten mit sich bringt. which causes some hardship,
I imagine.
それは多少の困難を伴うと思います。
Nein, ich bin in Leicester aufgewachsen.
No, I grew up in Leicester.
いいえ、私はレスターで育ちました。
- Mein Vater hatte eine Handschuhfabrik. - Wirklich?
- My father had a glove factory.
- Really?
- 私の父は手袋工場を経営していました。 - 本当ですか?
Eines weiß ich: wie ein Handschuh sitzen sollte.
One thing I do know is how a glove should fit.
私が知っていることの一つは、手袋がどのようにフィットするべきかということです。
Wirklich, Liebling. Du langweilst den armen Mr. Novello zu Tode.
Really, darling. You're boring poor Mr. Novello to death.
本当に、ダーリン。あなたはかわいそうなノヴェロ氏を死ぬほど退屈させているわ。
NEIN!
No!
いいえ！
Ich denke, er wird mir alles erklären,
I think he will explain everything to me,
彼は私に全てを説明してくれると思う、
und mir zeigen, wie das alles funktioniert. and kind of show me how it all works.
そして、それがどのように機能するかを私に見せてくれるのです。
Auf meinem Bild wird es eine Fasanenjagd geben.
There's gonna be a pheasant hunt in my picture.
私の絵にはキジ狩りが描かれる予定です。
Es gibt einen großen Markt für die Modernisierung der Armeen im Sudan,
There's a large market in modernizing the armies in the Sudan,
スーダンには軍隊の近代化に大きな市場がある。
und sie mit Stiefeln auszustatten. and providing them with boots.
そして彼らにブーツを提供します。
Und dann hat die alte Schachtel es einfach allen Bediensteten serviert.
And then the old bag just served it to all the servants.
そして、その老婆はそれを召使全員に配ったのです。
Ich konnte es nicht glauben.
I couldn't believe it.
信じられませんでした。
- Ist dir nicht kalt? - Es ist besser als diese Küche.
- Aren't you cold?
- It's better than that kitchen.
- 寒くないですか？ - あのキッチンよりはいいですよ。
Hier. Ich dachte, das könnte dir gut tun.
Here. I thought you could do with this.
ほら。これでいいと思ったんだ。
Oh, das ist nett, Liebling.
Oh, that's kind, love.
ああ、それは優しいですね、愛しい人。
- Elsie, hallo. - Guten Abend, Euer Lordschaft.
- Elsie, hello.
- Good evening, Your Lordship.
- エルシー、こんにちは。 - こんばんは、閣下。
Wir haben Taschen und Waffen und alles und keinen Mann.
We've got bags and guns and everything and no man.
バッグも銃も全部持ってるけど、男がいない。
Wirst du das für mich klären?
Will you sort it out for me?
私のためにそれを整理してくれますか？
- Natürlich, Euer Lordschaft. - Danke.
- Of course, Your Lordship.
- Thank you.
- もちろんです、閣下。 - ありがとうございます。
- Wir holen Ihr Gepäck, Sir. - Danke. Das ist sehr nett von Ihnen.
- We'll get your bags, sir.
- Thank you. That's very kind of you.
- 荷物をお預かりいたします。 - ありがとうございます。とても親切ですね。
Guten Abend.
Good evening.
こんばんは。
Stimmt. Im Kofferraum, oder?
Right. In the boot, is it?
そうです。トランクの中ですか？
Entschuldigen Sie, kann ich Sie bitte um Feuer bitten?
Sorry, can I trouble you for a light, please?
すみませんが、火を貸してもらってもいいですか？
- Hast du die Tasche? - Ja.
- You got that bag?
- Yeah.
- そのバッグを持ってる？ - うん。
Danke. Guten Abend.
Thank you.
Good evening.
ありがとう。こんばんは。
Glauben Sie, er verliert das Interesse an dieser Sache?
You think he's losing interest in that thing?
彼はそのことに興味を失っていると思いますか？
Nun, nicht nur das. Das ganze Imperium.
Well, not just that.
The whole Empire.
まあ、それだけではありません。帝国全体です。
Ich glaube, er sagte, ihm sei die Puste ausgegangen.
I think he said the steam's gone out of it.
蒸気が消えたと彼は言ったと思います。
Wilhelm?
William?
ウィリアム？
Das stimmt doch nicht, oder? Sie glauben, das Imperium sei am Ende?
That's not true, is it, that you think the Empire's finished?
帝国は終わったと思っているというのは本当ではないですか?
Ich ww-was?
I w-w-what?
えっと…何ですか?
Nun, nach dem Krieg war das Imperium am Ende.
Well, the Empire was finished after the war.
まあ、戦争後、帝国は終わりました。
Nun, wegen des Krieges. Er hat alles verändert.
Well, because of the war.
It changed everything.
そうです、戦争のせいです。戦争ですべてが変わりました。
Empire Leicester Square?
エンパイア・レスター・スクエア？
Nun, es ist mir egal, was sich geändert hat oder nicht.
Well, I don't care what's changed or not changed.
まあ、何が変わったか、何が変わっていないかは気にしません。
Solange unseren Söhnen das erspart bleibt, was Sie alle durchmachen mussten.
As long as our sons are spared what you all went through.
私たちの息子たちが、あなた方が経験したような苦しみから逃れられる限りは。
Oh, nicht alle. Du hast doch nicht gekämpft, William, oder?
Oh, not all.
You didn't fight, did you, William?
ああ、全部じゃないよ。ウィリアム、戦わなかったんだね？
Ich habe meinen Teil getan.
I did my bit.
私は自分の役割を果たしました。
Nun, Sie haben viel Geld verdient, aber es ist nicht ganz dasselbe
Well, you made a lot of money, but it's not quite the same thing
まあ、あなたはたくさんのお金を稼いだが、それは同じことではない
als würde man in die Mündung der Kanone stürmen, oder? as charging into the cannon's mouth, now, is it?
まるで大砲の口に突撃しているかのようですよね？
Gott sei Dank für Raymond. Wenigstens hatte die Familie einen Vertreter an vorderster Front.
Thank God for Raymond. At least the family had one representative in the front line.
レイモンドがいたおかげで、少なくとも家族には最前線に代表者が一人いた。
Raymond, sagen Sie ihnen, wie oft Sie in den Berichten erwähnt wurden.
Raymond, tell them how many times you were mentioned in dispatches.
レイモンド、あなたが何回特派員に言及されたか伝えてください。
- Ich vergesse es. - Nein, tust du nicht. Komm schon.
- I forget.
- No, you don't. Come on.
- 忘れてるよ。 - いや、忘れてないよ。さあ。
- Ist er bescheiden? - Ja, er ist sehr bescheiden.
- Is he being modest?
- Yes, he's being very modest.
- 彼は謙虚ですか？ - はい、とても謙虚です。
Was denkst du, was du hier machst?
What do you think you're doing here?
ここで何をしているつもりですか?
Mrs. Wilson hat mich gebeten, Ihnen mitzuteilen, dass die anderen angekommen sind.
Mrs. Wilson asked me to tell you that the others have arrived.
ウィルソン夫人が、他の人たちが到着したことをあなたに伝えるように私に頼みました。
Gut.
Good.
良い。
Lord Rupert Standish und Mr. Blond sind hier, Mylady.
Lord Rupert Standish and Mr. Blond are here, milady.
ルパート・スタンディッシュ卿とブロンド氏が来ております、お嬢様。
Sie können sich im Billardzimmer ein Tablett holen.
They can have a tray in the billiard room.
ビリヤードルームにトレイを置くことができます。
- Sie können später zu uns stoßen. - Sehr gut, Mylady.
- They can join us later.
- Very good, milady.
- 彼らは後で合流できます。 - 結構です、お嬢様。
- Ist Rupert hier? - Ja.
- Is Rupert here?
- Yes.
- ルパートはここにいますか? - はい。
- Soll ich hingehen und Hallo sagen? - Nein, ich glaube nicht.
- Shall I go and say hello?
- No, I don't think so.
- 挨拶に行ってもいいですか？ - いいえ、そうは思いません。
Seien Sie ehrlich, Sie sind der jüngere Sohn,
Face it, you're a younger son,
認めなさい、あなたは年下の息子です、
mit dem Geschmack eines Marquis und dem Einkommen eines Pfarrers. with the taste of marquess and the income of a vicar.
侯爵の趣味と牧師の収入を持ちます。
Ihre Mutter mag dich. Sie auch.
Her mother likes you.
She does, too.
彼女のお母さんもあなたのことが好きなんです。彼女もそうです。
Ich weiß, sie ist nicht gerade ein echter Hingucker …
Now, I know she's not exactly a show-stopper...
さて、彼女がまさにショーストッパーではないことはわかっています...
- Ihr Vater ist von der Idee nicht begeistert. - Er wird schon noch umdenken.
- Her father's not keen on the idea.
- He'll come around.
- 彼女の父親はその考えに乗り気ではない。 - 彼も賛成するだろう。
„Haben Sie meine Tochter, Lady Rupert Standish, kennengelernt?“
"Met my daughter,
Lady Rupert Standish?"
「私の娘、ルパート・スタンディッシュ夫人に会った？」
Er glaubt, es geht mir nur ums Geld.
He thinks I'm in it for the money.
彼は私が金のためにやっていると思っている。
Natürlich tut er das. Aber davon dürfen Sie sich nicht abschrecken lassen.
Of course he does.
But you can't let that put you off.
もちろんそうでしょう。しかし、それを理由に諦めてはいけません。
Er ist ein viel größeres Hindernis, als Sie denken.
He's much more of an obstacle than you think.
彼はあなたが思っているよりもずっと大きな障害です。
Dann müssen Sie das überwinden, nicht wahr?
Then you must overcome that, mustn't you?
だったらそれを乗り越えなきゃいけないじゃないですか？
Ihre Ladyschaft hat Sie gefragt, ob Sie nach Abschluss Ihrer Arbeit zu ihr ins Wohnzimmer kommen würden.
Her Ladyship asked if you would join her in the drawing room when you've finished.
夫人は、あなたが終わったら応接室に一緒に来ないかと尋ねました。
Also gut, meine Damen, los geht‘s.
Alright, ladies, off you go.
さあ、皆さん、行きましょう。
Herren.
Gentlemen.
紳士諸君。
Jungs, runter, runter.
Chaps, move down, move down.
みんな、下がれ、下がれ。
Louisa, kümmere dich für mich um Pip, ja?
Louisa, look after Pip for me, will you?
ルイザ、ピップの面倒を見てくれませんか？
Ich frage mich, ob wir später noch ein oder zwei Worte miteinander reden könnten, William?
I wonder if we could have a word or two later on, William?
ウィリアム、後で少しお話してもいいかな？
- Ah, George ... - Meinst du?
- Ah, George...
- Do you think so?
- ああ、ジョージ... - そう思う？
Ah, gut, gut.
Ah, good, good.
ああ、よかった、よかった。
- Jennings, könnte ich...? - Natürlich, Sir.
- Jennings, could I...?
- Certainly, sir.
- ジェニングスさん、よろしいでしょうか？ - もちろんです、先生。
Hier ist noch mehr. Ich hole es gerade.
There's more in here.
I'm just getting them.
ここにはまだあります。今取りに来ました。
Ich brauche alle Messer dort. Alle Messer.
I need all the knives there.
All the knives.
そこにあるナイフが全部必要です。ナイフが全部。
- Maude, lass uns den Fischkessel holen. - Nochmal zählen ...
- Maude, let's go and get the fish kettle.
- Counting again...
- モード、魚用のやかんを取って来よう。 - もう一度数えて...
Fred? Albert? Bereit?
Fred? Albert? Ready?
フレッド？アルバート？準備はいい？
- Da ist er. - Wer?
- There he is.
- Who?
- そこにいるよ。 - 誰？
Lord Stockbridges Kammerdiener. Anscheinend wuchs er in einem Waisenhaus auf.
Lord Stockbridge's valet.
Apparently, he grew up in an orphanage.
ストックブリッジ卿の従者。どうやら孤児院で育ったらしい。
Arthur sagte, sie hätten ihn gezwungen, es über den Tisch zu schreien.
Arthur said they made him shout it down the table.
アーサーは、テーブルに向かって叫ばされたと言った。
Es tut einem wirklich leid für ihn.
Makes you feel sorry for him, really.
本当に、彼に同情してしまいます。
Es ist nichts, wofür man sich schämen müsste. Es ist nicht seine Schuld.
It's nothing to be ashamed of. It's not his fault.
恥ずかしいことではありません。彼のせいではありません。
Möchten Sie, dass ich Lord Rupert und Mr. Blond bitte, sich Ihnen anzuschließen, Sir?
Would you like me to ask Lord Rupert and Mr. Blond to join you, sir?
ルパート卿とブロンド氏にもご同行いただくようお願いしてもよろしいでしょうか？
Nein, lass sie in Ruhe. Sie können die Damen unterhalten.
No, leave them be.
They can entertain the ladies.
いいえ、放っておいてください。女性たちを楽しませることができます。
Geben Sie Herrn Novello eine Pause.
Give Mr. Novello a rest.
ノヴェロ氏に休息を与えてください。
Anthony, habe ich Sie sagen hören, dass Sie mit Sir William ins Geschäft einsteigen wollen?
Anthony, did I overhear you saying you will go into business with Sir William?
アンソニー、あなたがウィリアム卿とビジネスを始めると言っているのを耳にしましたか？
- Wie bitte? - Ist es sehr alt?
- I beg your pardon?
- Is it very old?
- すみません？ - とても古いものですか？
Möglicherweise, möglicherweise.
Possibly, possibly.
おそらく、おそらく。
Wenn Sie einen Experten für Geldwechsel brauchen, insbesondere in Afrika, bin ich Ihr Mann ... Experte.
If you need an expert in changing money, especially Africa, I'm your man... expert.
特にアフリカで両替の専門家が必要な場合は、私があなたのお役に立ちます...専門家です。
Ja, der Experte.
Yes, the expert.
はい、専門家です。
Nein, es ist nicht hier.
No, it's not here.
いいえ、ここにはありません。
Mr. Jennings ist sicher, dass er es nicht hat?
Mr. Jennings is certain he hasn't got it?
ジェニングス氏は、自分がそれを手に入れていないと確信しているのですか?
Oh, das sagt er.
Oh, so he says.
ああ、そう言ってるんだ。
Aber wenn es ein silbernes Tranchiermesser ist, muss er es haben.
But if it's a silver carving knife, he must have it.
しかし、それが銀の彫刻ナイフであれば、彼はそれを必ず持っているはずです。
Es ist einfach in die falsche Schublade der silbernen Speisekammer gewandert.
It's just gone in the wrong drawer in the silver pantry.
銀色のパントリーの間違った引き出しに入れられてしまったのです。
- Hier wäre es nicht reingekommen. - Nun, das habe ich ihm gesagt!
- It wouldn't have been put in here.
- Well, that's what I told him!
- ここには入れられなかったよ。 - まあ、私は彼にそう言ったんだよ！
Wie alt war Mr. Stockbridge Ihrer Meinung nach?
How old would you say that Mr. Stockbridge was?
ストックブリッジ氏は何歳だったと思いますか?
Weiß nicht. Ungefähr 31, 32.
Don't know. About 31, 32.
分かりません。31、32くらいです。
- Warum? - Oh, kein Grund.
- Why?
- Oh, no reason.
- なぜですか？ - ああ、理由はないです。
Ich glaube, ich gehe schlafen. Wir sind früh losgekommen.
I think I'll turn in.
We got an early start.
そろそろ寝ようと思います。早めに出発しました。
Sie können Mr. Jennings sagen, dass wir das Messer nicht haben.
You can tell Mr. Jennings we haven't got that knife.
ジェニングスさんに、そのナイフは持っていないと伝えてください。
- Schönen Abend, Mylady? - Nicht wirklich, nein.
- Pleasant evening, milady?
- Not really, no.
- 楽しい夜でしたか、お嬢様？ - いいえ、そうではありません。
Auf der einen Seite hatte Lord Stockbridge für Großbritannien gebohrt,
Had Lord Stockbridge on one side boring for Britain,
一方ではストックブリッジ卿がイギリスのために掘削し、
und Freddie Nesbitt auf der anderen Seite, der sich einschleicht. and Freddie Nesbitt on the other sucking up.
一方、フレディ・ネスビットはおべっかを使っていた。
Oh, ich bin erschöpft. Ist da noch Schokolade im Topf?
Oh, I'm worn out.
Is there any more chocolate in that pot?
ああ、疲れた。あの鍋にはチョコレートはまだあるの？
Ich gehe runter und mache noch mehr, Mylady.
I'll go down and make some more, milady.
降りて行って、もう少し作ってみます、お嬢様。
Lewis?
ルイス？
- Ich habe mein Dienstmädchen gesucht. - Sie ist gerade nach unten gegangen.
- I was looking for my maid.
- She's just gone downstairs.
- メイドさんを探してたんです。 - ちょうど階下に行ってしまいました。
Kann ich helfen?
Can I help?
何かお手伝いしましょうか？
Sie ging, um Schokolade zu holen,
She went to fetch some chocolate,
彼女はチョコレートを買いに行きました、
aber jetzt frage ich mich, ob ich nicht lieber Milch hätte. but now I wonder whether
I wouldn't prefer milk.
しかし、今では牛乳のほうが好きではないかと思う。
Wäre das heiße oder kalte Milch?
Would that be hot milk or cold?
それは温かいミルクですか、それとも冷たいミルクですか？
- Das entscheiden Sie. - Das kann ich nicht sagen, Mylady.
- You decide.
- I couldn't say, milady.
- あなたが決めてください。 - 私には言えません、お嬢様。
Heiß also, mit etwas Süßem. Du hast die Hände in den Taschen.
Hot then, with something to make it sweet.
You have your hands in your pockets.
暑いので、何か甘くしましょう。両手をポケットに入れています。
- Sonst kann ich nie schlafen. - Warum?
- Otherwise I'll never sleep.
- Why?
- そうしないと眠れなくなっちゃうよ。 - なぜ？
Haben Sie Schlafprobleme, Mylady?
Do you have trouble sleeping, milady?
眠れないのですか、お嬢様？
Ich habe das Gefühl, dass ich heute Abend Probleme haben könnte.
I have a feeling
I might have trouble tonight.
今夜は何か問題が起きそうな気がする。
Ich werde um 1:00 Uhr hellwach sein und mich zu Tode langweilen.
I'll be wide awake at 1:00am, bored to sobs.
午前1時に目が覚めて、退屈で泣きそうになります。
Dann müssen wir versuchen, uns etwas auszudenken, das Sie unterhält.
Then we must try and think of something to amuse you.
では、皆さんを楽しませるために何か考えてみましょう。
- Barnes. Es ist alles in Ordnung. - Oh, das tut mir so leid, Sir.
- Barnes. It's alright.
- Oh, I'm so sorry, sir.
- バーンズ。大丈夫です。 - ああ、申し訳ありませんでした。
Nein, ich wusste es. Ich wusste, dass William so etwas versuchen würde.
No, I knew it. I knew William would try something like this.
いいえ、分かっていました。ウィリアムがこのようなことをするだろうと分かっていました。
- Natürlich würde er das. Scheiß auf ihn! - Kurzarsch!
- Course he would. Fuck him!
- Shortarse!
- もちろんそうだろう。クソ野郎！ - ちくしょう！
Und scheiß auf dieses Zimmer!
And fuck this room!
そしてこの部屋はクソだ！
Ich denke, du solltest morgen mit mir kommen.
I think you should come with me tomorrow.
明日は私と一緒に来たほうがいいと思います。
Ich sage nur, dass ich dich brauche.
I'll just say I need you.
ただ君が必要だと言うだけだ。
Oh, ich habe es heute Abend bis zur Küste geschafft. Endlich. Stimmt die Uhr?
Oh, I got through to the coast tonight.
Finally. Is that clock right?
ああ、今夜は海岸までたどり着いた。やっと。時計は合ってるかな？
Wir wurden von Una Merkel abgelehnt, also ... drängt Sheen auf eine Neufassung.
We got turned down by Una Merkel, so... Sheen's pushing for a rewrite.
ウナ・メルケルに断られたので…シーンは書き直しを要求している。
Er findet die Rolle zu klein.
He thinks the part's too small.
彼はその部分が小さすぎると思っている。
Es ist ein verdammter Charlie-Chan-Film, kein Film über eine Dame der Gesellschaft.
It's a fucking Charlie Chan picture, not a movie about a socialite.
それはチャーリー・チャンの映画であって、社交界の名士についての映画ではない。
Also...
So...
それで...
Sehen wir uns später?
Will I see you later?
また後で会えますか？
Ich glaube nicht, dass ich das riskieren sollte. Oder?
I don't think I should risk it.
Do you?
危険を冒すべきではないと思います。あなたはどう思いますか?
Gute Nacht, Sir.
Goodnight, sir.
おやすみなさい。
Heinrich.
Henry.
ヘンリー。
Vergessen Sie das nicht. Sie werden denken, es sei Ihnen egal.
Don't forget those.
They'll think you don't care.
それを見逃さないでください。彼らはあなたが気にしていないと思うでしょう。
- Oh, ich muss die falsche Treppe genommen haben. - Hier oben lässt man sich besser nicht sehen.
- Oh, I must've taken the wrong stairs.
- You better not be seen up here.
- ああ、間違った階段を使ってしまったようだ。 - ここにいることが見られないように気をつけてください。
- Ich gehe besser runter. - Warum?
- I'd better go down.
- Why?
- 降りたほうがいいよ。 - なぜ？
Es besteht keine Eile.
There's no rush.
急ぐ必要はありません。
Da Sie jetzt hier sind, wie wäre es mit einem Drink?
Since you're here now, what about a drink?
せっかく来たのだから、飲み物でもどうですか？
Was machst du?
What are you doing?
何してるの？
NEIN!
No!
いいえ！
Geh von mir runter!
Get off me!
離して！
Geh weg von mir! Geh weg ...
Get off me! Get off...
降りろ！降りろ…
Was?
What?
何？
Was ist das? Was machst du hier?
What's this?
What are you doing here?
これは何ですか？ここで何をしているのですか？
Ich bin die falsche Treppe hochgekommen. Ich habe nur gewartet, bis die Luft rein war.
I came up the wrong staircase. I was just waiting till the coast was clear.
間違った階段を上ってしまいました。ただ、危険が去るまで待っていました。
Dann geh lieber wieder runter, bevor dich jemand erwischt.
Well, you better go down again before anyone catches you.
まあ、誰かに捕まる前にもう一度降りたほうがいいよ。
Einen Moment.
Just a minute.
ちょっとだけ。
- Was? - Nichts.
- What?
- Nothing.
- 何だって？ - 何もないよ。
- Möchtest du etwas trinken? - Sicher.
- Do you want a drink?
- Sure.
- 飲み物はいかがですか？ - もちろんです。
Also, was halten Sie von diesem Ort?
So what do you make of the place?
それで、その場所についてどう思いますか?
Ist das Ihrer Meinung nach ein gut geführtes Haus?
Is this a well-run house, would you say?
この家はよく管理されていると思いますか？
Glauben Sie, dass es ein guter Arbeitgeber für Sir William wäre?
Do you think Sir William would be good to work for?
ウィリアム卿の下で働くのはいいことだと思いますか?
NEIN.
No.
いいえ。
Wie lange machst du das schon?
How long you been doing this?
これをどれくらいやっているんですか?
- Was? - Parkservice?
- What?
- Valeting?
- 何ですか？ - 駐車サービスですか？
Ungefähr sieben Jahre. Davor war ich Diener.
About seven years.
I was a footman before that.
約7年です。その前は従者でした。
Und für Lord Stockbridge zu arbeiten ... ist das eine Beförderung?
And working for Lord Stockbridge... is that a promotion?
ストックブリッジ卿の下で働くというのは昇進ですか？
NEIN.
No.
いいえ。
Ich war früher beim Earl of Flintshire.
I used to be with the Earl of Flintshire.
私はかつてフリントシャー伯爵と一緒にいました。
- Warum bist du dann umgezogen? - Weil ich Lust dazu hatte.
- Then why did you move?
- 'Cause I felt like it.
- じゃあ、なぜ引っ越したの？ - 気が向いたからだよ。
Wer ist er?
Who's that?
あれは誰？
- Das ist meine Mutter. - Wo wohnt sie?
- That's my mother.
- Where does she live?
- あれは私の母です。 - 彼女はどこに住んでいますか?
Sie tut es nicht. Deshalb haben sie mich in ein Waisenhaus gesteckt.
She doesn't. That's why they put me in an orphanage.
彼女はそうしない。だから私は孤児院に入れられた。
Das stimmt. Tut mir leid.
That's right. Sorry.
そうです。ごめんなさい。
Was ist mit ihr passiert?
What happened to her?
彼女に何が起こったのですか？
- Was meinst du? - Ich meine, warum ist sie gestorben?
- What do you mean?
- I mean, why did she die?
- どういう意味ですか？ - つまり、なぜ彼女は死んだのですか？
War sie jung? Lag sie gerade mitten in der Geburt?
Was she young?
Was it in childbirth?
彼女は若かったのですか？出産中だったのですか？
Sie sind nicht sehr neugierig, oder?
You're not very curious, are you?
あまり興味がないのですね？
Ja, sie war jung. Sie arbeitete in einer Fabrik.
Yeah, she was young.
She worked in a factory.
ええ、彼女は若かったんです。工場で働いていました。
Sie hatte mich. Kurze Zeit später starb sie.
She had me.
A little while later, she died.
彼女は私を産みました。そしてしばらくして、彼女は亡くなりました。
Ende der Geschichte.
End of story.
物語は終わりです。
Warum haben Sie dann beim Abendessen nicht gesagt, dass sie eine Fabrikarbeiterin war?
Then why didn't you say she was a factory worker at dinner?
じゃあ、なぜ夕食時に彼女が工場労働者だと言わなかったのですか？
Weil ich keine Lust hatte, über mein Privatleben zu sprechen
'Cause I didn't fancy discussing my private life
だって私生活について話すのは嫌だったから
mit einem Tisch voller Fremder. with a table full of strangers.
テーブルには見知らぬ人たちがいっぱい。
Tut mir leid, wenn ich mich ungefragt geäußert habe, Kumpel. Ich wollte dich nicht beleidigen.
I'm sorry if I spoke out of turn, mate.
Didn't mean to offend you.
失礼なことを言ってしまったらごめんなさい。あなたを怒らせるつもりはなかったんです。
Ich bin nicht beleidigt.
I'm not offended.
気分を害していません。
Und nenn mich nicht „Kumpel“.
And don't call me "mate".
そして私を「仲間」と呼ばないでください。
Also, wir sehen uns später.
Well, I'll see you later.
それでは、また後でお会いしましょう。
Ich habe eine Verabredung mit einem heißen Glas Milch.
I've got a date with a hot glass of milk.
熱いミルクを飲むデートがあるんだ。
Ich sollte mir darüber keine Sorgen machen. Das gehört dazu.
I shouldn't worry about it.
It goes with the territory.
心配する必要はありません。それは当然のことです。
Oh, sehen Sie, es ist Mr. Novello.
Oh, look. It's Mr. Novello.
ああ、見て。ノヴェロさんだ。
Denken Sie nur daran, dass er unten schläft.
Just think of him sleeping downstairs.
彼が階下で寝ていることを想像してみてください。
Ich muss dich im Auge behalten, mein Mädchen. Das sehe ich.
I'm gonna have to watch you, my girl.
I can see that.
君を監視しないといけないよ、娘よ。それは分かるよ。
Ihre Ladyschaft sagt, Mr. Weissman sei ein Hollywood-Produzent.
Her Ladyship says Mr. Weissman's a Hollywood producer.
ワイスマン氏はハリウッドのプロデューサーだと夫人は言っています。
Er macht die Charlie-Chan-Filme.
He does the Charlie Chan films.
彼はチャーリー・チャンの映画に出演しています。
Ja, die mag ich. Ich mag es, im Kino ein bisschen gruseln zu können.
Yeah, I like those.
I like a bit of a fright in the cinema.
ええ、好きです。映画館でちょっと怖いものを見るのが好きなんです。
Sie könnten mit seinem Diener gehen. Er würde Ihnen einen Schrecken einjagen.
You could go with his valet.
He'd give you a fright.
彼の従者と一緒に行くといいよ。彼はあなたを怖がらせるだろう。
Behalten Sie ihn besser im Auge. Ich glaube, er ist komisch.
You'd better keep your eye on him.
I think he's a queer one.
彼には気をつけた方がいいよ。変な奴だと思うよ。
Zunächst einmal kommt er nicht aus Schottland. Zumindest nicht aus irgendeinem Teil, den ich kenne.
He's not from Scotland, for a start.
At least not any part of it that I know.
まず、彼はスコットランド出身ではない。少なくとも私が知る限りスコットランドのどの地域からも来ていない。
- Wie ist Mrs. Nesbitt? - Ihr geht es gut.
- What's Mrs. Nesbitt like?
- She's alright.
- ネスビット夫人はどんな人ですか？ - 大丈夫ですよ。
Sie tut mir wirklich ein bisschen leid.
I feel a bit sorry for her, really.
実のところ、私は彼女に少し同情を感じます。
- Natürlich funktioniert es nie. - Was funktioniert nie?
- Of course, it never works.
- What never works?
- もちろん、それは決してうまくいきません。 - 何が決してうまくいかないのでしょうか?
Nun, wenn ein Mann wie er unter seinem Stand heiratet,
Well, when a man like that marries beneath him,
まあ、そんな男が自分より下の者と結婚すると、
er hat nicht den Verstand, es durchzuziehen. he hasn't got the brains to carry it off.
彼にはそれをやり遂げるだけの頭脳がない。
- Ich finde es romantisch, aus Liebe zu heiraten. - Liebe? Er nicht.
- I think it's romantic to marry for love.
- Love? Not him.
- 愛のために結婚するのはロマンチックだと思う。 - 愛？彼じゃない。
Er ist ein übler Bursche.
He's a nasty piece of work.
彼は本当に厄介な奴だ。
Der ehrenwerte Freddie Nesbitt. Das ist zum Lachen.
The honorable Freddie Nesbitt.
That's a laugh.
名誉あるフレディ・ネスビット。笑っちゃう。
Nein, er war hinter dem Geld ihres Vaters her.
No, it was her father's money he was after.
いいえ、彼が狙っていたのは彼女の父親のお金でした。
Es war weniger als er dachte, und jetzt ist alles ausgegeben,
It was less than he thought, and now it's all spent,
それは彼が思っていたよりも少なく、今ではすべて使い果たされてしまった。
Das Einzige, was er vorzuweisen hat, ist eine Frau, für die er sich schämt. all he's got to show for it is a wife he's ashamed of.
彼が得たものは、恥ずかしい妻だけだ。
Und er hat seinen Job verloren.
And he's lost his job.
そして彼は仕事を失いました。
Möchte, dass Miss Isobel ein Wort bei Sir William einlegt.
Wants Miss Isobel to put in a word with Sir William.
イザベル嬢にウィリアム卿に一言伝えてほしい。
- Was ist los? - Ich habe das Hemd nie gewaschen!
- What's the matter?
- I never washed that shirt!
- どうしたの？ - そのシャツは一度も洗ってないのに！
Oh, sie wird mich umbringen.
Oh, she's gonna kill me.
ああ、彼女は私を殺すつもりだ。
Glaubst du, ich könnte es jetzt tun?
Do you think I could do it now?
今ならできると思いますか？
- Soll ich mit dir gehen? - Nein.
- Do you want me to go with you?
- No.
- 私も一緒に行きましょうか？ - いいえ。
Mir geht es gut.
I'll be alright.
大丈夫だよ。
Was machst du hier unten?
What are you doing down here?
ここで何をしているんですか？
Ich soll Lady Trenthams Hemd für morgen waschen.
I'm supposed to wash
Lady Trentham's shirt for tomorrow.
明日のためにトレンサム夫人のシャツを洗わなければならない。
Im Bügelzimmer gibt es ein Waschbecken.
There's a sink in the ironing room.
アイロン室にはシンクがあります。
Ist da jemand drin?
Is someone in there?
そこに誰かいますか？
Was machst du hier?
What are you doing here?
ここで何をしているの？
Ich musste dieses Hemd einfach ausspülen.
I just had to rinse this shirt out.
このシャツを洗い流さなければならなかった。
Du hättest klopfen sollen, oder?
Should've knocked, shouldn't you?
ノックするべきだったよね？
Fräulein Trentham?
Miss Trentham?
トレンサムさん？
Ich habe gerade ein Hemd Ihrer Ladyschaft gewaschen.
I was just washing a shirt of Her Ladyship's.
私はちょうど夫人のシャツを洗濯していたところです。
Ich hoffe, Sie haben alles gefunden, was Sie brauchten.
I hope you found everything you required.
必要なものがすべて見つかることを願っています。
Muss sie unbedingt Marmelade essen?
Does she have to have marmalade?
彼女はマーマレードを食べなければなりませんか？
Nur Dorothy hat im letzten Januar zu wenig daraus gemacht,
Only Dorothy made too little of it last January,
ドロシーだけが昨年1月にそれをあまり考慮しなかった。
und uns ist das Selbstgemachte ausgegangen. and we've run out of the homemade.
自家製のものもなくなってしまいました。
Ich nehme nicht an, dass sie stattdessen Lust auf Erdbeermarmelade hätte?
I don't suppose she'd care for strawberry jam instead?
彼女は代わりにイチゴジャムを好まないでしょうか？
Nein, das dachte ich mir.
No, I thought not.
いいえ、そうは思いませんでした。
Oh, ich hatte eher auf ein Wort mit Mrs. Wilson gehofft.
Oh, I was rather hoping for a word with Mrs. Wilson.
ああ、私はむしろウィルソン夫人と話をしたいと思っていました。
Mrs. Wilson, sagen Sie Jennings
Mrs. Wilson, will you tell Jennings
ウィルソンさん、ジェニングスに伝えてもらえますか
dass es die Suppe morgen nach der vierten Fahrt gibt? that we'll have the soup after the fourth drive tomorrow?
明日の4回目のドライブの後にスープを食べますか？
Aa-und sagen Sie Mrs. Croft, sie soll-sie soll dafür sorgen, dass es heiß, kalt-heiß ist.
A-a-and tell Mrs. Croft to-to make sure it's hot, cold-hot.
ああ、クロフト夫人に、熱いか冷たいか、熱いかを確認するように伝えてください。
Es war die letzten Wochen kalt. Und mehr Pfeffer drin.
It's been cold the last few weeks.
And more pepper in it.
ここ数週間は寒いですね。それに、胡椒も増えてきました。
Sind Sie das?
Is that you?
あなたなの？
Haben Sie jemand anderen erwartet?
Were you expecting someone else?
他の人を期待していましたか?
Heute ist es siebenhundertster Tag?
Seven-hundred day today?
今日は700日目？
Also, Jungs, trainiert eure Waffen nicht, auch wenn sie nicht einmal ein Scheunentor treffen können.
Well, lads, don't coach your guns, even if they can't hit a barn door.
まあ、君たち、たとえ銃が納屋のドアに当たらなくても、銃を訓練してはいけないよ。
Sagen Sie ihnen nicht, wo sie fehlen, es sei denn, sie fragen danach.
Don't tell them where they're missing, unless they ask.
彼らが尋ねない限り、どこに行方不明になっているかを教えないでください。
- Schöner Tag! Jennings... - Ich hoffe, das bleibt auch so, Sir.
- Lovely day! Jennings...
- I hope it holds for you, sir.
- 素敵な一日でした！ジェニングス... - 良い一日でありますように、先生。
- Viel Spaß beim Schießen. - Kann ein Fasan jemals gefährlich sein?
- Enjoy the shoot.
- Can a pheasant ever be dangerous?
- 射撃を楽しんでください。 - キジは危険なことがありますか?
- Gefährlich? - Muss ich Angst haben, dass es angreift?
- Dangerous?
- Do I have to worry about it attacking?
- 危険ですか？ - 攻撃してくる心配はありますか？
- Morgen, Sir. - Gut, ziehen Sie Ihre Stifte.
- Morning, sir.
- Right, draw your pegs.
- おはようございます。 - では、ペグを引いてください。
Ich werde ihn anfeuern.
I'm gonna be cheering him on.
私は彼を応援するつもりです。
Hier sind wir.
Here we are.
ここです。
- Morgen, Jennings. - Schießen Sie heute, Sir?
- Morning, Jennings.
- Are you shooting today, sir?
- おはようございます、ジェニングス。 - 今日は撮影ですか？
- Ich schieße nie. - Oh.
- I never shoot.
- Oh.
- 私は撃たないよ。 - ああ。
Ich bin am Verhungern.
I'm-I'm starving.
お腹が空いちゃった。
Wo bist du gewesen?
Where have you been?
どこにいましたか？
Entschuldigung.
Sorry.
ごめん。
Oh, hier wird immer ein gutes Frühstück raufgeschickt.
Oh, they always send up a good breakfast here.
ああ、ここではいつもおいしい朝食が届けられます。
Das muss ich Sylvia lassen. Sie ist in dieser Hinsicht überhaupt nicht gemein.
I'll say that for Sylvia.
She's not at all mean in that way.
シルビアについてはそう言います。彼女はそういう意味ではまったく意地悪ではありません。
Oh je. Habe Marmelade gekauft. Meine Güte, das nenne ich sehr schwach.
Oh, dear. Bought marmalade.
Dear me, I call that very feeble.
ああ、大変。マーマレードを買った。まあ、それはとても弱いことだと思う。
Nun ja, ich schätze, man kann nicht alles haben.
Well, I suppose one can't have everything.
まあ、すべてを手に入れることはできないと思います。
Mary, ich glaube nicht, dass ich dieses Hemd doch tragen werde.
Mary, I don't think
I'll wear that shirt after all.
メアリー、結局そのシャツを着るつもりはないと思う。
Der andere ist wärmer. Das ist alles, was mich interessiert.
The other one's warmer.
That's all I care about.
もう一方は暖かい。それが私にとってのすべてです。
Oh, lecker!
Ooh, yummy!
ああ、おいしい！
Lecker, lecker, lecker.
Yummy, yummy, yummy.
おいしい、おいしい、おいしい。
Was meinst du damit, du gehst schießen?
What do you mean, you're going shooting?
射撃に行くってどういうことですか？
Herr Weissman möchte, dass ich ihn begleite. Daran ist nichts auszusetzen.
Mr. Weissman wants me to accompany him.
Nothing wrong in that.
ワイスマン氏は私に同行してほしいと言っています。何も悪いことではありません。
Aber wozu? Du lädst nicht. Er hat keine Waffe.
But what for? You're not loading.
He hasn't got a gun.
しかし、何のために？弾を装填していない。彼は銃を持っていない。
- Er könnte etwas brauchen. - Was könnte er brauchen?
- He might need something.
- What could he need?
- 何か必要なのかもしれない。 - 何が必要なの？
Ja, wir wissen, dass Sie allein schon der Gedanke an Service beleidigend finden, George.
Yeah, we know the very idea of service is offensive to you, George.
ええ、ジョージ、サービスという考え自体があなたにとって不快なものであることはわかっています。
Aber es besteht kein Grund, es an uns anderen auszulassen.
But there's no need to take it out on the rest of us.
しかし、それを私たち全員にぶつける必要はありません。
Bitte verzeihen Sie unsere schlechten Manieren, Mr. Weissman.
Please, forgive our ill manners,
Mr. Weissman.
ワイスマンさん、私たちの無礼をお許しください。
Ich glaube, der da hat etwas zu verbergen.
I think he's got something to hide, that one.
あの人は何かを隠していると思うよ。
Wir alle haben etwas zu verbergen, Mr. Meredith.
We all have something to hide,
Mr. Meredith.
私たちは皆、何かを隠しているんです、メレディスさん。
Möchten Sie sich jetzt umziehen, Fräulein?
Would you like to get changed now, Miss?
今着替えますか、お嬢さん？
- Er wird es nicht tun. - Wer wird was nicht tun?
- He won't do it.
- Who won't do what?
- 彼はそれをしません。 - 誰が何をしないのですか?
Mein Vater. Er will Freddie keinen Job geben.
My father. He won't give Freddie a job.
私の父。彼はフレディに仕事を与えてくれない。
Ich habe gestern Abend mit ihm gesprochen und er sagte, er würde darüber nachdenken.
I spoke to him last night, and he said he'd think about it.
昨晩彼と話したら、彼はそれについて考えると言っていました。
Doch heute Morgen sagt er, es liege nicht in seiner Hand, obwohl es natürlich seine Entscheidung ist.
But this morning, he says it isn't up to him, when, of course, it is.
しかし今朝、彼は、もちろんそれは自分の責任なのに、それは自分の責任ではないと言っている。
- Warum nicht? - Ich weiß nicht.
- Why not?
- I don't know.
- なぜだ？ - 分からないよ。
Hat etwas damit zu tun, warum Freddie entlassen wurde.
Something to do with why Freddie was sacked.
フレディが解雇された理由と関係がある。
Aber ich kann von keinem von beiden eine klare Antwort bekommen.
But I can't get a straight answer out of either of them.
しかし、どちらからも明確な答えを得ることはできません。
Nun, Sie haben Ihr Bestes gegeben.
Well, you've done your best.
まあ、ベストを尽くしましたね。
Mehr kann Herr Nesbitt jetzt nicht verlangen, oder?
Mr. Nesbitt can't ask for more than that now, can he?
ネスビット氏は今、それ以上のことは望めないのではないでしょうか？
Aber er kann noch viel mehr! Er sagt, er wird es ihm sagen.
But he can, much more!
He says he's going to tell him.
しかし、彼はもっと多くのことができるのです！彼は彼に伝えるつもりだと言っています。
Glaubst du, er wird es tun?
Do you think he will?
彼はそうすると思いますか？
Ich weiß nicht. Er sagt, Papa wird ihm einen Job geben, damit er ruhig bleibt.
I don't know. He says Daddy will give him a job to keep him quiet.
分かりません。パパが黙っていられるように仕事を与えるそうです。
- Möchten Sie etwas sagen? - Zu Mr. Nesbitt?
- Will you say something?
- To Mr. Nesbitt?
- 何か言っていただけますか？ - ネスビットさんに？
Für Papa.
To Daddy.
パパへ。
Im Ernst, Miss, warum glauben Sie, dass ich etwas bewirken kann?
Really, Miss, why do you think
I can make a difference?
本当に、お嬢さん、なぜ私が変化を起こせると思うのですか?
Wirst du?
Will you?
しますか？
Ich finde, du solltest heute deine warme Unterwäsche tragen.
I think you should wear your warm underwear today.
今日は暖かい下着を着たほうがいいと思います。
Fast.
Nearly.
ほぼ。
Das ist meins.
That's mine.
それは私のものです。
Oh Gott! Es ist unterwegs.
Oh, God! It's on its way.
ああ、神様！もう到着しています。
Verdammt! Die verdammte Waffe taugt nichts. Ich hab dir doch gesagt, du sollst die nicht mitbringen.
Damn! Bloody gun's no good.
I told you not to bring this one.
ちくしょう！銃なんて役に立たない。これを持ってくるなと言ったじゃないか。
Explosion.
Blast.
爆破。
Ich glaube, ich habe ihn angestochen. Ich bin mir ziemlich sicher, dass ich ihn angestochen habe.
I think I pricked that one.
I-I 'm pretty sure I pricked it.
あれを刺したと思う。刺したと確信している。
Mist!
Bugger!
くそっ！
Oh! Oh!
ああ！ああ！
Explosion!
Blast!
爆破！
Oh, verdammt! Verdammt!
Oh, damn! Blast!
ああ、くそっ！やられた！
- Geht es Ihnen gut, Sir? - Nein, mir geht es nicht gut!
- Are you alright, sir?
- No, I'm not alright!
- 大丈夫ですか？ - いいえ、大丈夫じゃないんです！
Gott, wo zum Teufel kam das her?
God, where the bloody hell did that come from?
ああ、一体どこからそんなものが出てきたんだ？
- Es hat Sie getroffen, Sir. - Gott, es hat mich getroffen.
- It's nicked you, sir.
- God, it's nicked me.
- あなたを傷つけました、先生。 - ああ、私も傷つけられました。
- Welcher Kretin hat das getan? - Ich weiß es nicht, Sir.
- What cretin did that?
- I don't know, sir.
- 一体誰がそんなことをしたんだ？ - 分かりません、先生。
Finden Sie Strutt! Fragen Sie ihn, ob er weiß, wer dafür verantwortlich ist.
Find Strutt! Ask him if he knows who's responsible.
ストラットを探せ！誰が犯人か知っているか尋ねろ。
Und wenn er es weiß, sagen Sie ihm, er soll die Waffe zurück in das verdammte Haus schicken.
And if he knows, tell him to send the gun back to the bloody house.
そしてもし彼が知っているなら、銃を血まみれの家へ送り返すように言いなさい。
Jeder weiß, in welch verzweifelter Lage wir uns befinden, aber es scheint niemanden zu kümmern.
Everybody knows the desperate situation we're in, but nobody seems to care.
私たちが置かれている絶望的な状況は誰もが知っているが、誰も気にしていないようだ。
Oh, da bist du ja. Hast du einen gefunden?
Oh, there you are.
Did you find one?
ああ、そこにいました。見つけましたか？
- Und? - Schau mich nicht an.
- Well?
- Don't look at me.
- えっと？ - 私を見ないで。
Wenn ich zu diesem Thema auch nur den Mund aufmache, wird alles nur noch schlimmer.
If I so much as open my mouth on the subject, it'll make things worse.
この件について口を開くだけでも、事態は悪化するだろう。
- Ich habe es bereits versucht. - Jennings sagt, das Auto ist fertig.
- I've already tried.
- Jennings says the car's ready.
- すでに試してみました。 - ジェニングスによると、車は準備ができているそうです。
Oh, toll. Ich bin am Verhungern.
Oh, goody. I'm starving.
ああ、よかった。お腹が空いてきた。
- Was trägst du? - Warum? Gefällt es dir nicht?
- What are you wearing?
- Why? Don't you like it?
- 何を着てるの？ - どうして？ 気に入らないの？
- Du hast es gekauft. - Habe ich?
- You bought it.
- Did I?
- 買ったの？ - 買ったの？
- Oh, wie außergewöhnlich von mir. - Komm schon. Ich sollte besser gehen.
- Oh, how extraordinary of me.
- Come on. Better get going.
- ああ、私はなんて素晴らしい人なんだろう。 - さあ、行きましょう。
Wo ist die elende Mabel?
Where's that wretched Mabel?
あの哀れなメイベルはどこにいる？
Hat jemand ihr Outfit überprüft? Sie trägt wahrscheinlich schwarzen Samt
Has anyone checked her outfit?
She's probably in black velvet
誰か彼女の服装を確認しましたか？彼女はおそらく黒のベルベットを着ているでしょう
mit einer Feder im Haar. with a feather in her hair.
髪に羽根がついている。
Sie ist im Morgenzimmer und sieht völlig normal aus.
She's in the morning room looking perfectly normal.
彼女は朝の部屋にいて、まったく普通に見えます。
- Sei nicht so ein Snob, Tante Constance. - Ich?
- Don't be such a snob, Aunt Constance.
- Me?
- そんなに気取らないで、コンスタンスおばさん。 - 私？
Ich habe nicht den geringsten Sinn für Snobismus.
I haven't the snobbish bone in my body.
私には、気取ったところなんてありません。
Oh, Herr Meredith.
Oh, Mr. Meredith.
ああ、メレディスさん。
- Ist Mr. Stockbridge da? - Suchen Sie mich.
- Is Mr. Stockbridge in?
- Search me.
- ストックブリッジさんはいますか？ - 私を捜してください。
Oh, Mr. Stockbridge. Es tut mir leid, Sie zu stören.
Oh, Mr. Stockbridge.
I'm sorry to disturb you.
ああ、ストックブリッジさん。お邪魔してすみません。
Ich habe nur meine Routineinspektion durchgeführt.
I was just making my routine inspection.
ただ定期点検をしていただけです。
Also, äh, wie kommen Sie bei Lord Stockbridge zurecht?
So, uh, how are you settling in with Lord Stockbridge?
それで、ストックブリッジ卿との生活はいかがですか?
Es tut mir Leid?
I'm sorry?
ごめんなさい？
Wie kommen Sie bei Lord Stockbridge zurecht?
How are you settling in with Lord Stockbridge?
ストックブリッジ卿との生活はいかがですか?
Ich weiß, dass du noch nicht lange mit ihm zusammen bist.
I know that you haven't been with him for long.
彼と長く一緒にいなかったことは知っています。
Nicht lange, nein.
Not long, no.
長くはないですよ。
Ich fürchte, das Rauchen ist hier oben nicht gestattet.
I'm afraid smoking isn't allowed up here.
残念ですが、ここでは喫煙は禁止されています。
Ich hoffe, Sie finden alles, um den Aufenthalt Seiner Lordschaft angenehmer zu gestalten.
I hope you're finding everything to make
His Lordship's stay more comfortable.
閣下のご滞在がより快適なものとなるよう、あらゆる準備が整っていることを願っております。
Ich hoffe, wir haben nichts vergessen.
I hope we haven't forgotten anything.
何か忘れていないことを願います。
Ich kann nicht glauben, dass Sie so viel vergessen, Mrs. Wilson.
I can't believe you forget much,
Mrs. Wilson.
ウィルソンさん、あなたがそんなに忘れるなんて信じられません。
Nein, nicht viel.
No, not much.
いいえ、あまりないです。
Nun, ich überlasse Sie Ihrem Buch.
Well, I'll leave you to your book.
まあ、あなたの本を読んでください。
Weißt du ... bumm! Wuff!
You know... bang! Whoof!
あのね...バン！フーッ！
Sie sollten bei der Auswahl der Personen, die Sie einladen, wählerischer sein.
You should be more selective about the people you invite.
招待する人についてはもっと慎重に選ぶべきです。
- Also, ich habe guten Appetit. - Ja.
- Well, I've got a good appetite.
- Yes.
- まあ、食欲はありますよ。 - はい。
Furchtbar matschig hier. Passen Sie auf.
Terribly muddy here.
Do watch.
ここはひどく泥だらけです。見てください。
Verstehen Sie, was ich meine? Mir ist es aufgefallen.
Do you see what I'm saying?
I've been noticing it.
私の言っていることが分かりますか？私は気づいていました。
Sieht das nicht hübsch aus? Sie haben das wirklich gut gemacht.
Doesn't this look lovely?
They really have done well.
とても素敵だと思いませんか？本当によくやりましたね。
Gehen Sie jetzt hinein und trinken Sie etwas.
Now do go in and have a drink.
さあ、中に入って飲み物を飲んでください。
Ich kann Ihnen sagen, Raymond, das ist wirklich schrecklich, was da passiert ist.
I can tell you, Raymond, it's a bloody awful thing to have happened.
レイモンド、本当にひどい出来事が起こったと断言できます。
- Oh Gott, Louisa. - Oh! Oh, sage ich.
- Oh, God, Louisa.
- Oh! Oh, I say.
- ああ、神様、ルイザ。 - ああ！ああ、そう言うわ。
Fünf Zentimeter weiter rechts von mir wäre ich tot gewesen. Ich wurde gerade angeschossen.
Two inches to my right I'd have been dead.
I've just been shot.
２インチ右に動いていたら、私は死んでいたでしょう。私は撃たれたばかりです。
- Was? - Ja, das stimmt.
- What?
- Yes, that's right.
- 何ですか？ - はい、その通りです。
- Oh ja, bitte. - Was ist mit deinem Ohr passiert?
- Oh, yes, please.
- What happened to your ear?
- ああ、はい、お願いします。 - 耳に何があったんですか?
Irgendein Idiot hat auf mich geschossen.
Some idiot shot me.
バカが私を撃った。
- Das war ein furchtbarer Schuss. - Hat es dir Spaß gemacht?
- That was a terrible shot.
- Did you have fun?
- ひどいショットだったね。 - 楽しかった？
Ich glaube, Ihnen ist nicht klar, wie ernst die Lage ist.
I don't think you realize how serious this is.
これがどれほど深刻なことか、あなたはわかっていないと思います。
Natürlich tue ich das.
Of course I do.
もちろんです。
Warum kannst du deine Schwestern nicht um Hilfe bitten?
Why can't you get your sisters to help?
どうして姉妹に手伝ってもらえないの？
Liebling, denkst du, ich hätte es nicht versucht? Du weißt, wie sie sind.
Darling, do you think I haven't tried?
You know what they're like.
ダーリン、私が試したことがないとでも思っているの？あなたはそれがどんなものか知っているでしょう。
Nun, ich weiß, es ist ihnen völlig egal, ob wir untergehen.
Well, I know they couldn't care less if we go under.
まあ、我々が倒産しても彼らは気にしないだろうということは分かっています。
Warum sollte es sie kümmern, solange ihre Schneiderinnen beschäftigt sind
Why should they care, as long as their dressmakers are busy
ドレスメーカーが忙しい限り、なぜ気にする必要があるのか
und ihr Abendessen wird pünktlich serviert? and their dinners are served on time?
夕食は時間通りに提供されますか?
- Moment mal. Hier ist eine Schlange. - Psst, psst.
- Wait a minute. There's a queue here.
- Shh, shh.
- ちょっと待って。ここに列ができてるよ。 - シーッ、シーッ。
Oh! Mach um Himmels willen die Tür zu.
Oh!
Shut the door, for heaven's sake.
ああ！お願いだからドアを閉めてください。
Keine Sorge. Es sind nur Lewis und Dorothy.
Don't worry.
It's only Lewis and Dorothy.
心配しないでください。ルイスとドロシーだけです。
Wenn einer der Männer hier oben erwischt wird, wird er auf der Stelle entlassen.
If any of the men get found up here, they get sacked on the spot.
もし誰かがここで見つかったら、その場で解雇されるでしょう。
Noch mehr Pech gehabt.
Worse luck.
運が悪い。
Also, erzähl mir nicht, dass du ein Klostermädchen bist. Oder ist das presbyterianische Bescheidenheit?
So, don't tell me you're a convent girl.
Or is that Presbyterian modesty?
だから、あなたが修道院の少女だなんて言わないでください。それとも、それが長老派の謙虚さなのでしょうか?
- Ist das Wasser heiß? - Nicht wirklich.
- Is the water hot?
- Not really.
- お湯は熱いですか？ - そんなに熱いわけではないです。
Nein, das wird erst passieren, wenn die Waffen wieder da sind. Ich sollte mich lieber um deine kümmern.
No, it won't be till the guns get back.
I'd better get in yours.
いいえ、銃が戻ってくるまでは無理です。あなたの銃を受け取ったほうがいいですよ。
Ihre Ladyschaft sagt, dass Sir William das Schießen liebt.
Her Ladyship says that Sir William loves his shooting.
ウィリアム卿は射撃が大好きだと夫人は言っています。
Ja, das tut er. Er kann zwar kein Scheunentor treffen, aber er liebt es.
Yeah, he does. Can't hit a barn door, but he does love it.
ええ、そうです。納屋のドアを叩くことはできませんが、彼はそれが大好きです。
Es ist wirklich ziemlich süß.
It's quite sweet, really.
本当に甘いですよ。
- Elsie. - Ja?
- Elsie.
- Yeah?
- エルシー。 - うん？
Letzte Nacht...
Last night...
昨晩...
Was?
What?
何？
- Nein, das sollte ich nicht sagen. - Doch, das solltest du. Was?
- No, I shouldn't say.
- Yes, you should. What?
- いや、言うべきじゃない。 - ええ、言うべきです。 何ですか？
Nun... als ich runterging, um das Hemd zu waschen,
Well... when I went down to wash that shirt,
えっと…シャツを洗濯しに行ったとき、
Ich glaube, ich habe ihn im Bügelzimmer gesehen.
I think I saw him in the ironing room.
アイロン室で彼を見たような気がします。
Er war mit einem der Küchenmädchen zusammen.
He was with one of the kitchen maids.
彼はキッチンメイドの一人と一緒にいました。
- Nein, das kann er nicht gewesen sein. - Ich glaube schon.
- No, that wouldn't have been him.
- I think it was.
- いいえ、それは彼ではなかったでしょう。 - そうだったと思います。
Er kam eine Minute später den Gang herunter und ich verstehe nicht, wie ...
He came down the passage a minute later, and I don't see how...
彼は1分後に通路を降りてきましたが、どうして...
Nein, er war es nicht.
No, it wasn't him.
いいえ、彼ではありませんでした。
Das war gestern Abend nicht Ihr Ernst, oder?
You weren't serious last night, were you?
昨夜は本気じゃなかったよね？
Ich fürchte, das war ich, alter Junge.
I'm afraid I was, old boy.
残念ながらそうでしたよ、おじさん。
Ich wollte es dir nächste Woche erzählen, aber da du es erwähnt hast …
I was going to tell you next week, but since you mentioned it...
来週お伝えするつもりでしたが、おっしゃっていたので...
Ich glaube nicht, dass Sie ganz verstanden haben, welche Auswirkungen das auf das gesamte Projekt hat.
I don't think you've grasped quite what it'll do to the whole project,
それがプロジェクト全体にどのような影響を与えるか、まだよくわかっていないと思いますが、
insbesondere, was es mit mir macht. in particular what it'll do to me.
特にそれが私に何をもたらすのか。
- So schwarz kann es doch nicht sein, oder? - Doch, das ist es, verdammt noch mal.
- It can't be as black as all that, can it?
- Yes, it bloody well is.
- そんなに黒いわけないですよね？ - ええ、確かにそうです。
Das tut mir leid, aber Geschäft ist Geschäft.
Well, I'm sorry to hear that, but business is business.
そうですね、残念ですが、ビジネスはビジネスです。
- Ich bin kein Wohltätigkeitsbeauftragter. - William, ich flehe dich an.
- I'm not a charity commissioner.
- William, I'm begging you.
- 私は慈善事業委員ではありません。 - ウィリアム、お願いです。
Verdammt!
Damn it!
くそ！
Oh je.
Oh, dear.
まあ。
- Ich werde das klären. - Es tut mir leid.
- I'll clear that up.
- I'm sorry.
- それを明確にしておきます。 - 申し訳ありません。
Arthur, geh und hol einen Eimer.
Arthur, go and get a bucket.
アーサー、バケツを取って来なさい。
- Hast du ein Tuch? - ...Glas unter dem Tisch.
- Have you a cloth?
- ...glass under the table.
- 布は持ってますか？ - ...テーブルの下のグラス。
Scheint sehr nervös zu sein.
Seems very nervous.
とても緊張しているようです。
Wir lassen das für Sie vor Ort reinigen.
We'll have that cleaned for you at the house.
家で掃除してもらいますよ。
- ♪ Ich sammle im Mai gerne Nüsse – das habe ich von Lewis geliehen.
- ♪ I do like gathering nuts in May
- I borrowed it from Lewis.
- ♪ 5月にナッツを集めるのが好きです - ルイスから借りました。
- Erschossen, zu Tode erschrocken. - Alles in Ordnung, Sir?
- Shot, frightened to death.
- Everything alright, sir?
- 撃たれて、死ぬほど怖がっています。 - 大丈夫ですか、先生？
- Ich glaube, ich bin taub geworden. - Danke, Arthur.
- I think it's left me deaf.
- Thank you, Arthur.
- 耳が聞こえなくなったようです。 - ありがとう、アーサー。
Sie sagten doch, Sir William hätte die Wahl haben können,
You know how you said Sir William could've had his pick,
ウィリアム卿は選べると言ったでしょう
zwischen Lady Sylvia und Lady Stockbridge? between Lady Sylvia and Lady Stockbridge?
シルヴィア夫人とストックブリッジ夫人の間には?
- Ja. - Nun, ich habe Ihre Ladyschaft danach gefragt.
- Aye.
- Well, I asked Her Ladyship about it.
- ええ。 - ええ、私はそのことについて女主人に尋ねました。
Und sie sagte, sie hätten Karten für ihn geschnitten.
And she said they cut cards for him.
そして彼女は、彼のためにカードを切ったと言った。
- Nein! - Ich weiß.
- No!
- I know.
- いいえ！ - わかっています。
Ich kann es auch nicht glauben. Meinst du, das war ein Witz?
I can't believe it, either.
Do you suppose it was a joke?
私も信じられません。冗談だったと思いますか？
Nun, ich wäre mir nicht so sicher.
Well, I wouldn't be too sure.
まあ、よく分かりませんが。
Wissen Sie, was ich gehört habe?
You know what I heard?
何を聞いたか知ってる？
- Oh, hör mir einfach zu. - Was?
- Oh, just listen to me.
- What?
- ああ、私の言うことを聞いて。 - 何？
Warum verbringen wir unser Leben damit, sie zu erleben?
Why do we spend our lives living through them?
私たちはなぜそれらを通して人生を過ごすのでしょうか?
Ich meine, sehen Sie sich den armen alten Lewis an.
I mean, look at poor old Lewis.
つまり、かわいそうなルイスを見てください。
Wenn ihre eigene Mutter einen Herzinfarkt hätte,
If her own mother had a heart attack,
もし自分の母親が心臓発作を起こしたら、
Sie würde denken, es sei weniger wichtig als einer von Lady Sylvias Fürzen. she'd think it was less important than one of Lady Sylvia's farts.
彼女は、それがシルビア夫人の屁の一つよりも重要でないと思うだろう。
Du musst es wissen. Du kannst mich nicht täuschen.
You must know. You can't fool me.
あなたは知っているはずです。私を騙すことはできません。
Wenn es etwas gibt, was ich bei einem Dienstmädchen nicht erwarte, dann ist es Diskretion.
If there's one thing I don't look for in a maid, it's discretion.
私がメイドに求めていないことが一つあるとすれば、それは慎重さです。
Außer natürlich mit meinen eigenen Geheimnissen.
Except with my own secrets, of course.
もちろん、私自身の秘密を除いて。
Nun, ich weiß nicht viel, Mylady,
Well, I don't know much, milady,
まあ、あまり詳しくは知りませんが、
aber anscheinend rechnete er mit einer Investition von Sir William, but apparently he was counting on Sir William for an investment,
しかし、どうやら彼はウィリアム卿に投資を頼っていたようで、
und hatte sein Interesse garantiert, was auch immer das bedeutet. and had guaranteed his interest, whatever that means.
そしてそれが何を意味するにせよ、彼の利益を保証した。
Wie dem auch sei, Mr. Barnes, der Diener des Kommandanten,
Anyway, Mr. Barnes, the commander's valet,
とにかく、司令官の従者のバーンズ氏は、
er sagte, er wolle sofort gehen, he said he wanted to leave at once,
彼はすぐに出発したいと言った。
aber Lady Lavinia hat ihn überredet, bis morgen zu bleiben but Lady Lavinia's persuaded him to stay until tomorrow
しかしラヴィニア夫人は彼に明日まで滞在するよう説得した
um es weniger wichtig zu machen. to make less of a thing of it.
それをあまり重要視しないようにする。
Oh, Gott sei Dank.
Oh, thank heavens.
ああ、よかった。
Lewis hat mir gesagt, dass Sie Weiß tragen.
Lewis told me you were wearing white.
ルイスがあなたが白を着ていると言っていました。
Weiß? Sie muss verrückt sein. Ich trage nie Weiß.
White? She must be mad.
I never wear white.
白？彼女は怒っているに違いない。私は白を着ない。
Ich fand es ein wenig seltsam.
I thought it was a little odd.
ちょっと変だと思いました。
Übrigens, um Gottes Willen, reiben Sie ihn heute Abend nicht auf.
By the way, for God's sake, don't rub him up tonight.
ところで、お願いだから、今夜は彼を触らないで。
- Ich weiß nicht, was du meinst. - Du weißt genau, was ich meine.
- I don't know what you mean.
- You know exactly what I mean.
- 何を言っているのか分かりません。 - 私の言っていることは正確に分かっています。
Er ist allen gegenüber schlecht gelaunt.
He's in a filthy mood with everyone.
彼は誰に対しても不機嫌だ。
Er spricht davon, Ihnen das Taschengeld zu streichen.
He's talking about stopping your allowance.
彼はあなたのお小遣いを止めることについて話しています。
Aber es ist lebenslang. Das war abgemacht. Das kann er nicht machen.
But it's for life. That was settled.
He can't do that.
しかし、それは一生のことだ。それは決まっている。彼はそんなことはできない。
Beobachten Sie ihn einfach. Er ist absolut kampflustig.
Just you watch him.
He's absolutely spoiling for a fight.
彼を見てください。彼は絶対に戦いを望んでいます。
Wenn Sie also meinen Rat befolgen, geben Sie ihm keines.
So if you'll take my advice, you won't give him one.
だから、もし私のアドバイスに従うなら、彼に何も与えないで下さい。
Darüber können Sie diskret sein.
Now, that you can be discreet about.
さて、それについては慎重に考えてください。
Danke schön.
Thank you.
ありがとう。
Meine Güte, ist es hier nicht schön? Das Haus hat eine so schöne Lage.
Goodness, isn't it pretty here?
The house has such lovely position.
ああ、ここはきれいじゃないですか。家はすごく素敵な場所にあります。
Die beste Aussicht hat man vom alten Wasserturm. Da kann man morgen gut hinaufgehen.
The best view's from the old water tower.
You might well walk up there tomorrow.
古い給水塔からの眺めが一番いいです。明日はそこまで歩いて行ってもいいかもしれません。
Müssen Sie wirklich nach London zurück?
Do you really have to go back to London?
本当にロンドンに戻らなければならないのですか？
Ich fürchte ja, Raymond.
I am afraid so, Raymond.
残念ながらそうですよ、レイモンド。
Wenn man ruiniert ist, gibt es so viel zu tun.
When you're ruined, there's so much to do.
破産したら、やるべきことがたくさんあります。
Doch, das gibt es, nicht wahr? Stöhn, stöhn, stöhn.
Yes, there is, isn't there?
Moan, moan, moan.
はい、ありますよね？うめき声、うめき声​​、うめき声​​。
Hat jemand Lust auf eine Partie Bridge nach dem Abendessen?
Would anybody care for a game of bridge after dinner?
夕食後にブリッジをしたい人はいませんか?
Oh ja, das würde mir nichts ausmachen.
Oh, yes, I wouldn't mind.
ああ、はい、構いませんよ。
Wer noch? Louisa, wie sieht es mit dir aus?
Who else? Louisa, how about you?
他には？ルイザさん、あなたはどうですか？
Oh, das glaube ich nicht. Ich habe mich eher von den Karten abgewandt.
Oh, I don't think so.
I've rather gone off cards.
ああ、そうは思わない。むしろカードをやめたんだ。
Ich hatte mit ihnen nie viel Glück.
I've never been very lucky with them.
私は彼らとはあまり幸運に恵まれたことがありません。
Ich auch.
Me too.
私も。
Herr Weissman, erzählen Sie uns von dem Film, den Sie machen werden.
Mr. Weissman, tell us about the film you're going to make.
ワイズマンさん、あなたが作ろうとしている映画について教えてください。
Oh, sicher. Es heißt „Charlie Chan in London“. Es ist ein Krimi.
Oh, sure. It's called "Charlie Chan in London". It's a detective story.
ああ、もちろんです。タイトルは「ロンドンのチャーリー・チャン」です。探偵小説です。
- Spielt es in London? - Naja, nicht wirklich.
- Set in London?
- Well, not really.
- ロンドンが舞台ですか？ - まあ、そうでもないですね。
Ähm, das meiste davon spielt sich bei einem Jagdfest in einem Landhaus ab,
Erm, most of it takes place at a shooting party in a country house,
えーっと、ほとんどは田舎の家で行われる射撃パーティーで起こります。
eigentlich so ähnlich wie dieses hier. sort of like this one, actually.
実際、これと似ています。
Ein Mord mitten in der Nacht. Viele Gäste für das Wochenende.
A murder in the middle of the night.
A lot of guests for the weekend.
真夜中の殺人事件。週末にはたくさんの客が来る。
Jeder ist ein Verdächtiger ... Sie wissen schon, solche Sachen.
Everyone's a suspect...
You know, that sort of thing.
誰もが容疑者だ...そういうことだ。
Wie schrecklich.
How horrid.
なんてひどいんだ。
Und wer war es, der es getan hat?
And who turns out to have done it?
そして、それをやったのは誰なのでしょうか?
Das kann ich dir nicht sagen. Das würde dir die Spannung verderben.
I couldn't tell you that.
It would spoil it for you.
それは言えません。ネタバレになってしまいますから。
Oh, aber keiner von uns wird es sehen.
Oh, but none of us will see it.
ああ、でも誰もそれを見ることはないでしょう。
Denken Sie daran, es hierher zu schaffen, Mr. Weissman?
Are you thinking of making it here,
Mr. Weissman?
ワイスマンさん、ここに来るつもりですか？
Äh, nein, wir werden in Hollywood drehen, auf dem Außengelände.
Uh, no, we're going to shoot it in Hollywood, on the backlot.
えっと、いいえ、ハリウッドのバックロットで撮影するつもりです。
Aber da ich in England war,
But since I was in England,
しかし、私はイギリスにいたので、
Ich dachte, ich würde ein wenig über das Leben auf dem Land recherchieren
I thought I would do a little research on country living
田舎暮らしについて少し調べてみようと思った
und Ivor war so freundlich, es für mich zu arrangieren. and Ivor was kind enough to arrange it for me.
そしてアイヴァーは親切にも私のためにそれを手配してくれました。
Mmm, nein. William hat das für dich arrangiert.
Mmm, no.
William arranged it for you.
うーん、いいえ。ウィリアムがあなたのために手配しました。
Interessieren Sie sich für Filme, Sir?
Are you interested in films, sir?
映画に興味はありますか？
Unwahrscheinlich.
Not likely.
あり得ない。
Warum sollte ich mich nicht für Filme interessieren? Du weißt nicht, was mich interessiert.
Why shouldn't I be interested in films?
You don't know what I'm interested in.
なぜ映画に興味を持ってはいけないのでしょうか？あなたは私が何に興味を持っているか知らないのです。
Nun, ich weiß, dass Sie an Geld und am Hantieren mit Ihren Waffen interessiert sind,
Well, I know you're interested in money and fiddling with your guns,
まあ、君が金と銃をいじることに興味があるのは分かっているが、
aber bei allem anderen bin ich ratlos. but for anything else I'm stumped.
しかし、他のことについては困惑しています。
Das ist nicht fair. Bill ist...
That is not fair. Bill is...
それは不公平だ。ビルは...
Elsie.
エルシー。
Elsie, was ist...?
Elsie, what's...?
エルシー、何ですか…？
Es ist nicht so, als ob ich es nicht wüsste.
It's not as if I didn't know.
知らなかったわけではない。
Damit wir alle Bridge spielen können.
So we can all play bridge.
そうすればみんなでブリッジをプレイできます。
Alle spielen?
All playing?
みんな遊んでるの？
Wer wird Bridge spielen? Werden sie Bridge spielen?
Who's going to play bridge?
Are they going to play bridge?
誰がブリッジをプレイするのでしょうか？彼らはブリッジをプレイするつもりでしょうか？
Wo ist Rupert?
Where's Rupert?
ルパートはどこですか？
- Rupert! - Komme.
- Rupert!
- Coming.
- ルパート！ - 行きます。
- Ich habe gehört, dass Lady Sylvia ungefragt etwas gesagt hat. - Das haben Sie nicht wirklich gesehen?
- I heard Lady Sylvia spoke out of turn.
- You didn't actually see?
- シルビア夫人が順番を守らずに話しているのを聞きました。 - 実際には見ていなかったのですか?
Was wird also mit Elsie passieren?
So what's going to happen to Elsie?
それでエルシーはどうなるのでしょうか？
Sie kann von Glück reden, wenn sie nicht vor dem Morgen rausgeschmissen wird.
She'll be lucky if they don't boot her out before the morning.
朝までに追い出されなければ幸運だ。
Du hättest es sehen sollen.
You should've seen it.
君もそれを見るべきだったよ。
Sie ist schon lange hier.
She has been here a long time.
彼女は長い間ここにいます。
Soll ich Ihnen sagen, was das für sie bedeutet? Gar nichts.
Shall I tell you what that means to them? Bugger all.
それが彼らにとって何を意味するか説明しましょうか? 何も意味しません。
Bitte, Mr. Meredith. Es sind Damen anwesend.
Please, Mr. Meredith.
There are ladies present.
お願いします、メレディスさん。女性がいらっしゃいます。
Wo genau ist Sir William jetzt?
Where, exactly, is Sir William now?
ウィリアム卿は今、正確にはどこにいるのでしょうか?
Er ist noch in der Bibliothek. Er wird heute Abend nicht mehr rauskommen.
He's still in the library.
He won't be out again tonight.
彼はまだ図書館にいます。今夜はもう出かけません。
Dorothy.
ドロシー。
Herr Meredith, darf ich fragen, was los ist?
Mr. Meredith, may I ask what is going on?
メレディスさん、何が起こっているのか教えていただけますか？
Äh, wir waren nur...
Uh, we were just...
えっと、私たちはただ...
George, kommst du bitte so bald wie möglich zu mir ins Wohnzimmer.
George, will you please join me in the drawing room as soon as possible.
ジョージ、できるだけ早く応接室に来てください。
Herr Probert, bringen Sie bitte alle nach unten.
Mr. Probert, kindly take everybody downstairs.
プロバートさん、全員を階下へ案内してください。
- Sicher. - Dorothy, ich bin besonders von dir überrascht.
- Certainly.
- Dorothy, I'm especially surprised at you.
- 確かに。 - ドロシー、私はあなたに特に驚いています。
Kommen Sie mit, meine Damen. Kommen Sie mit.
Come along, ladies.
Come along.
さあ、女性の皆さん。さあ、来てください。
Stimmt das? Wurde Elsie wirklich entlassen?
Is it true, then?
Has Elsie really been sacked?
それは本当ですか？エルシーは本当に解雇されたのですか？
- Lady Trentham. - Tja, das war reine Glückssache.
- Lady Trentham.
- Well, luck of the draw.
- トレンサム夫人。 - まあ、運次第ですね。
- Freddie, ich würde gerne ... - Liebling, wir haben gerade geschnitten.
- Freddie, I'd like to...
- Darling, we've just cut.
- フレディ、私は... - ダーリン、私たちはちょうど切ったところです。
- Ivor, Liebling ... - Vielen Dank.
- Ivor, darling...
- Thank you so much.
- アイヴァー、ダーリン... - 本当にありがとう。
Wäre es schlimm von mir, Sie zu bitten, etwas zu spielen, um uns alle ein bisschen aufzuheitern?
Would it be awful of me to ask you to play something to cheer us all up a bit?
私たち全員を少しでも元気づけるために何かを演奏してくれないかと頼むのはひどいことでしょうか?
- Natürlich nicht. - Danke. So süß.
- Of course not.
- Thank you. So sweet.
- もちろんですよ。 - ありがとう。とても優しいですね。
Ich habe die erste Heimreise gebucht.
I've booked the first passage home.
帰国の第一便を予約しました。
Ich werde bis zur Abfahrt am Telefon leben. Morgen muss ich in London sein.
I'll be living on the phone till I set sail.
I have to be in London tomorrow.
出航するまでは電話で生活します。明日はロンドンに行かなければなりません。
Wenn Sie also lieber bleiben möchten, kann ich einen Zug nehmen.
So, if you prefer to stay,
I can take a train.
それで、もしあなたがここに留まりたいのであれば、私は電車に乗ることができます。
- Ich nehme Sie in meinem Auto mit. - Oh, danke.
- I'll give you a lift in my car.
- Oh, thank you.
- 私の車で送ってあげるよ。 - ああ、ありがとう。
Sie bieten viel Unterhaltung für nichts.
You're providing a lot of entertainment for nothing.
君は無料でたくさんのエンターテイメントを提供している。
Morris, ich bin daran gewöhnt.
Morris, I'm used to it.
モリス、慣れてるよ。
Verzeihung.
Excuse me.
すみません。
- Die Musik geht weiter. - Komischer Abend, was?
- Music moves on.
- Funny old evening, hmm?
- 音楽は流れ続ける。 - 面白い昔の夜だったね、うん？
♪ Irgendwo gibt es ein anderes Land
♪ Somewhere there's another land
♪ どこかに別の土地がある
- Oh! - ♪ Anders als dieser hier ...
- Oh!
- ♪ Different from this one...
- ああ！ - ♪ これとは違う...
Bitte, Sie werden mir nicht über die Schulter schauen.
You're not going to stand over my shoulder and watch me, please.
私の肩越しに監視したりしないでください。
- ♪ Weitaus gnädiger geplant – Du wirst mich abschrecken.
- ♪ Far more mercifully planned
- You'll put me off.
- ♪ もっと慈悲深く計画された - あなたは私を遠ざけるでしょう。
- Er ist ein ziemlich großer Erfolg. - ♪ Als der grausame Ort, den wir kennen
- He's rather a big success.
- ♪ Than the cruel place we know
- 彼はむしろ大成功だ。 - ♪ 私たちが知っている残酷な場所よりも
Riesig. Es ist absolut lächerlich.
Huge.
It's absolutely ridiculous.
巨大だ。まったく馬鹿げている。
♪ Unschuld und Frieden sind da
♪ Innocence and peace are there
♪ そこには無邪気さと平和がある
Glaubst du, er wird so lang sein wie sonst?
Do you think he'll be as long as he usually is?
彼はいつもと同じくらい長生きすると思いますか？
- ♪ Alles ist gut, was man sich wünscht – ich finde ihn ziemlich wunderbar.
- ♪ All is good that is desired
- I think he's rather wonderful.
- ♪ 望まれるものはすべて良いもの - 彼はむしろ素晴らしいと思います。
♪ Die Gesichter dort sind immer fair
♪ Faces there are always fair
♪ そこの顔はいつも美しい
♪ Die Liebe wird nie alt oder müde
♪ Love grows never old nor tired
♪ 愛は決して古びず、飽きることもない
Nun, ich habe nur einen gesehen.
Well, I have only seen one.
まあ、私は一つしか見たことがありません。
♪ Wir werden nie finden
♪ We shall never find
♪私たちは決して見つけられない
♪ Dieses schöne Land des Was-wäre-wenn
♪ That lovely land of Might-Have-Been
♪ ありえたかもしれない素敵な国
♪ Ich werde nie dein König sein
♪ I shall never be your king
♪ 私は決してあなたの王にはなれない
♪ Du sollst auch nicht meine Königin sein
♪ Nor you shall be my queen
♪ あなたは私の女王にはなれない
♪ Tage können vergehen und Jahre können vergehen
♪ Days may pass and years may pass
♪日が経ち、年が経つかもしれない
♪ Und Meere können dazwischen liegen ...
♪ And seas may lie between...
♪そして、その間には海があるかもしれない...
- Ich glaube nicht, dass wir das tun sollten. - Ach, komm schon.
- I don't think we should be doing this.
- Oh, come on.
- こんなことをするべきではないと思うよ。 - ああ、いい加減にしてくれ。
♪ Manchmal in den seltensten Nächten
♪ Sometimes on the rarest nights
♪ たまには珍しい夜に
♪ Die Vision kommt ...
♪ Comes the vision...
♪ ビジョンがやってくる...
Ich weiß nicht. Es ist nur...
I don't know. It's just...
分からない。ただ…
Ich meine, wie konnte sie zulassen, dass er sie berührt?
I mean, how could she let him touch her?
つまり、どうして彼女は彼に触れさせられるのでしょうか?
- Sie klingen, als ob Sie ihn nicht mögen. - Sie wären überrascht.
- You sound as if you don't like him.
- You'd be surprised.
- まるで彼が嫌いみたいだね。 - びっくりするよ。
- Na gut, überrasche mich. - Vielleicht werde ich das.
- Alright, surprise me.
- Maybe I will.
- わかった、驚かせてよ。 - 多分そうするよ。
Ich habe ihn in „The Lodger“ gesehen.
I saw him in "The Lodger".
私は彼を『The Lodger』で見ました。
Aber ich habe ihn nie persönlich singen gehört.
But I've never heard him sing in person.
しかし、私は彼が直接歌うのを聞いたことはありません。
♪ Hoffe, dass sie allein ihre Melodie spielt
♪ Hope that plays her tune alone
♪ 希望は一人で奏でる
♪ Liebe, die Schmerz und Tod besiegt ...
♪ Love that conquers pain and death...
♪ 痛みと死を克服する愛…
Würden Sie mich, ähm, einen Moment entschuldigen?
Will you, um, excuse me for a minute?
えっと、ちょっと失礼してもいいですか？
- Du brauchst meine Hilfe nicht? - Nein, uns geht es gut.
- You don't need my help?
- No, we're fine.
- 私の助けは要らないの？ - いいえ、大丈夫です。
Oh, mein Herr.
Oh, my Lord.
ああ、主よ。
♪ Es können Tage oder Jahre vergehen
♪ Days may pass or years may pass
♪日が経っても、年が経っても
♪ Die Meere können zwischen
♪ The seas may lie between
♪ 海は、
♪ Werden wir jemals finden
♪ Shall we ever find
♪ いつか見つけられるかな
♪ Unser schönes Land ...
♪ Our lovely land...
♪ 私たちの美しい土地...
Es scheint viel mehr zu sein als irgendwie bloße Hintergrundmusik.
It seems to be much more than just background music, somehow or other.
どういうわけか、それは単なるバックグラウンドミュージック以上のものであるようです。
Ivor, Liebling, es war wunderschön.
Ivor, darling, it was lovely.
アイヴァー、ダーリン、素敵だったよ。
Danke schön.
Thank you.
ありがとう。
♪ Ich scheine das Opfer eines grausamen Scherzes zu sein
♪ I seem to be the victim of a cruel jest
♪ 私は残酷な冗談の犠牲者のようだ
♪ Es folgt mir auf Schritt und Tritt mit dem Mädchen, das ich am meisten liebe ...
♪ It dogs my footsteps with the girl I love the best...
♪ それは私が最も愛する女の子との足跡をたどります...
Anthony...
アンソニー…
Psst, da ist der Kommandant!
Shh, it's the commander!
シーッ、司令官だよ！
- Oh! - Guten Abend, Sir.
- Oh!
- Good evening, sir.
- ああ！ - こんばんは。
- Entschuldigen Sie. - Sir.
- Excuse me.
- Sir.
- すみません。 - 先生。
Nein, mach weiter.
No, carry on.
いいえ、続けてください。
♪ Mein Auto wird sie treffen
♪ My car will meet her
♪私の車が彼女を迎えに行く
♪ Und ihre Mutter kommt auch
♪ And her mother comes, too
♪そして彼女のお母さんもやって来て
♪ Es ist ein Zweisitzer
♪ It's a two-seater
♪二人乗りです
♪ Trotzdem kommt auch ihre Mutter ... ♪
♪ Still her mother comes, too... ♪
♪ それでも彼女のお母さんも来ます... ♪
- Was möchtest du? - Ich habe dir Kaffee mitgebracht.
- What do you want?
- I brought you some coffee.
- 何が欲しいの？ - コーヒーを持ってきました。
Wenn ich Kaffee gewollt hätte, hätte ich geklingelt.
If I wanted coffee, I'd have rung for it.
コーヒーが欲しかったら、電話して頼んでいただろう。
Lass das. Gib mir etwas Whisky.
Leave that.
Give me some whiskey.
それはやめて。ウイスキーをください。
♪ Und ihre Mutter kommt auch
♪ And her mother comes, too
♪そして彼女のお母さんもやって来て
♪ Gefragt, dies nicht zu tun
♪ Asked not to do so
♪そうしないように頼んだ
♪ Trotzdem kommt auch ihre Mutter
♪ Still her mother comes, too
♪それでも彼女の母親も来る
♪ Sie kann einfach keine Abfuhr ertragen
♪ She simply can't take a snub
♪ 彼女はただ無視されるのが耐えられない
♪ Ich gehe und schmolle herum
♪ I go and sulk about
♪ 私はふてくされて
♪ Und nimm ein Bad im Club
♪ And take a bath at the club
♪クラブでお風呂に入る
♪ Und ihr Bruder kommt auch
♪ And her brother comes, too
♪そして彼女の弟もやって来る
♪ Und obwohl wir uns getrennt haben
♪ And though we've parted
♪そして私たちは別れてしまったけれど
♪ Und ihre Mutter kam auch
♪ And her mother came, too
♪そして彼女のお母さんも来た
♪ Drei Taschen, die ich geschleppt habe
♪ Three bags I carted
♪ ３つのバッグを運んだ
♪ Und ihre Mutter kam auch
♪ And her mother came, too
♪そして彼女のお母さんも来た
♪ Sie ist direkt neben dem Abschlag ohnmächtig geworden
♪ She fainted just off the tee
♪ 彼女はティーショットで気絶した
♪ Mein Liebling flüsterte mir zu ...
♪ My darling whispered to me...
♪ 愛する人が私にささやきました...
♪ Endlich sind wir frei
♪ At last we are free
♪ ついに私たちは自由になった
♪ Aber ihre Mutter kam auch ♪
♪ But her mother came, too ♪
♪でも彼女のお母さんも来たよ♪
Ich dachte, Sie könnten etwas zu trinken und Gesellschaft gebrauchen.
I thought you might need a drink and some company.
飲み物と誰かの付き添いが必要かもしれないと思ったんです。
Das ist wirklich sehr nett von Ihnen. Geben Sie mir nur eine Sekunde.
Well, that's really very kind of you.
Give me just a sec.
まあ、それは本当に親切ですね。ちょっと待ってください。
Schönes, langes Repertoire.
Lovely long repertoire.
素敵な長いレパートリー。
♪ Ich kann dir das Sternenlicht geben
♪ I can give you the starlight
♪ 星の光をあなたにあげられる
♪ Unveränderliche und wahre Liebe ...
♪ Love unchanging and true...
♪ 変わらぬ真実の愛…
Wir haben keine Milch mehr, Mr. Jennings. Es dauert nicht lange.
We've run out of milk, Mr. Jennings.
Won't be a moment.
ミルクがなくなりました、ジェニングスさん。すぐに届きますよ。
Hmm.
ふーむ。
Verzweifelt auf der Suche nach einer Zigarette.
Desperate for a fag.
タバコが欲しくてたまりません。
♪ Pools aus schimmerndem Blau
♪ Pools of shimmering blue
♪ きらめく青い水たまり
♪ Alles was ich sein kann
♪ All that I can be
♪ 私がなれるすべて
♪ Alles, was du von mir verlangst
♪ All you ask of me
♪あなたが私に求めるものはすべて
♪ Musik im Frühling
♪ Music in spring
♪ 春の音楽
♪ Blumen für einen König
♪ Flowers for a king
♪ 王様に花を
♪ All dies bringe ich dir
♪ All these I bring to you
♪これらすべてをあなたにもたらします
♪ Als ich jung war
♪ When I was young
♪ 若い頃
♪ Meine dummen Fantasien ...
♪ My foolish fancies...
♪ 私の愚かな空想...
Wo ist Mr. Weissmans Mann?
Where's Mr. Weissman's man?
ワイスマン氏の部下はどこですか?
- Ihm fehlt die Musik. - Psst.
- He's missing the music.
- Shh.
- 彼は音楽が恋しいんだ。 - シーッ。
♪ Ein bisschen Leben ...
♪ A little living...
♪ ちょっとした暮らし…
Was machst du? Dorothy, geh zurück an die Arbeit.
What are you doing?
Dorothy, get back to work.
何をしているの？ドロシー、仕事に戻って。
Entschuldigen Sie, aber Dorothy unterliegt ebenfalls meiner Gerichtsbarkeit, wissen Sie.
Excuse me, but Dorothy's under my jurisdiction as well, you know.
すみませんが、ドロシーも私の管轄下なのです。
Und ich sage, sie kann ein bisschen Musik hören, wenn sie möchte.
And I say she can listen to a spot of music if she likes.
そして、もし彼女が望むなら、少し音楽を聴いてもいいよ、と私は言います。
- Entschuldigen Sie. Wo ist das Telefon? - Oh. Es tut mir leid, Sir.
- Excuse me. Where's the telephone?
- Oh. I'm sorry, sir.
- すみません。電話はどこですか？ - ああ、申し訳ございません。
Äh, es ist gleich da drüben, Sir.
Uh, it's just over there, sir.
えっと、あそこにありますよ、先生。
♪ Ich kann dir die Berge geben
♪ I can give you the mountains
♪山をあげよう
♪ Pools aus schimmerndem Blau
♪ Pools of shimmering blue
♪ きらめく青い水たまり
♪ Rufen Sie an und ich kann
♪ Call and I can be
♪電話していただければ
♪ Alles, was du von mir verlangst
♪ All you ask of me
♪あなたが私に求めるものはすべて
♪ Musik im Frühling
♪ Music in spring
♪ 春の音楽
♪ Blumen für einen König
♪ Flowers for a king
♪ 王様に花を
♪ All das bringe ich dir ♪
♪ All these I bring to you ♪
♪これらすべてをあなたにお届けします♪
Nicht, nicht, nicht. Bitte ermutige ihn nicht. Er wird einfach immer weitermachen.
Don't, don't, don't. Please don't encourage him. He'll just go on and on.
やめてください、やめてください、やめてください。彼を励まさないでください。彼は延々と言い続けるだけです。
♪ Im Jahr 33 v. Chr.
♪ In BC 33
♪ 紀元前33年
♪ Ah, ich, das ist schon lange her
♪ Ah, me, that's a dash long time ago
♪ ああ、それはずいぶん昔のこと
♪ Es lebte ein römischer Held
♪ There lived a Roman hero
♪ ローマの英雄が住んでいました
♪ Der Nero die Hand geschüttelt hatte ...
♪ Who had shaken hands with Nero...
♪ ネロと握手したのは誰だ…
- Oh, du bist noch hier. - Ich dachte, dass ...
- Oh, you're still here.
- I thought that...
- ああ、まだここにいたんだね。 - そうかと思ったよ...
Ja, der Schein kann trügen, nicht wahr?
Yeah, well, appearances can be deceptive, can't they?
そうですね、見た目は騙されるものです、そうですよね？
- Elsie. - Gute Nacht.
- Elsie.
- Goodnight.
- エルシー。 - おやすみなさい。
♪ Wenn Sie sich also fragen, was ein Herzog sein sollte
♪ So if you wonder what a duke should be
♪公爵とはどんな人かと疑問に思うなら
♪ Schau mich nur noch einmal an
♪ Just you take another look at me
♪もう一度私を見て
♪ Ich bin zweifelnd, ich habe Gicht
♪ I'm doubty, I'm gouty
♪ 私は疑わしい、痛風だ
♪ Ich bin wunderbar zu sehen
♪ I'm wonderful to see
♪見ていて楽しい
♪ Alle meine Leute auf meiner Seele, es ist wahr
♪ All my people 'pon my soul, it's true
♪ 私の魂に宿るすべての人々、それは真実
♪ Schau dir Noah an, als er ankam
♪ Look on Noah as a parvenu
♪ ノアが到着したときのことを
♪ Mit Gad können Sie Ihren Stammbaum durchsuchen
♪ By gad, you can search your family tree
♪なんと、家系図を検索できるのです
♪ Aber du wirst nie einen Herzog wie mich finden
♪ But you'll never find a duke like me
♪ でも私のような公爵は見つからない
♪ Als der alte Knud einen Anzug kaufte
♪ When old Canute was buying a suit
♪ カヌート老人がスーツを買っていたとき
♪ Eines Tages, so erzählt man sich
♪ One day, so runs the tale
♪ある日、物語はこう語る
♪ Ein junger verurteilter Schwerverbrecher
♪ A young convicted felon
♪ 有罪判決を受けた若い犯罪者
♪ Brachte ihm eine saftige Melone
♪ Brought him a juicy melon
♪ジューシーなメロンを持ってきました
♪ Und wurde dann aus dem Gefängnis entlassen
♪ And was then released from jail
♪そして刑務所から釈放された
♪ Dieser edle Jüngling, um die Wahrheit zu sagen
♪ This noble youth, to tell the truth
♪ この高貴な若者は、実を言うと
♪ Sofort in See gesegelt
♪ Sailed right away to sea
♪すぐに海へ出航
♪ Und die Tochter des Herzogs von Malta
♪ And the Duke of Malta's daughter
♪そしてマルタ公爵の娘
♪ Brachte sein Rasierwasser hoch
♪ Brought up his shaving water
♪ シェービングウォーターを持ってきた
♪ Und das großartige Ergebnis war ich
♪ And the grand result was me
♪ そしてその結果は私
♪ Wenn Sie sich also fragen, was ein Herzog sein sollte
♪ So if you wonder what a duke should be
♪公爵とはどんな人かと疑問に思うなら
♪ Schau dir einfach noch mal an
♪ Just you take another look at m
♪もう一度見てみて
♪ Ich bin zweifelnd, ich habe Gicht
♪ I'm doubty, I'm gouty
♪ 私は疑わしい、痛風だ
♪ Ich bin wunderbar zu sehen
♪ I'm wonderful to see
♪見ていて楽しい
♪ Alle meine Leute auf meiner Seele, es ist wahr
♪ All my people 'pon my soul, it's true
♪ 私の魂に宿るすべての人々、それは真実
♪ Schau dir Noah an, als er ankam
♪ Look on Noah as a parvenu
♪ ノアが到着したときのことを
♪ Mit Gad können Sie Ihren Stammbaum durchsuchen
♪ By gad, you can search your family tree
♪なんと、家系図を検索できるのです
♪ Aber du wirst nie einen Herzog wie mich finden
♪ But you'll never find a duke like me
♪ でも私のような公爵は見つからない
♪ Wenn Sie sich fragen, was ein Herzog sein könnte
♪ If you wonder what a duke could be
♪公爵とはどんな人か疑問に思うなら
♪ Schau mich nur noch einmal an
♪ Just you take another look at me
♪もう一度私を見て
♪ Ich bin zweifelnd, ich habe Gicht
♪ I'm doubty, I'm gouty
♪ 私は疑わしい、痛風だ
♪ Ich bin wunderbar zu sehen
♪ I'm wonderful to see
♪見ていて楽しい
♪ Alle meine Leute auf meiner Seele, es ist wahr
♪ All my people 'pon my soul, it's true
♪ 私の魂に宿るすべての人々、それは真実
♪ Schau dir Noah an, als er ankam
♪ Look on Noah as a parvenu
♪ ノアが到着したときのことを
♪ Mit Gad können Sie Ihren Stammbaum durchsuchen
♪ By gad, you can search your family tree
♪なんと、家系図を検索できるのです
♪ Aber du wirst nie herausfinden ...
♪ But you'll never find...
♪ でも、あなたは決して見つけられないでしょう...
Das hat er dir zum Geburtstag geschenkt, oder?
He gave you that for your birthday, did he?
彼はあなたの誕生日にそれをくれたのですね？
Hmm?
ふーむ？
Er hat dir das zum Geburtstag geschenkt, William?
He gave you that for your birthday, William did?
ウィリアムがあなたの誕生日にそれをくれたんですか？
Ja, ich habe einen Anruf für Kalifornien gebucht.
Yeah, I've got a call booked for California.
ええ、カリフォルニアへの電話を予約しました。
Kalifornien.
California.
カリフォルニア。
♪ Wir sind beide zweifellos gesund
♪ We're both undoubtedly sane
♪ 僕たちは間違いなく正気だ
♪ Wir sind nicht so schrecklich schlicht
♪ We're not so horribly plain
♪ 僕らはそんなに平凡じゃない
♪ Irgendetwas stimmt nicht, aber wer kann uns sagen, was ...
♪ Something is wrong but who can tell us what...
♪ 何かがおかしいが、何がおかしいのかは誰にも分からない...
Oh, Freddie, wir haben dich aufgegeben.
Oh, Freddie, we gave up on you.
ああ、フレディ、私たちはあなたを諦めたんだ。
Wir warteten, so lange wir konnten.
We waited as long as we could.
私たちはできる限り待った。
Glaubst du, William ist noch in der Bibliothek?
Do you think William's still in the library?
ウィリアムはまだ図書館にいると思いますか？
- Wo warst du? - Hmm?
- Where have you been?
- Hmm?
- どこに行っていたの？ - ん？
- Ich nehme an. - Wo warst du?
- I suppose.
- Where have you been?
- そうだと思う。 - どこに行っていたの？
- Das geht dich nichts an. - Was sollen wir sonst tun?
- None of your business.
- What else are we going to do?
- あなたには関係ない。 - 他に何をするつもり？
- Nun, ich könnte versuchen, ihn abzuholen. - Oh, würdest du?
- Well, I could try and fetch him.
- Oh, would you?
- まあ、彼を連れて来てみるのもいいかな。 - ああ、そうしてくれる？
Er hat dich immer mir vorgezogen.
He's always preferred you to me.
彼はいつも私よりあなたの方を好んでいました。
Ja, das würde mich freuen.
Yes, I'd be delighted.
はい、喜んで。
♪ Du hast die Augengröße, die ich vergöttere
♪ You've got the size of eyes I idolize
♪君の目は私が憧れる大きさだね
- ♪ Deine Arme laden zu einer glamourösen Nacht ein – Heute ist nicht mein Tag.
- ♪ Your arms invite a glamorous night
- Today is not my day.
- ♪ あなたの腕が魅惑的な夜を誘う - 今日は私の日じゃない。
♪ Was soll ich tun?
♪ What am I to do?
♪ どうすればいいの？
♪ Warum bist du es nicht?
♪ Why isn't it you?
♪ どうしてあなたじゃないの？
Wenn das ein Moment ist,
If that's what you call a moment,
それが瞬間と呼ぶものなら、
Ich würde gerne sehen, was passiert, wenn Sie eine richtige Pause machen.
I'd like to see what happens when you take a real break.
本当に休憩を取ったらどうなるか見てみたいですね。
♪ Du hast die richtigen Lippen für mich, die richtigen Hüften für mich ...
♪ You've got the lips for me, the hips for me...
♪ 君の唇は僕にぴったり、腰も僕にぴったり…
Hier. Hab's auch gemacht. Bevor der Ansturm losgeht.
Here. Did yours as well.
Before the rush starts.
はい。あなたもそうしました。ラッシュが始まる前に。
Danke schön.
Thank you.
ありがとう。
♪ Warum bist du es nicht?
♪ Why isn't it you?
♪ どうしてあなたじゃないの？
♪ Warum müssen wir eine Chance wie diese verpassen?
♪ Why must we miss a chance like this
♪なぜこんなチャンスを逃さなければならないのか
♪ Wenn die Chancen gering sind?
♪ When chances are few?
♪チャンスが少ないときは？
- ♪ Deine Augen sind so groß, wie ich sie vergöttere. - Wo warst du?
- ♪ You've got the size of eyes I idolize
- Where have you been?
- ♪ あなたの目は私が憧れる大きさですね - どこに行っていたんですか?
- Es ist gut, es ist gut. - ♪ Deine Arme laden zu einer glamourösen Nacht ein ... ♪
- It's fine, it's fine.
- ♪ Your arms invite a glamorous night... ♪
- 大丈夫、大丈夫。 - ♪ 君の腕が魅惑の夜を誘う… ♪
Wilhelm?
William?
ウィリアム？
Oh Gott, Bill.
Oh, God, Bill.
ああ、神様、ビル。
Komm her, du scheußliches, kleines, dreckiges Ding.
Come here, you horrid little dirty thing.
こっちへ来いよ、このひどく汚い小悪魔め。
Rechnung!
Bill!
請求書！
♪ Du hast die Lippen für mich, die Hüften für mich
♪ You've got the lips for me, the hips for me
♪君の唇は僕のためのもの、腰は僕のためのもの
♪ Die Füße für mich und der Beat für mich ...
♪ The feet for me and the beat for me...
♪ 足は私のために、ビートも私のために…
♪ Also sag mir warum ... ♪
♪ So tell me why... ♪
♪ それで、理由を教えてください... ♪
- Lieber Gott! - Oh, mein Gott.
- Dear God!
- Oh, my God.
- ああ神様！ - ああ、なんてことだ。
Louisa!
ルイザ！
Isobel? Isobel?
イザベル？イザベル？
George. Entschuldigen Sie, Sir.
George. Excuse me, sir.
ジョージ。失礼しました。
Jennings.
ジェニングス。
Oh, meine Liebe.
Oh, my dear.
ああ、愛しい人よ。
Liebling? Liebling?
Darling? Darling?
ダーリン？ダーリン？
Könnte mir bitte jemand ein Glas Wasser bringen?
Could someone get a glass of water, please?
誰かコップ一杯のお水をもらえますか？
- Halten Sie alle aus diesem Raum fern. - Ja, Sir, auf jeden Fall.
- Keep everybody out of this room.
- Yes, sir, certainly.
- 誰もこの部屋に入れないでください。 - はい、もちろんです。
- Hierher. Louisa. - Bill.
- Over here. Louisa.
- Bill.
- こちらです。ルイザ。 - ビル。
- Louisa, setz dich einfach hin und sei still. - Aber ...
- Louisa, just sit and be quiet.
- But...
- ルイザ、ただ座って静かにしなさい。 - でも...
- Mama? - Bleib einfach da.
- Mummy?
- Just stay there.
- ママ？ - そこに居なさい。
- Geht es ihr gut? - Alles ist gut.
- Is she alright?
- Everything's fine.
- 彼女は大丈夫ですか？ - 大丈夫です。
Oh, Sylvia ...
Oh, Sylvia...
ああ、シルビア...
- Also, sagen Sie Mr. Warner ... - Entschuldigen Sie, ich brauche das Telefon.
- Well, tell Mr. Warner...
- Excuse me, I need that telephone.
- では、ワーナーさんに伝えてください... - すみません、あの電話が必要なんです。
Entschuldigen Sie, ich bin am Telefon. Ich telefoniere nach Kalifornien.
Excuse me, I'm on the telephone.
I'm on a call to California.
すみません、電話中です。カリフォルニアに電話中です。
Hallo? Ja, würden Sie mich bitte mit der Polizei verbinden?
Hello? Yes, would you connect me with the police station, please?
もしもし？はい、警察署につないでいただけますか？
Ich suche nach einer Art realistischem Charlie-Chan-Film.
I'm looking for a kind of realistic Charlie Chan movie.
現実的なチャーリー・チャンの映画を探しています。
Das ist nicht ausgeschlossen. Wir sollten versuchen, das zu tun.
This isn't out of the question.
We should try to do this.
これは不可能ではありません。私たちはこれを試してみるべきです。
Es muss besser werden. Wir können nicht immer wieder den gleichen Mist machen.
It has to be better. We can't do the same old shit over and over again.
もっと良くならないといけない。同じことを何度も繰り返すわけにはいかない。
Alan Mowbray... das gefällt mir. Ich meine, das ist ein Butler.
Alan Mowbray... I like that.
I mean, that's a butler.
アラン・モウブレイ…いいですね。だって、あれは執事ですから。
Diese Leute hier sehen aus wie Alan Mowbray.
These people here look like Alan Mowbray.
ここにいる人たちはアラン・モウブレイに似ています。
Ich meine, sie sind ziemlich groß und sagen nicht viel.
I mean, they're sort of tall, and they don't say too much.
つまり、彼らは背が高くて、あまり多くを語らないんです。
Und sie haben einen verdammten britischen Akzent, oder?
And they have fucking British accents, right?
それに彼らはイギリス訛りだよね？
Sie reden, als kämen sie aus England.
They talk like they're from England.
彼らはまるでイギリスから来たかのように話します。
- Guten Abend. - Ist Ray Milland Brite?
- Good evening.
- Is Ray Milland British?
- こんばんは。 - レイ・ミランドはイギリス人ですか？
- Abend. Hier spricht Constable Dexter ... - Sie müssen von der Polizei sein.
- Evening. This is Constable Dexter...
- You must be the police.
- こんばんは。こちらはデクスター巡査です... - 警察ですね。
- Ja, ich bin Inspektor Thom ... - Ich bin Lady Sylvia McCordle.
- Yes, I'm Inspector Thom...
- I'm Lady Sylvia McCordle.
- はい、トム警部です... - シルビア・マコードル夫人です。
Wir haben ihn nicht weggebracht. Ich habe alle versammelt. Kommt direkt durch.
We haven't moved him. I've gathered everyone. Come straight through.
彼を移動させていません。全員を集めました。まっすぐに来てください。
Mach dir keine Sorgen um ihn. Er ist nur ein Amerikaner, der bei uns wohnt.
Don't worry about him.
He's just an American staying with us.
彼のことは心配しないでください。彼は私たちと一緒に滞在しているだけのアメリカ人です。
Ich sage Ihnen, wer wir alle sind.
I'll tell you who we all are.
私たちが誰なのか教えましょう。
Dann können wir alle ins Bett gehen und dich mit dem armen William zurücklassen.
Then we can all go to bed and leave you with poor William.
そうすれば、私たちはみんな寝て、あなたはかわいそうなウィリアムと別れることになります。
- Klingt das nach einem guten Plan? - Ja, in der Tat.
- Does that sound like a good plan?
- Yes, indeed.
- それは良い計画のように思えますか? - ええ、確かに。
Soll ich mich vorstellen? Ich bin Inspektor Thom...
Shall I introduce myself?
I'm Inspector Thom...
自己紹介しましょうか？トム警部です…
– Das ist meine Tante, Lady Trentham. – Ah ja, die Gräfin von Trentham.
- This is my aunt, Lady Trentham.
- Ah, yes, the Countess of Trentham.
- こちらは私の叔母、トレンサム夫人です。 - ああ、そうです、トレンサム伯爵夫人です。
Ich habe mit Ihrem Mann auf einer ... gedient.
I served with your husband on a...
私はあなたの夫と一緒に...
Mein Schwager, Lord Stockbridge. Lady Stockbridge.
My brother-in-law Lord Stockbridge.
Lady Stockbridge.
私の義理の兄弟、ストックブリッジ卿。ストックブリッジ夫人。
Jennings, würden Sie dieses abscheuliche Tier bitte entfernen?
Jennings, please would you remove that vile animal?
ジェニングスさん、あの卑劣な動物を排除してもらえませんか？
- Sicherlich, Mylady. - Äh, Mrs. Nesbitt.
- Certainly, milady.
- Uh, Mrs. Nesbitt.
- もちろんです、お嬢様。 - えっと、ネスビット夫人。
Herr Nesbitt.
Mr. Nesbitt.
ネスビットさん。
Ivor Novello, der sicher keiner Vorstellung bedarf.
Ivor Novello, who I'm sure needs no introduction.
アイヴァー・ノヴェロについては、説明の必要はないと思います。
- Natürlich. Mr. Novello ... - Nein, warten Sie.
- Of course. Mr. Novello...
- No, wait.
- もちろんです。ノヴェロさん... - いや、待ってください。
Möchten Sie heute Abend mit dem Personal sprechen, Inspektor?
Would you like to speak to the servants tonight, Inspector?
今夜、使用人たちと話してみませんか、警部？
- Inspektor Thom ... - Er sollte mit dem Kammerdiener meines Mannes sprechen.
- Inspector Thom...
- He ought to speak to my husband's valet.
- トム警部... - 彼は私の夫の従者と話すべきです。
Sag ihm, er soll hochkommen. Wo war ich stehen geblieben?
Tell him to come up.
Now, where was I?
彼に上がるように伝えてください。さて、どこまで言いましたっけ?
- Äh ... Isobel McCordle, meine Tochter. - Charlie Chan ist in London.
- Uh... Isobel McCordle, my daughter.
- Charlie Chan is in London.
- えーと...イザベル・マコードル、私の娘です。 - チャーリー・チャンはロンドンにいます。
Er ist nicht in Kalifornien.
He's not in California.
彼はカリフォルニアにはいません。
Sie sprechen mit mir über Umschreibungen für die Rolle des Cockney-Dienstmädchens,
They're talking to me about rewrites about the part of the Cockney maid,
彼らはコックニーのメイドの役の書き直しについて私に話しています。
und sie rennt herein und sagt all diese Dinge. and she's running in and saying all these things.
そして彼女は走って来て、こんなことを言っています。
Schauen Sie, ich bin hier. Sie reden nicht.
Look, I'm here. They don't talk.
ほら、私はここにいる。彼らは話さない。
Die Butler und die Dienstmädchen stehen da und schauen zu.
The butlers and the maids, they stand, they watch.
執事やメイドたちは立って見守っています。
Ich meine, wissen Sie, sie dienen. Sie tun Dinge.
I mean, you know, they serve.
They do things.
つまり、彼らは奉仕するのです。彼らは何かをするのです。
Was ist mit Claudette Colbert? Sie ist Britin, oder?
What about Claudette Colbert?
She's British, isn't she?
クローデット・コルベールはどうですか？彼女はイギリス人ですよね？
Sie klingt britisch. Ist sie irgendwie gekünstelt oder ist sie Britin?
She sounds British.
Is she, like, affected, or is she British?
彼女はイギリス人っぽい口調ですね。彼女はイギリス人風に聞こえますか、それともイギリス人ですか?
Oh, Dorothy, würdest du nehmen...?
Oh, Dorothy, would you take...?
ああ、ドロシー、...を取ってもらえますか？
Ähm, also, ich...
Um, well, I...
えっと、そうですね、私は...
Komm schon, spuck es aus.
Come on, spit it out.
さあ、吐き出してください。
Die Polizei möchte Sie kurz sprechen.
The police would like to see you for a moment.
警察があなたにちょっと会いたがっています。
- Ich? - Nein, Mrs. Croft. Mr. Probert.
- Me?
- No, Mrs. Croft. Mr. Probert.
- 私ですか？ - いいえ、クロフト夫人。プロバートさん。
Ich? Warum?
Me? Why?
私ですか？なぜですか？
Nun ja.
Oh, well.
しかたがない。
Ich weiß nicht, was ich ihnen sagen kann.
I don't know what I can tell them.
彼らに何を言えばいいのか分からない。
George, könntest du nachsehen, ob im roten Salon noch etwas benötigt wird?
George, would you see if anything more is required in the red drawing room?
ジョージ、赤い応接室に何か他に必要なものがないか確認してもらえますか?
Ja, Sir.
Yes, sir.
はい、わかりました。
Ich sehe keinen Sinn darin, dass der Rest von euch noch wartet.
I don't see the point in the rest of you waiting up.
残りの皆さんが待つ意味がわかりません。
Was ist mit mir, Mr. Jennings?
What about me, Mr. Jennings?
私はどうですか、ジェニングスさん？
Sie können gehen, sobald die Polizei Sie freilässt.
You can go as soon as the police release you.
警察があなたを釈放したらすぐに出発できます。
Ich wage zu behaupten, dass das irgendwann morgen sein wird.
I daresay that'll be sometime tomorrow.
それは明日のいつかになると思います。
Bis dahin können Sie in Ihrem Zimmer bleiben.
Until then, you can stay in your room.
それまでは部屋に居てください。
Ich bin nicht ansteckend, wissen Sie.
I'm not contagious, you know.
僕は伝染性じゃないんだよ。
Niemand geht irgendwohin.
Nobody's going anywhere.
誰もどこにも行きません。
Diejenigen unter Ihnen, die noch Aufgaben zu erledigen haben, erledigen diese so schnell wie möglich.
Those of you with remaining duties, see to them as quickly as you can.
残っている任務がある人は、できるだけ早くこなしてください。
Ansonsten... gute Nacht allerseits.
Otherwise... goodnight, everyone.
そうでなければ...皆さん、おやすみなさい。
- Gute Nacht, Sir. - Gute Nacht, Sir.
- Goodnight, sir.
- おやすみなさい。 - おやすみなさい。
- Herr Jennings. - Ja, Herr Weissman?
- Mr. Jennings.
- Yes, Mr. Weissman?
- ジェニングスさん。 - はい、ワイスマンさん？
Ich muss etwas beichten.
I have a confession to make.
告白したいことがあります。
Stimmt, aber ich denke, es ist klar, dass der Diener es getan hat.
Right, but I think it's clear that it's the valet that did it.
そうですが、それをしたのは係員であることは明らかだと思います。
Nein, denn der Parkservice hat Zugang zu allen.
No, because the valet has access to everybody.
いいえ、係員は誰でもアクセスできるからです。
Nein, der Kammerdiener ist nicht der Butler.
No, the valet isn't the butler.
いいえ、係員は執事ではありません。
Nein, es gibt einen Butler und überall laufen viele Diener herum.
No, there's one butler, and there's lots of valets running all over the place.
いいえ、執事は一人しかいませんし、あちこちに係員がたくさんいます。
Er kümmert sich um die Menschen. Nachts ist er in ihren Zimmern.
He takes care of people.
He's in their rooms at night.
彼は人々の世話をします。夜は彼らの部屋にいます。
Er hätte es tun können. Ich meine, der Diener hätte es mit Leichtigkeit tun können.
He could do it. I mean, the valet easily could've done it.
彼ならできる。つまり、係員なら簡単にできたはずだ。
Reißen Sie sich zusammen, Herr Probert.
Pull yourself together, Mr. Probert.
しっかりしてください、プロバートさん。
Versuchen Sie, ein wenig Geduld zu haben. Sie werden in einer Minute da sein.
Try and be a bit patient.
They'll be along in a minute.
少し辛抱してください。彼らはすぐにやって来ます。
Könnte ich es ihm nicht einfach etwas bequemer machen, Sir?
Couldn't I just make him a little more comfortable, sir?
もう少し彼を安心させてあげられないでしょうか？
- Bitte? - Haben Sie ein Herz, Inspektor.
- Please?
- Have a heart, Inspector.
- お願いします？ - 心を持ってください、警部。
Nein, das wäre nicht klug, Sir. Wir sollten jetzt nicht mehr allzu lange warten müssen.
No, it wouldn't be wise, sir. We shouldn't have to wait too much longer now.
いいえ、それは賢明ではありません。もうあまり長く待つ必要はないでしょう。
Oh, ich glaube nicht, dass es schaden würde. Mach weiter.
Oh, I don't think it'd do any harm.
Go on.
ああ、害はないと思いますよ。続けてください。
Oh!
おお！
Ja, sehen Sie, aus diesem Grund haben wir Regeln und Vorschriften, nicht wahr?
Yes, well, you see, this is why we have rules and regulations, isn't it?
はい、そうですね、これが規則や規制がある理由ですよね？
Was ist los, Dexter?
What is it, Dexter?
何ですか、デクスター？
Nun, es scheint nur, dass nicht viel Blut fließt, Sir.
Well, only that there doesn't seem to be much blood, sir.
ええ、ただ、血はあまり出ていないようです、先生。
- Ist das alles, Mylord? - Ja, danke, Parks.
- Is that everything, milord?
- Yes, thank you, Parks.
- これで全部ですか、殿下？ - はい、ありがとう、パークス。
Ich denke, Sie sollten versuchen, etwas zu schlafen.
I think you should try and get some sleep.
少し眠るようにした方がいいと思います。
Es ist so unfair. Niemand mochte ihn.
It's so unfair.
Nobody liked him.
とても不公平だ。誰も彼を好きじゃなかった。
Hör auf zu jammern. Jeder würde denken, du wärst Italiener.
Do stop sniveling.
Anyone would think you were Italian.
鼻水を出すのはやめてください。誰もがあなたをイタリア人だと思うでしょう。
Christus!
Christ!
キリスト！
Dürfen wir Ihnen nicht mit Ihrem Kleid helfen, Mylady?
Will you not let me help you with your frock, milady?
お嬢様、ドレスの着替えを手伝わせていただけませんか？
Nein, ich komme zurecht.
No, I can manage.
いいえ、なんとかできます。
- Dann sage ich gute Nacht, Mylady ... - Nein, warten Sie, warten Sie.
- Then I'll say good night, milady...
- No, wait, wait.
- それではおやすみなさいと申し上げます、お嬢様... - いや、待ってください、待ってください。
Vielen Dank, Mylady.
Thank you, milady.
ありがとう、お嬢様。
Was ist das?
What is it?
それは何ですか？
Bitte sagen Sie mir, dass Sie nicht gekommen sind, um Ihr Beileid auszusprechen.
Please tell me you haven't come with condolences.
弔問に来なかったと言ってください。
Nein, ich habe mich nur gefragt, ob Sie möchten ...
No.
I was just wondering if you wanted...
いいえ。ただ、あなたが望むかどうか知りたかっただけです...
Was?
What?
何？
Ich sagte: „Ich habe mich nur gefragt, ob Sie etwas Gesellschaft möchten.“
I said, I was just wondering if you wanted some company.
私は、ただ誰かと一緒にいたいかどうか気になっただけだと言いました。
Nun ja, das Leben muss wohl weitergehen. Häng mich ab.
Well, I suppose life must go on.
Unhook me.
まあ、人生は続いていくのでしょう。私を外してください。
Nein, da ist noch einer. So kriegst du den nie weg.
No, there's another one.
You'll never get it off like that.
いや、もうひとつある。そんな風には絶対に取れないよ。
Es tut mir wirklich alles leid.
I'm really sorry about everything.
いろいろと本当に申し訳ありませんでした。
Hab kein Mitleid mit mir. Hab Mitleid mit der armen Dorothy.
Don't feel sorry for me. pity that poor Dorothy.
私を哀れに思わないでください。あの可哀想なドロシーを哀れんでください。
Sie muss den ganzen Morgentee zubereiten und die Frühstückstabletts bereithalten.
She's got all the early morning teas to do and the breakfast trays.
彼女は早朝のお茶の準備と朝食のトレイの準備をすべてやらなければなりません。
Und sie muss Miss Isobel ins Esszimmer bringen
And she's got to get Miss Isobel to the dining room
そして彼女はミス・イソベルをダイニングルームに連れて行かなければならない
und sehen, ob sie etwas in Schwarz finden kann. and see if she can find anything in black.
そして、黒いものが見つかるかどうか見てみましょう。
Sie ist diejenige, die Ihr Mitgefühl braucht. Ich bin da raus.
She's the one who needs your sympathy.
I'm well out of it.
あなたの同情を必要としているのは彼女です。私はもうその状態から抜け出しました。
Ich könnte mir vorstellen, dass Miss Isobel morgen im Bett bleibt.
I would think Miss Isobel might stay in bed tomorrow.
イソベルさんは明日もベッドで寝ているかもしれないと思う。
Unverheiratete Mädchen haben kein Frühstückstablett. Nicht in diesem Haus.
Unmarried girls don't have breakfast trays. Not in this house.
未婚の女の子には朝食用のトレイはありません。この家では無理です。
Ich wünschte, ich könnte helfen.
I wish I could help.
助けてあげられればよかったのですが。
Das kannst du nicht.
You can't.
あなたはできません。
„George sagt, Mr. Novello war darin verwickelt.
'George says
Mr. Novello was in on it.
「ジョージはノヴェロ氏もそれに加担していたと言っている。」
„Und Sir William.“
'And Sir William.'
「そしてウィリアム卿。」
Der Punkt ist, dass Henry Denton ein Schauspieler ist.
The point is, that Henry Denton, he's an actor.
要点は、ヘンリー・デントンは俳優だということです。
Ein Schauspieler?
An actor?
俳優？
Er spielt einen Butler im nächsten Charlie Chan. Ich wollte es authentisch machen.
He's playing a butler in the next Charlie
Chan. Wanted to make it authentic.
彼は次のチャーリー・チャンで執事役を演じます。本物らしくしたかったんです。
Ich würde sagen, der Witz ging auf Kosten von Lady Sylvia.
I'd say the joke was on Lady Sylvia.
冗談はシルビア夫人に向けられたものだと思います。
Ich hoffe, er orientiert sich bei seiner Leistung nicht an Mr. Jennings,
I hope he don't model his performance on Mr. Jennings,
彼がジェニングス氏を真似て演技をしないことを願っています。
oder er ist zu betrunken, um sich an seinen Text zu erinnern. or he'll be too squiffy to remember his lines.
さもないと、彼は酔っぱらってセリフを覚えられなくなってしまうでしょう。
Ah, Mrs. Croft, nicht wahr? Ich frage mich, ob ich ...
Ah, Mrs. Croft, isn't it?
I wonder if I could...
ああ、クロフト夫人、そうですよね？ 私にできるかな...
Ah, ja, ähm ... ich möchte kurz mit Ihnen sprechen. Ich bin Inspektor Thom ...
Ah, yes, er...have a few words with you.
I'm Inspector Thom...
ああ、はい、えーと...少しお話があります。トム警部です...
Oh, dafür habe ich jetzt keine Zeit. Ich mache das Frühstück.
Oh, I haven't got time for this now.
I'm doing the breakfast.
ああ、今は時間がない。朝食を作っているところ。
Es würde nicht lange dauern. Vielleicht haben Sie einen Raum, in dem wir sprechen könnten.
It wouldn't take much time. Perhaps you have a room where we could speak.
そんなに時間はかからないでしょう。話せる部屋があるかもしれませんよ。
Oh, ich schätze, du solltest besser in mein Zimmer kommen.
Oh, I suppose you'd better come to my room.
ああ、私の部屋に来たほうがいいと思います。
Bertha, ich überlasse dir die Verantwortung.
Bertha, I'm leaving you in charge.
バーサ、あなたに任せます。
Dorothy, stellen Sie sicher, dass diese Menüs auf dem Tablett Ihrer Ladyschaft landen.
Dorothy, make sure those menus go up on Her Ladyship's tray.
ドロシー、そのメニューが女王陛下のトレイに載せられるようにしてください。
Und schaffen Sie diesen dreckigen Hund hier raus!
And get that filthy dog out of here!
そしてその汚い犬をここから追い出せ！
Ehrlich gesagt wird es auf dem Land heutzutage gefährlicher als in Piccadilly.
Honestly, these days the countryside's getting more dangerous than Piccadilly.
正直に言うと、最近はピカデリーよりも田舎の方が危険になってきています。
Aber warum eines der Messer aus der Silberkammer?
But why one of the knives from the silver pantry?
しかし、なぜ銀のパントリーからナイフが1本出てきたのでしょうか?
Das ergibt keinen Sinn.
Doesn't make sense.
意味が分かりません。
Er muss vergessen haben, eins mitzubringen.
He must have forgotten to bring one.
彼は持ってくるのを忘れたに違いない。
Wenn man bedenkt, was sie alles mit sich herumtragen müssen,
When you think of what they have to carry about,
彼らが何を運ばなければならないかを考えると、
all diese Brecheisen und Fackeln und Dietriche, all those jemmies and torches and skeleton keys,
ジェミーやトーチやスケルトンキーなど
Es ist ein Wunder, dass überhaupt jemals eingebrochen wird. it's a miracle anyone ever gets burgled at all.
誰かが強盗に遭うなんて奇跡だ。
Oh, es ist eisig hier. Hol mir mein Fell, ja?
Oh, it's glacial in here.
Get my fur, will you?
ああ、ここは氷のように冷たい。私の毛皮を取ってくれないか？
Jedenfalls war es nicht in der Silberkammer.
Anyway, it wasn't in the silver pantry.
とにかく、それは銀色のパントリーにはありませんでした。
Es fehlt seit gestern.
It's been missing since yesterday.
昨日から行方不明です。
Offensichtlich hatte William es.
Obviously William had it.
明らかにウィリアムはそれを持っていました。
Und als der Kerl ihn überraschte, da war es,
And when the fellow surprised him, there it was,
そしてその男が彼を驚かせたとき、そこには
auf dem Tisch so griffbereit wie Sie möchten. on the table as handy as you like.
テーブルの上なら好きなだけ便利に使えます。
Steht einer der anderen zum Frühstück auf? Die Frauen, meine ich.
Are any of the others getting up for breakfast? The women, I mean.
他の人は朝食のために起きますか？女性たちです。
Ich glaube, Lady Lavinia könnte es sein.
I think Lady Lavinia may be.
ラヴィニア夫人はそうかもしれないと思う。
Das ist geklärt. Komm um halb neun wieder. Ich ziehe mich an.
That settles it. Come back at half past eight. I'll get dressed.
それで決まりです。8時半に戻ってきてください。着替えてきます。
Das ist natürlich mega langweilig, aber ich will nichts verpassen.
It's the greatest bore, of course, but I don't want to miss anything.
もちろん、それは非常に退屈なことですが、何も見逃したくありません。
Als ich gestern Abend zurückkam, fand ich das auf meiner Frisierkommode.
When I came back last night,
I found this on my dressing table.
昨晩帰宅したら、化粧台の上にこれがありました。
Was ist das?
What is it?
それは何ですか？
„Dies ist Ihre letzte Warnung. Wenn ich kein Angebot erhalten habe …“
"This is your final warning.
If I've not received an offer..."
「これは最後の警告です。もしオファーを受け取っていないなら…」
Freddie. Was für ein dummer Idiot.
Freddie. What a stupid idiot.
フレディ。なんて愚かなバカなんだ。
Na ja, wenigstens hast du ihn jetzt nicht mehr im Nacken. Es gibt niemanden, dem du es erzählen könntest.
Well, at least he's off your back now.
There's no one to tell.
まあ、少なくとも彼はもうあなたの背後にはいない。誰にも言うことはない。
Zumindest gibt es niemanden, der ihm einen Job gibt, um ihn zum Schweigen zu bringen.
At least no one's who's gonna give him a job to shut him up.
少なくとも、彼を黙らせるために仕事を与える人は誰もいない。
Ha-ha! Oh, er ist ein richtig hübscher Junge, nicht wahr?
Ha-ha! Oh, now, he's quite the bonny lad, isn't he?
ハハハ！ああ、彼は本当にかわいい子だね。
Was macht der denn so in letzter Zeit, dieser hier, hm?
What's he up to these days, this one, eh?
彼は最近何をしているんだろう、この人？
Er ist tot.
He's dead.
彼は死んだ。
Ich weiß nicht, was ich Ihnen sagen kann.
I don't know what I can tell you.
何を言えばいいのか分かりません。
Sollten Sie nicht nach Anzeichen eines Einbruchs suchen?
Shouldn't you be looking for signs of a break-in?
侵入の痕跡を探すべきではないですか?
Die Sache ist die, Mrs. Croft, ich verstehe, dass niemand Sir William gedient hat
The thing is, Mrs. Croft, I understand that no one has served Sir William
問題は、クロフト夫人、ウィリアム卿に仕えた人は誰もいないということです
länger als du, stimmt das? longer than you have, is that true?
あなたより長い、それは本当ですか？
Ich sollte jetzt besser gehen. Vielleicht sehe ich dich nie wieder.
I'd better be off.
Might not see you again.
もう行かなきゃ。もう二度と会えないかもしれないから。
Ich bleibe nur, bis die Polizei ihr Einverständnis gibt.
I'm only staying till the police give the nod.
私は警察が許可を出すまでだけここに留まります。
Aber, Elsie ...
But, Elsie...
でも、エルシーは…
Sie stecken doch nicht in Schwierigkeiten, oder?
You're not in any difficulty, are you?
何か困ったことはありませんか？
Was, außer kein Zuhause und keinen Job zu haben?
What, apart from having no home and no job?
家も仕事もない以外に何があるの？
Nein, da gibt es keinen Grund zur Sorge.
Nah. There's no worries there.
いや、心配する必要はない。
Ja, ich hatte es vergessen. Du warst viel schlauer als ich.
Yes, I was forgetting.
You were much cleverer than I was.
はい、忘れていました。あなたは私よりもずっと賢かったです。
Es wird dir gut gehen.
You'll be fine.
大丈夫だよ。
Ich frage mich, was Lady Sylvia jetzt tun wird.
I wonder what Lady Sylvia will do now.
シルビア夫人はこれからどうするのだろうか。
Wenn ich sie wäre, würde ich mich in London als glamouröse Witwe niederlassen,
If I were her, I'd set up in London as a glamorous widow,
もし私が彼女だったら、ロンドンで華やかな未亡人として暮らしていただろう。
mit all den Herren, die hinter mir her sind, um mein Geld zu bekommen. with all the gentlemen chasing me for my money.
紳士たちがみんな私を追いかけてお金を取ってきました。
Das würde ich nicht tun. Ich bin in London aufgewachsen.
I wouldn't. I grew up in London.
そうは思いません。私はロンドンで育ちました。
- War dort das Waisenhaus? - Am Rand. Isleworth.
- Is that where the orphanage was?
- On the edge. Isleworth.
- そこが孤児院があった場所ですか？ - 端っこです。アイルワースです。
Und Sie haben kein Heimweh?
And you don't get homesick?
ホームシックにならないんですか？
Ich glaube nicht, dass man Heimweh bekommt, wenn man nie ein Zuhause hatte.
I don't think you get homesick if you've never had a home.
一度も家を持ったことがなければ、ホームシックになることはないと思います。
Haben Sie von Mr. Weissmans Kammerdiener gehört? Es stellt sich heraus, dass er ein Betrüger ist.
Heard about Mr. Weissman's valet?
Turns out he's a fraud.
ワイスマン氏の従者のことを聞きましたか？彼は詐欺師であることが判明しました。
- Er ist überhaupt kein Schotte. - Nein!
- He isn't Scottish at all.
- No!
- 彼はスコットランド人じゃないよ。 - 違うよ！
Das hätte ich dir sagen können.
I could've told you that.
あなたにそう言うこともできたのに。
- Wer ist er dann? - Glauben Sie, dass er der Mörder ist?
- Who is he, then?
- Do you think he's the murderer?
- それで彼は誰ですか？ - 彼が殺人犯だと思いますか？
Es ist schlimmer als das. Er ist Schauspieler.
It's worse than that.
He's an actor.
それより悪いです。彼は俳優です。
Ja, ich möchte, dass du ihn weckst. Wie soll ich sonst mit ihm reden?
Yes, I want you to wake him up.
How else do you suggest I talk to him?
はい、彼を起こしてほしいです。他にどうやって彼と話をしたらいいと思いますか？
Ja. Stimmt. Was hat er denn gesagt? Was, er redet schon wieder von Clara Bow?
Yes. Right. Well, what did he say?
What, he's talking about Clara Bow again?
はい。その通りです。それで、彼は何と言いましたか？またクララ・ボウのことを言っているのですか？
Hören Sie, sagen Sie Sheehan, dass ich Clara Bow für eine wirklich nette Person halte.
Listen, you tell Sheehan that I think
Clara Bow's a really nice person,
いいかい、シーハンにクララ・ボウは本当にいい人だと思うって伝えて
und sie kommt nicht näher als zehn Meilen an mein Bild heran. and she's not coming in ten miles of my picture.
そして彼女は私の写真から10マイル以内には来ない。
Ich will sie nicht in dem verdammten Film.
I don't want her in the fucking movie.
彼女をそのクソ映画に出させたくない。
Eines ist sicher: Der Tod dieses Mistkerls hat mir vielleicht den Arsch gerettet.
There's one thing. The bastard's death may have saved my bacon.
一つだけある。あの野郎の死が私を救ったかもしれない。
Um Gottes Willen, sei still. Was ist los mit dir?
For God's sake, be quiet.
What's the matter with you?
お願いだから静かにして。どうしたの？
Arthur...
アーサー…
- Oh, sind das Tomaten? - Ja, Mylady.
- Oh, are these tomatoes?
- Yes, milady.
- ああ、これはトマトですか？ - はい、お嬢様。
Das ist genau das, was ich will.
That's exactly what I want.
まさにそれが私が望んでいることです。
- Guten Morgen. - Morgen, Liebling.
- Good morning.
- Morning, dear.
- おはようございます。 - おはようございます。
Schon gehört?
Have you heard?
聞いたことありますか？
Es ist zu ermüdend. Dieser schreckliche Inspektor lässt niemanden gehen.
It's too tiresome. That frightful inspector won't let anyone leave.
面倒すぎる。あの恐ろしい検査官は誰も帰らせてくれない。
So wird uns ein weiterer Tag beschert
So we're to be treated to another day
それでまた別の日を楽しもう
von Herrn Weissman, der ins Telefon schreit. of Mr. Weissman shouting down the telephone.
ワイスマン氏が電話越しに叫んでいる。
Ich fürchte, er hat einige Probleme mit seiner Arbeit in Los Angeles.
He has some problems with his work in Los Angeles, I'm afraid.
残念ながら、彼はロサンゼルスでの仕事でいくつか問題を抱えているようです。
Nun, ich muss sagen, er führt seine Geschäfte sehr merkwürdig.
Well, I must say, he conducts his affairs very oddly.
まあ、彼は物事を非常に奇妙に扱っていると言わざるを得ません。
Gerade eben dachte ich, ich wäre in eine Bar in Marseille versetzt worden.
Just now, I thought I'd been transported to a bar in Marseilles.
たった今、マルセイユのバーに来たかと思った。
Jennings? Entschuldigen Sie, es tut mir leid.
Jennings?
Excuse me, I'm sorry.
ジェニングス？すみません、すみません。
Ich erwarte einen wirklich wichtigen Telefonanruf.
I'm expecting a really important telephone call.
本当に重要な電話がかかってくると思います。
Erwischen Sie mich, sobald es eintrifft?
Will you get me the second it comes through?
届いたらすぐに連絡してもらえますか？
Sehr gut, Sir.
Very good, sir.
結構です、先生。
Und ich hätte gern, äh, oh ... Tomaten und Eier. Danke.
And I'd like, uh, oh... tomato and eggs.
Thank you.
それから、えーと、トマトと卵もお願いします。ありがとう。
Natürlich, Sir, aber ...
Of course, sir, but...
もちろんです、しかし…
Vielleicht möchten Sie lieber selbst wählen, Sir? perhaps you would prefer to choose for yourself, sir?
おそらく、あなた自身で選択することを好むのではないでしょうか？
Was meinst du mit „im Cafeteria-Stil“?
What do you mean, like cafeteria style?
カフェテリアスタイルってどういう意味ですか？
Der Engländer wird beim Frühstück nie bedient.
The Englishman is never waited on at breakfast.
イギリス人は朝食時に決して給仕を受けない。
Wirklich? Nun, das ist interessant, denn ein Amerikaner ist es.
Really? Well, that's interesting, because an American is.
本当ですか？まあ、アメリカ人はそうなので、それは興味深いですね。
Wow! Das werde ich mir merken.
Wow!
I'm going to make a note of that.
わあ！メモしておきます。
Guten Morgen.
Good morning.
おはよう。
Morgen.
Morning.
朝。
Ich hätte gerne einen Kaffee, Jennings.
I'd like some coffee, Jennings.
コーヒーをください、ジェニングス。
Da ist es.
There it is.
そこにあるよ。
Ah. Gut. Guten Morgen, meine Damen und Herren.
Ah. Good.
Good morning, ladies, gents.
ああ。よかった。おはようございます、皆さん。
Ähm, ich frage mich ... Entschuldigen Sie.
Um, I wonder...
Excuse me.
えっと、何だろう... 失礼。
Äh, kommt Lady Sylvia bald runter?
Uh, will Lady Sylvia be coming down soon?
えっと、シルビア様はもうすぐ降りて来られますか？
Das glaube ich nicht. Sie frühstückt in ihrem Zimmer.
I shouldn't think so.
She has breakfast in her room.
そんなことはないと思います。彼女は部屋で朝食を食べます。
Dann macht sie normalerweise eine Fahrt.
Then she usually goes for a ride.
それから彼女はたいてい乗りに行きます。
Ja, aber das wird sie heute Morgen nicht tun, oder?
Yes, but she won't be doing that this morning, will she?
はい、でも彼女は今朝はそんなことしないですよね？
Nun, ich verstehe.
Well, I see.
なるほど。
Nun, in diesem Fall frage ich mich, Lady Trentham,
Well, in that case I wonder,
Lady Trentham,
まあ、その場合、トレンサム夫人、
wenn Sie so freundlich wären, sich uns für einige Fragen anzuschließen. if you would be kind enough to join us for some questions.
ぜひご参加いただき、いくつか質問していただければ幸いです。
Wenn Sie wünschen, Inspektor.
If you wish, Inspector.
よろしければ、警部。
Ich fürchte, ich werde nicht viel helfen können,
I'm afraid I won't be much help,
あまり役に立たないかもしれないけど、
aber ich schätze, an einem Tag wie diesem müssen wir alle unseren Beitrag leisten. but I suppose on a day like this we all have to pull our weight.
しかし、こういう日には私たち全員が責任を果たさなければならないと思います。
„Mr. Denton hat aus Mr. Jennings einen richtigen Trottel gemacht.“
'Mr. Denton made a right chump out of Mr. Jennings.'
「デントン氏はジェニングス氏を本当にバカにしたんだ。」
Das ist egal. Haben Sie von Sir William gehört?
Never mind that.
Did you hear about Sir William?
それは気にしないでください。ウィリアム卿について聞きましたか?
Offenbar wurde er doch nicht erstochen.
Apparently, he wasn't stabbed after all.
どうやら、結局刺されていなかったようだ。
Also, ich meine, das war er, aber das ist nicht der Grund für seinen Tod.
Well, I mean, he was, but that's not why he died.
まあ、そうだったけど、それが死んだ理由じゃない。
Er wurde vergiftet. Daran starb er.
He was poisoned.
That's what killed him.
彼は毒を盛られた。それが彼の死因だ。
Der Inspektor informierte Mrs. Croft.
The inspector told Mrs. Croft.
検査官はクロフト夫人にそう告げた。
Sie wissen nicht, warum der Mörder auch ihn erstochen hat.
They don't know why the killer stabbed him as well,
犯人がなぜ彼を刺したのかも分からない。
aber er muss schon tot gewesen sein. but he must've been dead already.
しかし、彼はすでに死んでいたに違いない。
Deshalb gab es kein Blut.
That's why there was no blood.
だから血は出なかったのです。
Tote Körper bluten nicht, wissen Sie?
Dead bodies don't bleed, you know?
死体からは血は出ないんだよ、知ってる？
Vertrauen Sie darauf, dass Sir William zweimal ermordet wurde.
Trust Sir William to be murdered twice.
ウィリアム卿が二度殺されると信じてください。
Natürlich wurde er nicht ermordet. Nicht diese Art von Mord.
Of course he wasn't murdered.
Not that sort of murder.
もちろん彼は殺されたわけではない。そんな種類の殺人ではない。
Ein Raufbold brach ein, weil er dachte, die Bibliothek sei leer.
Some ruffian broke in, thinking the library was empty,
図書館が空だと思い込んでいた悪党が侵入し、
Sir William überraschte ihn und zahlte den Preis dafür.
Sir William surprised him and paid the price for it.
ウィリアム卿は彼を驚かせ、その代償を払った。
Und es ist auch sehr tragisch.
And very tragic it is too.
そしてそれはとても悲劇的でもあります。
Das kann ich nicht erkennen, Mr. Jennings.
I can't see that, Mr. Jennings.
それは分かりません、ジェニングスさん。
Ich glaube nicht, dass Raufbolde Leute vergiften
I don't think ruffians go about poisoning people
悪党が人を毒殺するとは思えない
und dann die Leichen erstochen. and then stabbing the corpses.
そして死体を刺し殺した。
Abgesehen von allem anderen,
Apart from anything else,
何よりも、
sie haben es normalerweise eilig, wegzukommen, nicht wahr? they're usually in a hurry to get away, aren't they?
彼らはたいてい逃げようと急いでいますよね？
Was schlagen Sie vor?
What are you suggesting?
何を提案しているのですか?
- Ich schlage nichts vor. Es ist nur ... - Nur was?
- I'm not suggesting anything. It's just...
- Just what?
- 何も提案しているわけではありません。ただ... - 一体何ですか?
Nun ja, für mich sieht es so aus, als wäre Sir William vorsätzlich getötet worden, das ist alles.
Well... it looks to me like Sir William was killed deliberately, that's all.
ええと...ウィリアム卿は故意に殺されたように見えます、それだけです。
Kein Wunder, dass sie keinen von uns gehen lassen.
No wonder they're not letting any of us go.
彼らが我々を誰も解放しないのも不思議ではない。
Pech für alle, die Geheimnisse zu verbergen haben.
Tough luck on whoever's got any secrets to hide.
秘密を隠している人にとっては不運だ。
Jetzt haben sie die Dreharbeiten abgesagt,
Now they've cancelled the shooting,
撮影は中止になったが、
Der Idiot hier muss für Gott weiß wie viele ein Mittagessen aus dem Hut zaubern. muggins here has got to pull a luncheon for God knows how many out of the hat.
ここのマギンズは、帽子の中から神のみぞ知る何人分の昼食を用意しなければならない。
- Ist Ihre Ladyschaft schon zurück? - Nein.
- Is Her Ladyship back yet?
- No.
- 女主人はもう戻ってきましたか? - いいえ。
Nun ja, sie muss nehmen, was sie kriegt.
Well, she'll have to take what she gets.
まあ、彼女は与えられたものを受け入れるしかないでしょう。
Warum sollte jemand Sir William töten wollen?
Why would anyone want to kill Sir William?
なぜ誰かがウィリアム卿を殺したいのでしょうか?
Nun ja, er war nicht gerade der Weihnachtsmann!
Well, he wasn't exactly
Father Christmas!
まあ、彼はまさにサンタクロースではありませんでした！
Oh, machen Sie mit Ihrer Arbeit weiter.
Oh, get on with your work.
ああ、仕事を続けてください。
Und schaffen Sie diesen dreckigen Hund hier raus!
And take that filthy dog out of here!
そしてその汚い犬をここから連れ出せ！
Er hat sich im Laufe der Zeit ein paar Feinde gemacht, das ist alles.
He made a few enemies in his time, that's all.
彼は在職中に数人の敵を作った、それだけだ。
Was meinst du mit Feinden? Wann?
What do you mean, enemies? When?
敵ってどういう意味ですか？いつですか？
War das vor dem Krieg, Mrs. Croft, als Sie Fabrikarbeiterin waren?
Is this before the war, Mrs. Croft, when you were a factory worker?
クロフトさん、これは戦前、あなたが工場で働いていた頃ですか？
Ich war kein Fabrikarbeiter. Ich war nie ein Fabrikarbeiter.
I was not a factory worker.
I was never a factory worker.
私は工場労働者ではありませんでした。私は工場労働者だったことはありません。
Ich war Koch in einer seiner Fabriken.
I was a cook in one of his factories.
私は彼の工場の一つで料理人をしていました。
Er hatte zwei in Isleworth und zwei in Twickenham, und alle voller Mädchen,
He had two in Isleworth and two in Twickenham, and all full of girls,
彼はアイルワースに2軒、トゥイッケナムに2軒所有しており、いずれも女の子ばかりだった。
Sie können es sich also vorstellen. so you can imagine.
想像できるでしょう。
War das mit den Fabrikmädchen nicht riskant? Was, wenn sie sich beschwerten?
Wasn't that risky with factory girls?
Suppose they complained?
工場の女たちにとっては危険ではなかったですか？ 彼女たちが苦情を言ったら？
An wen genau?
Who to, exactly?
具体的に誰に？
Aber was wäre, wenn sie in Schwierigkeiten gerieten?
But what if they got, you know, in trouble?
でも、もし彼らがトラブルに巻き込まれたらどうなるでしょうか？
- Was für ein Ärger? - Hier, nimm das. Nur Weiße, okay?
- What sort of trouble?
- Here, take these. Whites only, alright?
- どんなトラブル？ - さあ、これを受け取って。白人限定でいいかな？
Kam nicht sehr oft vor.
Didn't happen very often.
あまり頻繁には起こりませんでした。
Als dies der Fall war, veranlasste er die Adoption.
When it did, he arranged to have it adopted.
それが起こったとき、彼はそれを養子に出す手配をしました。
Aber was wäre, wenn Sie es gar nicht adoptieren möchten? Oder es lieber behalten möchten?
But what if you didn't want it adopted?
Say you wanted to keep it?
しかし、養子縁組を望まなかったらどうしますか？ 飼っておきたいとしたらどうしますか？
Dann wurden Sie rausgeschmissen und haben Ihren Job verloren.
Then you got kicked out, lost your job.
その後、あなたは追い出され、仕事を失いました。
Sie können mir glauben, er war ein hartherziger, geiler alter Kerl.
You can take my word for it, he was a hard-hearted, randy old sod.
私の言うことを信じてください、彼は冷酷で好色な老人でした。
Ah, kommen Sie herein, Miss Maceach ... ich bin Inspektor Thom ...
Ah, come in, Miss Maceach...
I'm Inspector Thom...
ああ、入ってください、ミス・マックチ...私はトム警部です...
Das ist alles zu ermüdend und absurd.
This is all too tiresome and absurd.
これはあまりにも退屈で不条理です。
Er macht einen furchtbaren Aufstand.
He's making the most dreadful fuss.
彼は本当にひどい騒ぎを起こしている。
Wenn es Ihnen nichts ausmacht, würde ich der jungen Dame gerne einige Fragen stellen.
If you don't mind, I would like to ask the young lady some questions.
もしよろしければ、その若い女性にいくつか質問させていただきたいのですが。
Also, ich werde nicht gehen, falls Sie das glauben.
Well, I'm not leaving, if that's what you think.
まあ、あなたがそう思うなら、私は去りません。
Nun, stört es Sie, wenn Lady Trentham bleibt?
Well, does it bother you if Lady Trentham stays?
さて、トレンサム夫人が留まってもあなたは困りますか？
Warum sollte es?
Why should it?
なぜそうすべきなのでしょうか?
Sir, jemand hat hier unten Schlamm hineingeschleppt.
Sir, someone's traipsed mud in down here.
先生、誰かがここに泥を踏み入れました。
Nicht jetzt, Dexter, bitte.
Not now, Dexter, please.
今はだめだよ、デクスター。
Ich habe verstanden, dass es einige Schwierigkeiten gab
I understood that there was some difficulty
何か困難があったことは理解した
zwischen dem verstorbenen Sir William McCordle und Ihrem Arbeitgeber. between the late Sir William McCordle and your employer.
故ウィリアム・マコードル卿とあなたの雇用主との間の契約です。
Das ist zu vulgär, um es zu glauben.
This is too vulgar to be believed.
これはあまりにも下品なので信じられない。
Das war mir nicht bewusst, Sir. Soweit ich sehen konnte, kamen sie gut miteinander aus.
I wasn't aware of that, sir.
They got on well as far as I could see.
それは知りませんでした、先生。私が見る限り、彼らは仲がよかったです。
Inspektor, hier unten liegt eine kaputte Kaffeetasse.
Inspector, there's a broken coffee cup down here.
警部さん、ここに割れたコーヒーカップがあります。
Dexter, sie haben Leute, die diese Dinge klären. Mach weiter mit deiner Arbeit.
Dexter, they have people to clear these things up. Get on with your own job.
デクスター、彼らにはこれらの問題を解決する人材がいる。自分の仕事を続けなさい。
Von Schwierigkeiten in Sachen Zulagen war Ihnen also nichts bekannt?
So you were not aware of any trouble over the matter of an allowance?
ということは、手当の件でトラブルがあったとは知らなかったのですか？
Ich möchte hinzufügen, dass dieser Zuschuss durch den Tod von Sir William nun gesichert ist.
An allowance, I might add, that
Sir William's death has now made secure.
ウィリアム卿の死によって、このことは確実になったと付け加えておきたい。
Was wäre das für eine Zulage, Sir?
What sort of an allowance would that be, sir?
それはどのような手当でしょうか？
Ah, da bist du ja.
Ah, there you are.
ああ、そこにいたんだ。
Hast du genug Licht?
Have you got enough light?
十分な光はありますか？
Schwarz auf Schwarz? Wir wollen nicht, dass Sie auch noch erblinden.
Black on black? We don't want you going blind on top of everything else.
黒の上に黒？他のすべてに加えて、あなたが失明してしまうのは望ましくありません。
Sie müssen erledigt werden, Mr. Jennings,
They've got to be done,
Mr. Jennings,
やらなきゃいけないんだよ、ジェニングスさん
aber das externe Personal braucht sie für die Beerdigung. but the outside staff need them for the funeral.
しかし、葬儀のために外部のスタッフがそれらを必要としています。
Es tut mir leid, dass Ihnen die Sache mit Elsie so viel Arbeit eingebracht hat.
I'm sorry that this business with Elsie has landed you with so much work.
エルシーとの件で、あなたにたくさんの仕事がかかってしまって残念です。
Das kommt davon, wenn man so zuverlässig ist.
That's what comes of being so reliable.
それはとても信頼できるからこそ生まれるのです。
- Kümmere dich nicht um mich. - Hmm.
- Never mind me.
- Hmm.
- 気にしないで。 - うーん。
Mr. Jennings, haben Sie... haben Sie noch einmal mit der Polizei gesprochen?
Mr. Jennings, have you... have you spoken to the police again?
ジェニングスさん、あなたは…また警察と話しましたか？
Noch nicht, nein.
Not yet, no.
まだ、いいえ。
Ich nehme an, sie müssen ihre Fragen stellen, oder nicht?
I suppose they have to ask their questions, don't they have to?
彼らは質問をしなくてはならないと思いますが、そうではありませんか？
Nun ja.
Well, yes.
そうですね。
Werden sie mit uns allen sprechen?
Will they be talking to all of us?
彼らは私たち全員と話をするのでしょうか?
Das sollte ich nicht glauben, nein.
I shouldn't think so, no.
そうは思わないほうがいいですね。
- Nun, ich überlasse es Ihnen. - Mr. Jennings ...
- Well, I'll leave you to it, then.
- Mr. Jennings...
- では、あなたにお任せします。 - ジェニングスさん...
Wissen Sie ... Sie wissen, dass ich alles sagen würde, was Sie von mir wollen.
You know... You know
I'd say anything you want me to.
ほら...君が望むことなら何でも言うって分かってるでしょ。
- Was? - Irgendetwas.
- What?
- Anything at all.
- 何ですか？ - 何でもいいです。
Es ist mir egal, was ich ihnen erzähle, solange es Ihnen hilft. Das wissen Sie doch, oder?
I don't care what I tell them, if it'll help you. You know that, don't you?
あなたにとって役に立つなら、私が何を話しても構いません。それは分かっていますよね？
Sie müssen nur fragen.
You've only to ask.
ただ尋ねるだけです。
Also, lassen Sie mich, äh... lassen Sie mich Ihnen eine Tasse Tee einschenken, ja?
So, let me, uh... let me pour you a cup of tea, eh?
それで、えーと...お茶を一杯お注ぎしましょうか？
Ja, danke. Könnten Sie die Milch anschließend hineingeben?
Yes, thank you. Would you mind putting the milk in afterwards?
はい、ありがとうございます。後でミルクを入れていただいてもよろしいでしょうか？
Natürlich. Natürlich. Ich weiß nicht, was über mich gekommen ist.
Of course. Of course.
Don't know what came over me.
もちろん。もちろん。何が起こったのか分からない。
Normalerweise gebe ich die Milch danach hinein, aber bei dieser Gelegenheit …
I usually put the milk in after, but on that occasion...
いつもは後からミルクを入れるのですが、その時は…
- Sir? - Nicht jetzt, danke.
- Sir?
- Not now, thank you.
- 先生？ - 今は結構です、結構です。
Es tut mir so leid.
So sorry.
本当にごめんなさい。
Frau Inspektor Thompson bevorzugt die Milch zuerst,
Mrs. Inspector Thompson prefers the milk in first,
トンプソン警部夫人はミルクを先に飲むのが好きです。
also gewöhne ich mich daran, es ihr einzuschenken. so I get used to pouring it for her.
だから私は彼女に注ぐことに慣れています。
Ich weiß nicht warum. Irgendein Unsinn über Bakterien. Du weißt ja, wie Frauen sind ...
I don't know why. Some nonsense about bacteria. You know what women are like...
理由は分かりません。細菌に関するナンセンスです。女性がどんなものかはご存知ですよね...
Tja, wie Ehefrauen nun einmal sind.
Well, what wives are like.
まあ、妻というのはそういうものですね。
Nein, sie ist eine komische alte … Süße?
No, she's a funny old...
Sugar?
いいえ、彼女は面白いおじいさんです...シュガー？
Nein danke.
No, thank you.
いいえ、結構です。
Sie werden ihr ein gutes Zeugnis ausstellen,
They'll give her a good reference,
彼らは彼女に良い推薦状をくれるだろう、
sonst müssten sie erklären, warum sie ihr ein schlechtes geben. otherwise they'd have to explain why they're giving her a bad one.
そうでなければ、なぜ彼女に悪い評価を与えているのか説明しなければならないだろう。
- Herr Parks ... - Robert.
- Mr. Parks...
- Robert.
- パークスさん... - ロバート。
Dann Robert.
Robert, then.
じゃあロバート。
Es ist nur... letzte Nacht, als du gesagt hast, du würdest mich überraschen,
It's just... last night when you said you'd surprise me,
ただ…昨夜あなたが私を驚かせると言っていたのに、
du hast es nicht so gemeint, oder? you didn't mean anything by it, did you?
何も意図してなかったですよね？
Warum? Magst du keine Überraschungen?
Why? Don't you like surprises?
なぜですか？サプライズは好きではないのですか？
Nun ... Oh, Mr. Stockbridge.
Now...
Oh, Mr. Stockbridge.
さて...ああ、ストックブリッジさん。
Ich nehme an, Sie alle sind sich inzwischen bewusst,
By now, I assume you are all aware
皆さんはもうご存知だと思いますが
dass, äh, Mr. Denton uns einen Streich gespielt hat that, uh, Mr. Denton has been playing a trick on us
デントン氏は私たちを騙していた
indem er sich als Kammerdiener ausgibt. by posing as a valet.
係員を装って。
Da Sir William von dem Plan wusste,
Since Sir William was aware of the plan,
ウィリアム卿はその計画を知っていたので、
es steht mir oder irgendjemand anderem nicht zu, es zu kritisieren. it is not for me or anyone else to criticize it.
それを批判するのは私や他の誰かの仕事ではありません。
Für diesen Abend müssen wir jedoch einige Anpassungen vornehmen.
However, it does leave us with some adjustments to make for this evening.
しかし、今晩に向けていくつか調整が必要な点が残っています。
Arthur, Sie übernehmen das Ankleiden, Herr Weissman.
Arthur, you will take over dressing Mr. Weissman.
アーサー、ワイスマン氏の着替えを引き継いでください。
Damit bleiben wir mit dem Problem von Herrn Novello zurück,
That leaves us with the problem of Mr. Novello,
それで、ノヴェロ氏の問題は残る。
und ich möchte Sie wirklich nicht fragen, Mr. Probert. and I really don't want to ask you,
Mr. Probert.
プロバートさん、私はあなたに本当に聞きたくないんです。
Es macht mir nichts aus, Mr. Jennings.
I don't mind, Mr. Jennings.
構いませんよ、ジェニングスさん。
Oh nein. Du hast genug um die Ohren.
Oh, no.
You've got enough on your plate.
ああ、いや。もう十分やることあるでしょう。
Ich mache es ihm, wenn du willst.
I'll do him, if you like.
よろしければ、私がやりますよ。
Das ist sehr großzügig von Ihnen, Mr. Stockbridge.
That's very generous of you,
Mr. Stockbridge.
それはとても寛大なことですね、ストックブリッジさん。
Ich nehme an, ich könnte es natürlich immer selbst tun.
I suppose I could always do it myself, of course.
もちろん、自分でやることもできると思います。
Nein, nein, das macht nichts. Es ist nur für ein oder zwei Nächte.
No, no, it's no trouble.
It's only for a night or two.
いえいえ、問題ありません。1、2晩だけです。
Gut. Großartig. Dann wäre das geklärt.
Good. Splendid.
That's settled, then.
よかった。素晴らしい。それで決まりだ。
Und ich denke, wir können Mr. Denton das Anziehen selbst überlassen. Ha-ha!
And I think we can leave Mr. Denton to dress himself. Ha-ha!
デントン氏に自分で服を着てもらうこともできると思います。ハハハ！
„Der Tod dieses Bastards hat mir vielleicht den Arsch gerettet.“
"The bastard's death may have saved my bacon."
「あの野郎の死が私を救ったかもしれない。」
- Was hat er Ihrer Meinung nach damit gemeint? - Ist das nicht offensichtlich?
- What do you think he meant by that?
- Isn't it obvious?
- 彼は何を意味していたと思いますか？ - それは明らかではないですか？
Ist es das?
Is it?
そうですか？
Nun, vielleicht meinte er die Investition, die Sir William vereinbart hatte
Well, perhaps he meant the investment that Sir William had agreed
まあ、おそらく彼はウィリアム卿が同意した投資のことを言っていたのだろう
müsste wohl jetzt bezahlt werden... Sir! would probably have to be paid now... Sir!
おそらく今すぐに支払わなければならないでしょう...先生！
Was ist mit dem Flachschuss, der ihn an dem Morgen, als sie draußen waren, fast getötet hätte?
What about that low shot that nearly killed him that morning they were out?
彼らが外出していたあの朝、彼を危うく死に至らしめた低い弾丸はどうなったのですか?
- Sir. - Was ist es?
- Sir.
- What is it?
- 先生。 - 何ですか？
Wir haben diese Dinger noch nicht auf Fingerabdrücke abgestaubt.
We haven't dusted those things for fingerprints yet.
まだ指紋を取るためにそれらのほこりを払っていません。
Gut.
Good.
良い。
Glauben Sie, dass dieser Schuss Sir William galt?
Do you think that shot might have been intended for Sir William?
そのショットはウィリアム卿に向けたものだったと思いますか?
- Na ja, es hätte ihm fast ein Ohr abgerissen. - Hmm.
- Well, it nearly took his ear off.
- Hmm.
- まあ、彼の耳はほぼ取れてしまいました。 - うーん。
Vielen Dank, Mr. Barnes, Sie waren äußerst hilfreich.
Well, thank you, Mr. Barnes, you've been most helpful.
そうですね、バーンズさん、本当に助かりました。
Vielleicht wären Sie so freundlich, Commander Meredith zu bitten, sich uns jetzt anzuschließen.
Perhaps you'd be good enough to ask
Commander Meredith to join us just now.
おそらく、メレディス司令官に今すぐに加わるようお願いしていただけると幸いです。
Sie werden ihm doch nicht sagen, was ich gesagt habe, oder, Inspektor Thomas?
Y-y-you won't tell him what I said, will you, Inspector Thomas?
えっと…私が言ったことは彼に言わないでしょうね、トーマス警部？
Thompson. Hier ist Inspektor Thom...
Thompson.
It's Inspector Thom...
トンプソン。トム警部だ…
Macht nichts. Geh einfach und hol ihn ab, bitte.
Never mind.
Just go and fetch him up, please.
気にしないでください。ただ彼を迎えに来てください。
Herr...
Sir...
お客様...
- Wir haben nur das. - Ich glaube nicht, dass es meinen stört.
- We've only got this.
- I don't think mine's bothered.
- 私たちにはこれしかありません。 - 私のは気にしていないと思います。
Sie hat hier kein Schwarz.
She hasn't got any black here.
彼女はここに黒いものを持っていません。
- Du bist ein Lustmolch. - George?
- You're a lech.
- George?
- 君は淫乱だね。 - ジョージ？
Sie kommen gleich. Die Ankleideglocke ist gerade geläutet.
They're coming in a minute.
The dressing bell's just gone.
すぐに来ます。着替えのベルが鳴りました。
Ich werde da oben verrückt. Ich habe alle meine Zeitschriften zweimal gelesen.
I'm going out of my mind up there.
I've read all my magazines twice.
私は気が狂いそうだ。雑誌を全部2回読んだ。
Konntest du mir nichts aus der Bibliothek klauen?
You couldn't pinch something out of the library for me?
図書館から何かを借りてきませんか？
Es ist mir egal, ob es „Horse and Hound“ ist, solange ich es nicht gelesen habe.
I don't care if it's "Horse and Hound", as long as I haven't read it.
読んでいなければ、「Horse and Hound」でも構いません。
Nun, wir fühlen uns geehrt.
Well, we are honored.
そうですね、光栄です。
Falls Sie es vergessen haben, dies ist der Dienstbotenbereich, Sir.
In case you've forgotten, this is the servants area, sir.
忘れていらっしゃるかもしれませんが、ここは使用人エリアです、旦那様。
Ihr Exemplar befindet sich oben auf der Treppe hinter der Tür dort, Sir.
Yours is at the top of the stairs behind that door there, sir.
あなたのものは、あそこのドアの後ろの階段の一番上にあります、旦那様。
Barnes, es war nur ein ...
Barnes, it was just a...
バーンズ、それはただの...
- Ich wollte erklären … - Keine Erklärung nötig, Mr. Denton.
- I wanted to explain...
- No explanation necessary, Mr. Denton.
- 説明したいと思ったのですが... - 説明は必要ありません、デントンさん。
Wenn Sie uns entschuldigen würden, einige von uns haben echte Arbeit zu erledigen. Komm schon, Arthur.
If you'll excuse us, some of us have got real work to do. Come on, Arthur.
失礼ですが、私たちの中にはやるべき仕事がある人もいます。さあ、アーサー。
Der Akzent war ein todsicherer Hinweis, wissen Sie. Wir alle wussten es.
The accent was a dead giveaway, you know. We all knew.
アクセントを見れば一目瞭然だった。みんな知ってたよ。
Robert, ich hatte nur Spaß.
Robert, I was just having fun.
ロバート、私はただ楽しんでいただけだよ。
Vielleicht sollten Sie Ihren Spaß lieber im Salon genießen, Sir.
Perhaps you'd better enjoy your fun in the drawing room, sir.
応接室で楽しい時間を過ごしたほうが良いかもしれませんね。
Sie haben Angst, dass Sie Dinge wiederholen oder indiskret sind.
They're afraid you'll repeat things, be indiscreet.
彼らはあなたが同じことを繰り返したり、無分別なことをしたりするのではないかと恐れているのです。
Aber ich bin sehr diskret.
But I'm very discreet.
しかし、私は非常に慎重です。
In Hollywood bin ich für meine Diskretion bekannt.
In Hollywood, that's what
I'm known for... my discretion.
ハリウッドでは、私は慎重な性格で知られています。
Sag es Rupert, wenn du möchtest. Er wird dir kein Geld geben.
Tell Rupert if you like.
He won't give you any money.
よろしかったらルパートに伝えてください。彼はあなたにお金は渡さないでしょう。
Nein, Sie verstehen mich völlig falsch.
No, you're completely misunderstanding me.
いいえ、あなたは私のことを完全に誤解しています。
Und Mama würde keine fünf Pfund zahlen, um mich zu retten …
And Mummy wouldn't pay five pounds to save me...
そしてママは私を救うために5ポンドも払ってくれなかった...
Oh, mein armer Liebling. Komm her. Komm schon.
Oh, my poor darling.
Come here. Come on.
ああ、かわいそうなあなた。こっちへ来なさい。さあ。
Denken Sie bitte nicht, dass mir das Spaß macht. Ich wollte nur einen Job.
Look, please don't think that
I'm enjoying this. All I wanted was a job.
いいですか、私がこれを楽しんでいるとは思わないでください。私が望んでいたのはただ仕事だったんです。
Mein Scheckbuch ist unten. Ich gebe Ihnen nach dem Abendessen einen Scheck.
My checkbook's downstairs.
I'll give you a check after dinner.
小切手帳は階下にあります。夕食後に小切手をお渡しします。
Ich versuche, meinen Mann Parks zu finden. Hast du ihn gesehen?
I'm trying to find my man Parks.
Have you seen him?
私は仲間のパークスを探しているんだ。彼を見たかい？
Äh, nein. Ich war bei der Polizei.
Uh, no.
I've been with the police.
うーん、いいえ。私は警察にいました。
Sie sehen aus, als hätten Sie eine ziemliche Tracht Prügel bekommen.
You look as if you've had rather a pasting.
かなりひどい叩き方をしたように見えますね。
Sie redeten immer wieder von dem Flachschuss gestern und ließen nicht locker.
They kept on and on about that low shot yesterday, and they wouldn't let it go.
彼らは昨日の低いショットについて何度も繰り返して、それを放っておこうとしなかった。
- Ich habe ihnen gesagt, dass es nichts mit mir zu tun hat. - Das habe ich bestimmt gesagt.
- I told them it was nothing to do with me.
- I'm sure you did.
- 私は彼らにそれは私とは何の関係もないと言いました。 - あなたはそうだったと思います。
Aber ein anderes Mal, Anthony, versuche, weniger gierig zu sein. Parks!
But another time, Anthony, try to be less greedy. Parks!
でも、アンソニー、今度は欲張らないようにしてね。パークス！
Was?
What?
何？
Kümmern Sie sich zuerst um Mr. Novello. Ich möchte mit Ihrer Ladyschaft sprechen.
Attend to Mr. Novello first.
I want a word with Her Ladyship.
まずノヴェロ氏に連絡してください。女王陛下とお話したいことがあります。
Sehr gut, Mylord.
Very well, milord.
結構です、殿下。
- Was? - Ich habe dich gesehen.
- What?
- I saw you.
- 何だって？ - 君を見たよ。
Natürlich war es ein Unfall. Wenn ein Mann so klein ist wie du,
Of course it was an accident.
When a man's as short as you,
もちろんそれは事故だった。君ほど背が低い男は
es muss sehr schwierig sein, die Größe der Vögel abzuschätzen. it must be very difficult to gauge the height of the birds.
鳥の高さを測るのは非常に難しいに違いありません。
- Herr Meredith. - Hmm?
- Mr. Meredith.
- Hmm?
- メレディスさん。 - ん？
Sie haben Commander Meredith nirgendwo gesehen, oder?
You haven't seen Commander Meredith anywhere, have you?
メレディス司令官をどこかで見かけませんでしたか?
NEIN.
No.
いいえ。
Er ist nie die Treppe heruntergekommen und ist nicht in seinem Zimmer.
He never came down stairs and he's not in his room.
彼は一度も階段を降りてこなかったし、自分の部屋にもいません。
Mr. Jennings, ich habe ihn gewaschen und angezogen.
Mr. Jennings,
I've washed him and dressed him.
ジェニングスさん、私は彼を洗って服を着せておきました。
Wenn er den Weg zum Salon nicht findet, ist das nicht meine Schuld.
If he can't find his way to the drawing room, it isn't my fault.
もし彼が応接室への道を見つけられなかったとしても、それは私のせいではありません。
Oh, das tut mir wirklich leid, Sir. Ich wollte Sie nicht stören.
Oh, I'm so sorry, sir.
I didn't mean to disturb you.
ああ、申し訳ありません。邪魔するつもりはなかったんです。
Nein, nein, nein, bitte. Ich probiere nur etwas von Ihrer Marmelade.
No, no, no, Please.
I'm just trying some of your jam.
いや、いや、いや、お願い。ただあなたのジャムを試しているだけなんです。
Ich muss dir im Weg sein.
I must be in your way.
邪魔をしているようです。
Nein, nein. Nein, nein. Kein Problem.
No, no. No, no. No bother.
いや、いや。いや、いや。気にしないで。
Welcher ist das, Sir?
What one is that, sir?
それは何ですか？
Ähm, es ist Himbeere. Oktober ’31.
Um, it's raspberry.
October '31.
えっと、ラズベリーです。10月31日。
Vielleicht möchten Sie die, ähm … Erdbeersorte probieren.
You might like to try the, um... strawberry one.
えーっと…イチゴ味を試してみるといいかもしれません。
Oh, gibt es Erdbeere?
Oh, is there strawberry?
ああ、イチゴはありますか？
Mal sehen. Ah, ja.
Let's see. Ah, yes.
そうだね。ああ、そうだね。
Alles in Ordnung, Sir?
You alright, sir?
大丈夫ですか？
War gerade beim Inspektor und ... ich fühle mich ein wenig verletzt.
Just been with the inspector and...
I feel a little bruised.
検査官と一緒にいたばかりで...少し傷ついた気がします。
Mmm.
うーん。
Warum ist es Ihrer Meinung nach so,
Why is it, would you say,
それはなぜだと思いますか？
dass manche Menschen im Leben scheinbar alles bekommen, was sie wollen? that some people seem to get whatever they want in life?
人生において、望むものは何でも手に入る人がいるということでしょうか?
Alles, was sie berühren, wird zu Gold.
Everything they touch turns to gold.
彼らが触れるものはすべて金に変わります。
Während andere sich immer weiter anstrengen und nichts erreichen.
Whereas others can strive and strive and have nothing.
一方、他の人は努力しても何も得られない。
Ich frage mich, glauben Sie an Glück?
I wonder, do you believe in luck?
あなたは運を信じますか？
Glauben Sie, dass manche Männer Glück haben und ...
Do you think some men are lucky and...
男性の中には幸運な人もいると思いますか...
manche Männer sind es einfach nicht und ... sie können nichts dagegen tun? some men just aren't and... nothing they can do about it?
男性の中にはそうではない人もいますが...それについては何もできないのでしょうか?
Ich glaube an die Liebe. Nicht nur daran, sie zu bekommen. Sie zu geben.
I believe in love.
Not just getting it. Giving it.
私は愛を信じています。ただ受け取るのではなく、与えることです。
Ich denke, solange man jemanden lieben kann, ob er einen nun liebt oder nicht,
I think as long as you can love somebody, whether or not they love you,
誰かを愛することができる限り、相手があなたを愛しているかどうかは関係なく、
dann lohnt es sich und... then it's worth it and...
そうすれば価値はあるし...
Das ist eine gute Antwort.
That's a good answer.
それは良い答えです。
Äh, ich glaube, ich muss los. Ich muss jetzt mit dem Abendessen fertig sein.
Uh, I think I've got to go.
Must have finished dinner by now.
えーと、もう行かなきゃ。もう夕食は終わってるはず。
Danke schön.
Thank you.
ありがとう。
Ich fand den Wein heute Abend furchtbar. Widerlich.
I thought the wine was frightful tonight. Vile.
今夜のワインはひどいと思った。ひどい。
Jennings, alter Junge, ich nehme einen Bourbon.
Jennings, old boy,
I'll have a bourbon.
ジェニングス、おじさん、バーボンを一杯頂戴。
Wir haben keinen Bourbon. Wir haben normalen Scotch oder Single Malt.
We don't have bourbon.
We have ordinary Scotch or single malt.
バーボンはございません。普通のスコッチかシングルモルトです。
Für mich ganz normal. Ich bin einfach Amerikaner.
Ordinary for me.
I'm just an American.
私にとっては普通です。私はただのアメリカ人です。
Wen interessiert das? Wir wissen es ...
Who cares? We know...
誰が気にする？私たちは知っている...
Ich verstehe, dass dies nicht der ideale Zeitpunkt ist, aber ich würde Sie gern wiedersehen.
I understand this is not an ideal time, but I would like to see you again.
今は理想的なタイミングではないことは承知していますが、もう一度お会いしたいと思っています。
Mabel ist so clever, mit leichtem Gepäck zu reisen.
Mabel is so clever to travel light.
メイベルは荷物を軽くして旅行するなんてとても賢いですね。
Warum sollte man jeden Abend ein anderes Kleid tragen?
Why should one wear a different frock every evening?
なぜ毎晩違うドレスを着なければならないのでしょうか?
Wir sind nicht bei einer Modenschau.
We're not in a fashion parade.
私たちはファッションパレードに参加しているわけではありません。
Nein, und das möchte ich auch nicht. Entschuldigen Sie.
No, and I wouldn't want to be.
Excuse me.
いいえ、そうなりたくありません。失礼。
Schwierige Farbe, Grün.
Difficult color, green.
難しい色、緑。
- Was hat sie gesagt? - Mmm. Sehr knifflig.
- What did she say?
- Mmm. Very tricky.
- 彼女は何て言ったの？ - うーん。とても難しい。
- Isobel ... - Entschuldigen Sie.
- Isobel...
- Excuse me.
- イザベル... - すみません。
Es zieht einen irgendwie an...
It sort of draws you...
ちょっと惹かれますね...
Oh, wie diese Melodie mich immer zum Weinen gebracht hat.
Oh, how this tune used to make me cry.
ああ、この曲を聴くといつも泣いてしまうもの。
- Ich verspreche, ich werde jeden Cent zurückzahlen ... - Nimm es einfach.
- I promise, I'll pay back every penny...
- Just take it.
- 約束するよ、全額返すから... - 受け取って。
Ich muss sagen, Ihre Gäste schlafen in viel bequemeren Betten als Ihre Bediensteten.
I must say, your guests sleep in much more comfortable beds than your servants.
言わざるを得ませんが、あなたのお客様は召使いよりもずっと快適なベッドで眠っています。
Verzeihung.
Excuse me.
すみません。
Was hat Isobel dir gegeben?
What did Isobel give to you?
イザベルはあなたに何をあげましたか？
- Mach hier keine Szene. - Erzähl es mir!
- Don't make a scene here.
- Tell me!
- ここで大騒ぎしないで。 - 教えて！
Ivor, Liebling, wäre es möglich, etwas Fröhlicheres zu spielen?
Ivor, dear... would it be possible to play something a little more cheerful?
アイヴァー、もう少し明るい曲を演奏してもらえませんか？
Wir sind alle schon emotional genug.
We're all quite emotional enough, as it is.
私たちは皆、すでに十分に感情的になっています。
Verzeihung.
Excuse me.
すみません。
Freddie, hör auf mit deinen Lügen.
Freddie, stop all your lies.
フレディ、嘘はやめなさい。
Wenn Sie es mir nicht geben, werde ich dieses Haus niederschreien.
If you don't give it to me,
I will scream this house down.
それを私に渡さないなら、私はこの家中を大声で叫びます。
Wenn Sie mir nicht glauben, versuchen Sie es mit mir.
If you don't believe me, try me.
信じられないなら、試してみて下さい。
Wo warst du?
Where've you been?
どこに行ってたの？
Sie haben das Abendessen verpasst. Wir können ein Tablett für Sie organisieren.
You know, you've missed dinner.
We can organize a tray for you.
夕食を食べ損ねたようですね。トレイを用意しておきます。
Versuchen Sie, sich davon ein neues Kleid zu kaufen.
Try buying yourself a new frock with that.
それで新しいドレスを買ってみてください。
- Wir haben aufgegeben, Louisa, Liebes. - Oh, richtig.
- We gave up, Louisa, dear.
- Oh, right.
- 諦めたんだよ、ルイザ。 - ああ、そうだった。
Es tut mir so leid...
I'm so sorry...
ごめんなさい...
Kein Kaffee, George, aber ich nehme ein ... Ah!
No coffee, George, but I'll have a... Ah!
ジョージ、コーヒーはないけど、私は...あ！
Ich entschuldige mich, Sir. Ich kann mir nicht vorstellen, wie das passiert ist.
I do apologize, sir.
Can't imagine how that happened.
申し訳ありません。どうしてそんなことが起きたのか想像もつきません。
Du Hurensohn. Das hast du mit Absicht gemacht!
You son of a bitch.
You did that on purpose!
このクソ野郎。わざとやったんでしょ！
Soll ich Ihnen ein Handtuch holen, Sir?
Shall I fetch you a towel, sir?
タオルを持ってきましょうか？
Oh!
おお！
- Arthur? - Oh je!
- Arthur?
- Oh, dear!
- アーサー？ - ああ、大変！
Mach das sauber, ja?
Clean this up, will you?
これを掃除してもらえますか？
Sie fischten Teile ihres Körpers aus der Themse
They were fishin' parts of her body out the Thames
彼らはテムズ川から彼女の体の一部を釣り上げていた
von Richmond nach Rotherhithe. from Richmond to Rotherhithe.
リッチモンドからロザーハイズまで。
- Noch Tee, Constable? - Das nehme ich gerne. Danke, Bertha.
- More tea, Constable?
- I'll take that. Thank you, Bertha.
- 警官さん、お茶をもう一杯？ - いただきます。ありがとう、バーサ。
Kein Kopf. Keine Hände ...
No head. No hands...
頭も手もない...
Was soll das bringen? Wird das nicht alles rausgeschmissen?
What's the point in that?
Won't it all be chucked out?
それは何の意味があるのですか? 全部捨てられてしまうのではないですか?
Ich weiß, dass ich alles in Ordnung hinterlassen habe.
I'll know I've left everything in good order.
すべてをきちんと整頓しておいたかどうかがわかります。
Das ist alles, was ich jetzt für ihn tun kann.
That's all I can do for him now.
今私が彼のためにできるのはそれだけです。
- Ja, aber ... - Hey, lass ihn in Ruhe.
- Yeah, but...
- Hey, leave him alone.
- ああ、でも... - おい、彼を放っておいてくれ。
George hat sich an Mr. Denton gerächt. Heißer Kaffee auf dem Schoß.
George has had his revenge on Mr. Denton. Hot coffee in the lap.
ジョージはデントン氏に復讐しました。膝の上に熱いコーヒーがあります。
- Oh! - Armer Mr. Denton.
- Oh!
- Poor Mr. Denton.
- ああ！ - かわいそうなデントンさん。
Constable, ich bin froh, dass ich Sie erwischt habe.
Constable, I'm glad I caught you.
警官さん、捕まえられてよかったです。
Ich nehme an, der Inspektor wird nicht alle über morgen hinaus dabehalten,
I assume the inspector won't keep everyone beyond tomorrow,
検査官は明日以降は全員を拘束しないだろうと思うが、
aber ich dachte, ich sollte das besser überprüfen. but I thought I'd better check.
でも確認したほうがいいと思いました。
Wir haben noch nicht mit allen Bediensteten gesprochen, also ...
We haven't spoke to all the servants yet, so...
まだ全ての使用人と話をしていないので...
Da bist du ja, Dexter. Komm, wir gehen nach Hause.
There you are, Dexter.
Come on, we're going home.
そこにいたよ、デクスター。さあ、家に帰ろう。
Ich habe nur gefragt, wie lange unsere Gäste bleiben werden.
I was just asking how long our guests will be staying.
ゲストがどれくらい滞在するのかを尋ねていました。
Mrs. Croft muss Mahlzeiten vorbereiten und ein Hausmädchen möchte unbedingt weg.
Mrs. Croft has meals to arrange and one housemaid is anxious to get away.
クロフト夫人は食事の準備をしなければならず、メイドの一人は早く帰りたがっています。
Darüber besteht kein Grund zur Sorge. Die Bediensteten interessieren mich nicht.
There's no need to worry about that.
I'm not interested in the servants.
心配する必要はありません。私は使用人に興味はありません。
Nur Menschen mit einer echten Verbindung zum Toten.
Only people with a real connection with the dead man.
死んだ男と本当につながりのある人だけ。
Ich verstehe. Danke.
I see. Thank you.
分かりました。ありがとうございます。
- Haben Sie Licht, Inspektor? - Ja.
- Do you have a light, Inspector?
- Yes.
- ライトはお持ちですか、警部？ - はい。
Ehrlich gesagt denke ich, wir können sie alle nach Hause gehen lassen.
I think we can let them all go home, to be honest.
正直に言うと、全員家に帰らせてもいいと思う。
Habe immerhin ihre Adressen.
Got their addresses, after all.
結局、彼らの住所を入手しました。
Constable Dexter wird morgen früh hier sein, um das zu bestätigen.
Constable Dexter will be here tomorrow morning to confirm that.
デクスター巡査が明日の朝、それを確認するためここに来る予定です。
Keine Sorge. Es ist noch nicht vorbei. Oh nein.
Don't you worry.
It doesn't end here. Oh, no.
心配しないでください。ここで終わりではありません。ああ、いや。
Wer auch immer er ist, ich werde ihn finden.
Whoever he is, I'll find him.
彼が誰であろうと、私は彼を見つけるでしょう。
Das tue ich immer.
I always do.
いつもそうしています。
Inspektor, Ihre Streichhölzer.
Inspector... your matches.
検査官…あなたの試合です。
Ja, danke.
Yes. Thank you.
はい。ありがとうございます。
Äh, Sir, ich denke, Sie werden feststellen, dass es so ist.
Uh, sir, I think you'll find it's this way.
ええと、こんな感じだと思います。
Nun ja, das könnten wir gebrauchen.
Well, yes, we could use this one.
そうですね、これは使えますね。
Ich glaube, es gibt dort draußen einen Ausweg, aber ja, wir nehmen Ihren Weg.
There is, I think, a way out that way, but, yeah, we'll take your way.
そういう方法でも抜け道はあると思うけど、そうだね、君のやり方で行くよ。
Oh! Bitte um Verzeihung, Sir.
Oh! Beg your pardon, sir.
ああ！失礼しました。
Ich hole nur Mr. Nesbitts Schuhe ab, Sir.
Just collecting Mr. Nesbitt's shoes, sir.
ネスビット氏の靴を集めているところです、先生。
Ich denke, Sie werden feststellen, dass diese Treppe der einfachste Weg nach oben ist, Sir.
I think you'll find these stairs are the easiest way up, sir.
この階段が一番登りやすい道だとお分かりいただけると思います、先生。
- Danke, äh ... - George, Sir.
- Thank you, uh...
- George, sir.
- ありがとう、えーと... - ジョージです。
Georg.
George.
ジョージ。
Du ungezogenes, ungezogenes Mädchen.
You naughty, naughty girl.
あなたって、悪い子ね。
Armer Kerl... Wir waren neulich im Bügelzimmer,
Poor bloke... We were in the ironing room the other night,
かわいそうに...先日アイロン室にいたんだけど
und eines der Dienstmädchen kam herein. and one of the visiting maids walked in.
すると訪問メイドの一人が入ってきた。
Ich muss denken, ich hätte es mit Absicht gemacht.
Must think I did it on purpose.
わざとやったんだと思うよ。
- Du wirst es nicht sagen, oder? - Ich werde es nicht sagen.
- You won't tell, will you?
- I won't tell.
- 言わないでしょうね？ - 言わないよ。
Aber Sie haben Glück, dass Sie in der Küche sind und nicht unter Mrs. Wilson.
But you're lucky you're in the kitchen and not under Mrs. Wilson.
しかし、あなたがキッチンにいて、ウィルソン夫人の下ではないのは幸運です。
Sie hätte Sie auch ohne meine Hilfe aufgespürt.
She'd have sniffed you out without any help from me.
彼女は私の助けがなくてもあなたを嗅ぎ分けていたでしょう。
Glauben Sie, dass Sir William in Sie verliebt war?
Do you think Sir William was in love with you?
ウィリアム卿はあなたに恋をしていたと思いますか？
Nein. Es war nur ein bisschen lustig, das ist alles.
Nah. I was a bit of fun, that's all.
いや。ちょっと楽しんだだけだよ。
Und du?
And you?
あなたも？
Ich habe ihn nicht geliebt. Er hat mir nichts ausgemacht, aber ...
I didn't love him.
I didn't mind him, but...
私は彼を愛してはいなかった。気にもしていなかったが...
Mir gefiel, wie er redete.
I liked the way he'd talk.
私は彼の話し方が好きでした。
Er redete nur mit mir, weil er sie satt hatte, aber mir gefiel es.
He'd only talk to me because he was sick of her, but I liked it.
彼が私に話しかけたのは、彼女にうんざりしていたからだけだったが、私はそれが気に入っていた。
Er sagte immer zu mir: „Ich könnte alles sein, was ich wollte, solange ich es nur genug wollte.“
He used to say to me, I could be anything
I wanted as long as I wanted it enough.
彼はいつも私にこう言っていました。「私が十分に望めば、何にでもなれるよ。」
Es tut dir also nicht leid? Selbst nach dem, was nun passiert ist?
You're not sorry, then?
Even after the way things have turned out?
では、後悔はしていないのですか？ 物事がこうなってしまった後でも？
Nein, es tut mir nicht leid. Es ist Zeit für eine Veränderung.
Nah, I'm not sorry.
It's time for a change.
いや、申し訳ないと思ってない。変化の時が来たんだ。
Wer weiß? Das könnte mich zu etwas Besonderem machen.
Who knows?
Could be the makin' of me.
誰にも分からないよ。それが私のせいかもしれない。
Wie sagte er immer? Carpe diem. Nutze den Tag.
What did he used to say?
Carpe diem. Seize the day.
彼は何と言っていたっけ？Carpe diem（今を生きろ）。一日を大事にしろ。
Was ist los?
What's up?
どうしたの？
Was habe ich gesagt? Wohin gehst du?
What did I say?
Where are you going?
何を言った？どこへ行くの？
Wer ist es?
Who is it?
誰だ？
Was machst du?
What are you doing?
何してるの？
Geh lieber zurück in dein Zimmer. Du willst hier nicht erwischt werden.
You'd better go back to your room.
You don't want to get caught in here.
部屋に戻った方がいいよ。ここに閉じ込められたくないだろうから。
Sie mochten ihn doch nicht wirklich, oder?
You didn't really dislike him, did you?
本当に嫌いだったわけじゃないよね？
Nicht wirklich.
Not really.
あまり。
Zumindest nicht genug, um ihn zu töten.
At least not enough to kill him.
少なくとも彼を殺すには十分ではない。
Das kannst du nicht haben.
You can't have.
それはあり得ません。
Du kanntest ihn nicht.
You didn't know him.
あなたは彼を知らなかった。
Sie müssten ihn hassen. Und warum sollten Sie?
You'd have to hate him.
And why would you?
あなたは彼を憎むでしょう。なぜ憎むのですか?
Kann ein Mann seinen eigenen Vater nicht hassen?
Can't a man hate his own father?
男は自分の父親を憎むことはできないのか？
Sir William McCordle ... war mein Vater.
Sir William McCordle... was my father.
ウィリアム・マコードル卿は私の父でした。
Er wusste es nicht, aber er war es.
He didn't know it, but he was.
彼は知らなかったが、そうだったのだ。
Sie sagten, Sie seien eine Waise.
You said you were an orphan.
あなたは孤児だと言った。
Nein, habe ich nicht. Ich sagte, ich bin in einem Waisenhaus aufgewachsen.
No, I didn't. I said I grew up in an orphanage.
いいえ、そうではありません。私は孤児院で育ったと言いました。
Kurz bevor ich ging, brachen wir in das Büro des Direktors ein und holten unsere Akten heraus.
Not long before I left, we broke into the warden's office and took out our files.
私が出発する少し前に、私たちは所長室に侵入し、ファイルを盗み出しました。
Ich habe meine Geburtsurkunde gefunden.
I found my birth certificate.
出生証明書を見つけました。
Name der Mutter, Vater unbekannt.
Mother's name, father unknown.
母親の名前、父親の名前は不明。
Habe dieses Foto gefunden. Und sie hatten mein Aufnahmeformular.
Found this photograph.
And they had my admission form.
この写真を見つけました。そして彼らは私の入学申込書を持っていました。
Ich war zwei Tage alt. Ratet mal, wer mich zur Tür gebracht hat.
I was two days old.
Guess who brought me to the door.
私は生後2日目でした。誰が私を玄関まで連れて来たと思いますか。
- Robert, das heißt nicht, dass er... - Doch, das tut es.
- Robert, that doesn't mean that he...
- Yes, it does.
- ロバート、それは彼が...という意味ではありません。 - そうです。
Danach fand ich heraus, dass sie in einer seiner Fabriken arbeitete.
After that, I found out she worked in one of his factories.
その後、彼女が彼の工場の一つで働いていたことが分かりました。
Sie war offenbar nicht die Einzige.
She wasn't the only one, apparently.
どうやら彼女だけではなかったようだ。
Entweder wussten die Behörden nichts davon, oder sie wollten es nicht wissen.
Either the authorities didn't know, or they didn't want to know.
当局は知らなかったか、知りたくなかったかのどちらかだ。
Sie nahmen ihm seine Babys ... und sie nahmen ihm sein Geld.
They took his babies... and they took his money.
彼らは彼の赤ちゃんを奪い、そして彼のお金も奪ったのです。
Was ist mit deiner Mutter passiert?
What happened to your mother?
あなたのお母さんに何が起こったのですか？
Sie ist gestorben.
She died.
彼女は死んだ。
Haben Sie deshalb den Job bei Lord Stockbridge angenommen?
Is that why you took the job with Lord Stockbridge?
それがストックブリッジ卿の仕事を引き受けた理由ですか?
Um zu Sir William zu gelangen?
To get to Sir William?
ウィリアム卿に会うために？
Um ihn zu vergiften?
To poison him?
毒を盛るため？
Ich habe ihn nicht vergiftet.
I didn't poison him.
私は彼に毒を盛っていません。
Was?
What?
何？
Ich habe ihn nicht vergiftet.
I didn't poison him.
私は彼に毒を盛っていません。
Aber Sie haben ihn nicht getötet.
But then you didn't kill him.
しかし、あなたは彼を殺さなかった。
Hast du ihn erstochen?
Did you stab him?
彼を刺したの？
Selbst wenn Sie es getan hätten, wäre er bereits tot gewesen.
Even if you did, he was already dead.
たとえそうだったとしても、彼はすでに死んでいた。
Und wer auch immer es getan hat, muss das gewusst haben.
And whoever did it must've known that.
そして、それをやった人は誰であれ、それを知っていたに違いありません。
Niemand könnte eine Leiche erstechen, ohne es zu merken.
No one could stab a corpse and not know it.
死体を刺してそれに気づかない人はいないだろう。
Wirklich? Wann hast du das letzte Mal eine Leiche erstochen?
Really? When was the last time you stabbed a corpse?
本当ですか？最後に死体を刺したのはいつですか？
Dann haben Sie ihn wirklich ermordet.
You really murdered him, then.
じゃあ本当に彼を殺したんですね。
Ich weiß nicht.
I don't know.
わからない。
Es ist mir egal.
I don't care.
私は気にしない。
Oh.
Ooh.
ああ。
Das wollte ich schon immer tun, seit ich dich zum ersten Mal gesehen habe.
I've been wanting to do that ever since I first set eyes on you.
初めて君を見た時からずっとそうしたいと思っていたんだ。
Oh!
おお！
- Herr Jennings? - Wilson! Frau Wilson. Frau ...
- Mr. Jennings?
- Wilson! Mrs. Wilson. Mrs...
- ジェニングスさん？ - ウィルソン！ウィルソン夫人。ウィルソン夫人...
Dorothy, ich brauche deine Hilfe.
Dorothy. I need your help.
ドロシー。あなたの助けが必要です。
Natürlich, Mrs. Wilson. Geht es Ihnen gut?
Of course, Mrs. Wilson.
Are you alright?
もちろんです、ウィルソンさん。大丈夫ですか？
- Niemand darf ihn so sehen. - Oh!
- No one must see him like this.
- Oh!
- 誰も彼をこんな風に見てはいけません。 - ああ！
Hilf mir.
Help me.
助けて。
- Mr. Jennings? - Kommen Sie, Mr. Jennings.
- Mr. Jennings?
- Come on, Mr. Jennings.
- ジェニングスさん？ - さあ、ジェニングスさん。
Komm schon. Schlafenszeit.
Come on. Bedtime.
さあ、寝る時間です。
- Okay, Schlafenszeit. - Nein, hier entlang. Kommen Sie, Mr. Jennings.
- Alright, bedtime.
- No, this way. Come on, Mr. Jennings.
- よし、寝る時間だ。 - いや、こっちだ。さあ、ジェニングスさん。
Schlafenszeit, Mr. Jennings. Jetzt ist es Schlafenszeit. Kommen Sie.
Bedtime, Mr. Jennings.
Bedtime now. Come on.
寝る時間ですよ、ジェニングスさん。もう寝る時間ですよ。さあ。
Wo ist...?
Where is...?
...はどこですか？
Wo ist meine Referenz?
Where is my reference?
私の参照先はどこですか?
Du bekommst dein Zeugnis. Jetzt ab ins Bett.
You'll get your reference. Into bed now.
紹介状が届きます。今すぐベッドに入りましょう。
- Ins Bett. - Aah!
- Into bed.
- Aah!
- ベッドへ。 - ああ！
Beobachten Sie ihn. Beobachten Sie ihn.
Watch him. Watch him.
彼を見てください。彼を見てください。
Zieh ihm bitte die Hose aus, Dorothy?
Take his trousers off him, would you, Dorothy?
ドロシー、彼のズボンを脱がせてくれませんか？
Das könnte ich nicht tun, Mrs. Wilson. Das könnte ich nicht tun.
I couldn't do that, Mrs. Wilson.
I couldn't do that.
それはできませんでした、ウィルソンさん。それはできませんでした。
Zieh ihm die Hose aus. Komm schon!
Take his trousers off. Come on!
ズボンを脱がせ。さあ！
- Komm schon. - Dorothy!
- Come on.
- Dorothy!
- さあ。 - ドロシー！
Wer ist es?
Who is it?
誰だ？
- Oh, das tut mir wirklich leid, Sir. - Wofür entschuldigen?
- Oh, I'm ever so sorry, sir.
- Sorry for what?
- ああ、本当に申し訳ございません。 - 何に対して申し訳ございませんですか?
Ich soll das Feuer anzünden, ohne Sie zu wecken.
I'm supposed to get the fire lit without waking you.
あなたを起こさずに火を灯さなければなりません。
Warum behandeln mich alle, als wäre ich einer dieser dummen Snobs?
Why does everyone treat me as if I were one of these stupid snobs?
なぜみんなは私をバカなスノッブの一人のように扱うのでしょうか?
Ich habe die halbe Woche unten mit euch allen verbracht.
I spent half the week downstairs with all of you.
私は一週間の半分を皆さんと一緒に階下で過ごしました。
Sie können nicht gleichzeitig in beiden Teams sein, Sir.
You can't be on both teams at once, sir.
同時に両方のチームに所属することはできません。
Es ist offiziell. Nach dem Frühstück geht es los.
It's official.
They're off after breakfast.
正式に決定です。朝食後出発です。
Gott sei Dank dafür. Was ist mit ihm?
Thank God for that. What about him?
それは神に感謝します。彼はどうですか?
Er wird auch gehen, sobald er Mr. Jennings gesehen hat.
He's going too, as soon as he's seen Mr. Jennings.
彼もジェニングス氏に会ったらすぐに出かけます。
Alles in Ordnung, Mrs. Croft? Sie klingen ein bisschen komisch.
Are you alright, Mrs. Croft? you sound a bit funny.
大丈夫ですか、クロフトさん？ちょっと変な声ですね。
Oh, einfach zu viele Zigaretten, das ist alles.
Oh, just too many fags, that's all.
ああ、ただホモが多すぎるだけだよ。
Sie werden mein Todesurteil sein. Hier, mach du es fertig.
They'll be the death of me.
Here, you finish it.
奴らは私を死なせてしまうだろう。さあ、お前がそれを終わらせろ。
- Haben Sie der Polizei irgendetwas davon erzählt? - Nein.
- Did you tell the police any of that stuff?
- I did not.
- 警察にそのことについて何か話しましたか? - 話していません。
Entschuldigen Sie, wenn ich Sie schockiere, aber Tatsache ist, dass er nur bekommen hat, was er verdient hat.
Sorry if I shock you, but the plain fact is, he only got what he deserved.
驚かせたら申し訳ないが、明白な事実は、彼は当然の報いを受けただけだということだ。
So, jetzt ist es gesagt.
There, I've said it.
はい、言いましたよ。
Ich muss ständig an diese Mädchen denken. Die, die, weißt du ...
I can't stop thinkin' about those girls.
The ones that got, you know...
私はあの女の子たちのことを考えずにはいられない。あの子たちは、あの子たちは…
Es überrascht mich nicht, wie Sie weitermachen.
I'm not surprised, the way you carry on.
あなたのやり方には驚きません。
Sorgen Sie einfach dafür, dass Ihnen das nie passiert, das ist alles.
Just see it never happens to you, that's all.
あなたには決してそんなことが起こらないように気をつけてください。それだけです。
Das wird es nicht... Und selbst wenn es so wäre, weiß ich, dass ich mich nicht von meinem Baby trennen könnte,
It won't... And even if it did,
I know I couldn't part with my baby,
そんなことはないだろう...たとえそうなったとしても、私は赤ちゃんと別れることはできないとわかっている。
nicht nur, um einen Job zu behalten. not just to hang on to a job.
単に仕事を続けるためだけではありません。
Das freut mich sehr zu hören.
I'm very glad to hear it.
とても嬉しいです。
Wer ist es?
Who is it?
誰だ？
Nein, kümmern Sie sich nicht um mich, Mr. Jennings.
No, don't mind me, Mr. Jennings.
いいえ、気にしないでください、ジェニングスさん。
Inspektor Thompson hat mich gerade gebeten, einen letzten Blick darauf zu werfen.
Inspector Thompson's just asked me to take one last look round.
トンプソン警部が私に最後にもう一度見回すように言ったんです。
Ist der Inspektor bei Ihnen?
Is the inspector with you?
検査官は同行していますか?
Nein, wir arbeiten ab sofort vom Bahnhof aus.
No, we're working from the station from now on.
いいえ、これからは駅から仕事になります。
Mal sehen, ob wir die Dinge von dort aus nicht besser in den Griff bekommen.
See if we can't manage things better from there.
そこから物事をもっとうまく管理できないか考えてみましょう。
Was ist mit dem Gift? Konnten Sie es wenigstens aufspüren?
What about the poison?
Have you traced that at least?
毒物についてはどうですか？少なくともそれを追跡しましたか？
Wohl kaum. Dieses Haus ist ein Paradies für Giftmörder.
Hardly.
This house is a poisoner's paradise.
そんなことはない。この家は毒殺者にとって天国だ。
Wir haben das Zeug praktisch überall gefunden...
We found the stuff in practically ev...
ほとんどすべての場所でその商品を見つけました...
...jedes Zimmer.
...every room.
...すべての部屋。
Leider liegt keiner der Beteiligten vor.
Unfortunately, no one's got a police record.
残念ながら、誰も警察記録を持っていません。
Na ja, außer Ihnen natürlich.
Well, except you, of course.
まあ、もちろんあなたを除いてね。
Vielleicht war es der Butler.
Perhaps the butler did it.
おそらく執事がやったのでしょう。
Ich hatte einen Bruder, der Kriegsdienstverweigerer war.
I had a brother who was a conscientious objector.
私には良心的兵役拒否者の兄がいました。
Er hat auch eine Weile gesessen.
He did a bit of time too.
彼も少しだけ刑務所にいました。
Wussten sie da oben, dass Sie sich geweigert hatten zu kämpfen und ins Gefängnis geschickt wurden?
Did they know upstairs you refused to fight and were sent to prison?
あなたが戦うことを拒否して刑務所に送られたことを上の階の人たちは知っていたのですか？
Ich würde es an deiner Stelle vergessen.
I'd forget about it if I were you.
もし私があなただったら、それを忘れてしまうでしょう。
Nicht jeder ist zum Soldaten geeignet.
Not everyone's cut out to be a soldier.
誰もが兵士に向いているわけではない。
- Haben Sie an die anderen Kisten gedacht? - Alles ist im Auto, Mylady.
- Did you remember the other boxes?
- Everything's in the car, milady.
- 他の箱は覚えていますか? - すべて車の中にあります、お嬢様。
Wunderbar. Gut.
Wonderful. Good.
素晴らしい。よかった。
Liebling, ich komme.
Darling, here I come.
ダーリン、行くよ。
Weißt du, ich kann es kaum erwarten, diesen Ort zu verlassen.
Do you know?
I can't wait to leave this place.
知ってますか？ここから早く出たいんです。
Herrgott, was sollen wir jetzt tun?
Christ, what are we supposed to do now?
ああ、私たちはこれから何をすればいいのでしょうか？
Freddie, versuch, nicht die ganze Zeit so viel Angst zu haben.
Freddie, do try to stop being so frightened all the time.
フレディ、いつもそんなに怖がるのはやめてください。
Liebling, habe ich mich furchtbar zum Narren gemacht?
Darling, have I made the most terrible fool of myself?
ダーリン、私は自分自身を最もひどい愚か者にしてしまったのでしょうか？
- Vielleicht. - Anthony, ähm ...
- Maybe.
- Anthony, erm...
- 多分。 - アンソニー、えーと...
- Nur, ähm ... - Oh, Gott.
- Just, erm...
- Oh, God.
- ただ、えーと... - ああ、神様。
Ich wollte Sie an das Gespräch erinnern, das wir neulich beim Abendessen hatten.
I wanted to remind you of the conversation we had at dinner the other night.
先日の夕食のときに交わした会話を思い出してもらいたいと思いました。
Vielleicht ist dies nicht der beste Moment,
Perhaps this is not the most appropriate moment,
おそらくこれは最も適切な瞬間ではないだろうが、
aber wenn Sie in den Sudan kommen, brauchen Sie einen Experten, und ich bin Ihr Mann. but when you get to the Sudan you'll need an expert, and I'm your man.
しかし、スーダンに着いたら専門家が必要になります。そして、私がその専門家です。
- ...findet heraus, dass ich nicht angemeldet bin. - Ich möchte wissen ...
- ...finds out I haven't been signed up.
- I want to know...
- ...登録されていないことがわかりました。 - 知りたいのですが...
- Hast du sie gefragt? - Nein, habe ich nicht.
- Did you ask her?
- No, I didn't.
- 彼女に尋ねましたか? - いいえ、尋ねていません。
Ich denke, im Nachhinein ist das eine gute Sache.
I think, on reflection, that's a good thing.
よく考えてみると、それは良いことだと思います。
Dem Klatsch in der Dienerhalle zufolge
According to the servants' hall gossip,
使用人の部屋の噂によると、
Sie wird nichts von ihrem Nachlass bekommen, bis ihre Mutter stirbt. she won't get any of her estate till her mother dies.
彼女は母親が亡くなるまで財産を一切受け取ることができない。
Wenn das der Fall ist, können Sie nicht mehr lange warten. Sie können es besser machen.
If that's the case, it's too long for you to wait. You can do better.
もしそうなら、待つには長すぎます。もっと良い方法がありますよ。
Haben Sie Ihr Zimmer überprüft?
Have you checked your room?
部屋は確認しましたか？
Sie dürfen nichts zurücklassen.
You mustn't leave anything behind.
何も残してはいけません。
Ich bin sicher, Mama wird das Haus verkaufen.
I'm sure Mummy's going to sell the house.
ママはきっと家を売るつもりよ。
Isobel. Isobel. Isobel!
イザベル。イザベル。イザベル！
Sidney Kent übernimmt das Studio.
Sidney Kent's taking over the studio.
シドニー・ケントがスタジオを引き継ぎます。
Er liebt Charlie Chan und er hasst Winfield Sheehan.
He loves Charlie Chan and he hates Winfield Sheehan.
彼はチャーリー・チャンが大好きで、ウィンフィールド・シーハンが嫌いです。
Keine Umschreibungen mehr und ich kann besetzen, wen ich will.
No more rewrites, and I can cast whoever I like.
もう脚本を書き直す必要はなく、好きな人をキャストできます。
- Nun, das war schmerzlos, nicht wahr? - Nein, war es nicht.
- Well, that was painless, wasn't it?
- No, it wasn't.
- まあ、痛みはなかったですね？ - いいえ、痛みはありませんでした。
Jedenfalls nicht für mich.
Not for me, anyway.
少なくとも私にとってはそうではない。
Vorsicht, Vorsicht. Passen Sie auf sich auf!
Careful, careful. Watch yourself!
気をつけて、気をつけて。気をつけて！
- Wissen sie es? - Nein.
- Do they know?
- No.
- 彼らは知っていますか？ - いいえ。
- Glaubst du nicht, dass sie es bemerken könnten? - Das ist mir egal.
- Don't you think they might notice?
- I don't care.
- 気付かれるとは思わないの？ - 気にしないよ。
Hey, du da. Wo gehst du hin?
Hey, you there.
Where you going?
やあ、君。どこに行くの？
- Der Bahnhof. - Hey, willst du nach London mitfahren?
- The station.
- Hey, you want a ride to London?
- 駅です。 - ねえ、ロンドンまで乗せて行かない？
Sicher. Warum nicht?
Sure. Why not?
もちろんです。なぜダメなのですか？
- Steigen Sie ein. - Danke.
- Hop in.
- Thank you.
- 乗ってください。 - ありがとう。
Da haben Sie es.
There you go.
そうです。
Also, viel Glück. Tu nichts, was ich nicht tun würde.
Well, good luck.
Don't do anything I wouldn't do.
まあ、頑張ってください。私がやらないようなことはしないでください。
Zumindest weiß ich, dass mir das Handlungsspielraum gibt.
At least I know that gives me room for maneuver.
少なくとも、それが私に行動の余地を与えることはわかっています。
Nein, behalte deine Hände bei dir.
No, keep your hands to yourself.
いいえ、手を触れないでください。
Ihr Briten habt wirklich keinen Sinn für Humor, oder?
You Brits really don't have a sense of humor, do you?
あなたたちイギリス人は本当にユーモアのセンスがないですね。
Das tun wir, wenn etwas komisch ist, Sir.
We do if something's funny, sir.
何か面白いことがあればそうしますよ、先生。
- Mr. Jennings, kann ich...? - Beeilen Sie sich.
- Mr. Jennings, can I...?
- Be quick about it.
- ジェニングスさん、...してもいいですか？ - 急いでください。
Ehrlich gesagt, es wird so teuer,
Honestly, it's getting so expensive,
正直、すごく高くなってきているんです
bis man Jennings macht und etwas für die Hausmädchen übrig lässt, by the time one does Jennings and leave something for the housemaids,
ジェニングスを終えてメイドに何か残す頃には、
man hätte genauso gut eine Suite im Ritz nehmen können. one might as well have taken a suite at the Ritz.
リッツのスイートルームに泊まったのと同じようなものだった。
Sag mir, was ist mit Williams kleinem Dienstmädchen passiert?
Tell me, what happened to William's little maid?
教えてください、ウィリアムの小さなメイドに何が起こったのですか?
Ich habe sie nach diesem Abendessen nie wieder gesehen.
I never saw her again after that dinner.
その夕食の後、私は彼女に二度と会うことはなかった。
- Elsie?
- Mmm.
- エルシー？ - うーん。
- Sie ist weg. - Oh. Schade, wirklich.
- She's gone.
- Oh. Pity, really.
- 彼女はいなくなった。 - ああ。本当に残念だ。
Ich hätte gedacht, es wäre eine gute Idee gewesen, jemanden im Haus zu haben
I'd have thought it was a good idea to have someone in the house
家に誰かいるのはいい考えだと思う
dem es tatsächlich leid tut, dass er tot ist. who's actually sorry he's dead.
彼が死んだことを本当に残念に思っている人。
Oh, da bist du ja, Liebes. Hattest du eine schöne Fahrt?
Oh, there you are, dear.
Did you have a nice ride?
ああ、そこにいたのね。楽しいドライブでしたか？
Ich fühle mich ziemlich schuldig. Anscheinend sind alle weg.
I'm feeling rather guilty.
Apparently everyone's gone.
かなり罪悪感を感じています。どうやらみんないなくなってしまったようです。
Außer dir und Louisa.
Apart from you and Louisa.
あなたとルイザを除いて。
- Warum bleibst du nicht zum Mittagessen? - Nein, ich gehe lieber. Lass dich in Ruhe.
- Why don't you stay for lunch?
- No, best be off. Leave you in peace.
- 昼食まで残ってはいかがですか? - いや、もう行ってしまった方がいい。君を静かにさせておこう。
Sie werden jetzt wegen der Bestattungspläne anrufen, hmm?
Now, you will telephone about the funeral plans, hmm?
さて、葬儀の予定について電話するんですね？
- Wenn es langweilig ist, musst du nicht kommen. - Unsinn. Natürlich komme ich.
- You don't have to come if it's a bore.
- Nonsense. Of course I'm coming.
- 退屈なら来なくていいよ。 - 馬鹿馬鹿しい。もちろん行くよ。
Haben Sie entschieden, was Sie mit diesem Ort machen werden?
Have you decided what you're going to do about this place?
この場所をどうするか決めましたか?
- Oh, ich weiß nicht. - Wirst du es behalten?
- Oh, I don't know.
- Will you keep it?
- ああ、分からない。 - 取っておくの？
Es ist so schwierig.
It's so difficult.
とても難しいです。
Ich meine, will man sich heutzutage wirklich die Mühe machen?
I mean, does one really want the bother nowadays?
つまり、今どき、本当に面倒なことを望む人がいるでしょうか?
Oh, ich schätze, ich könnte die Klappe halten
Oh, I suppose I could shut it up
ああ、黙っててもいいかな
und eine Entscheidung treffen, wenn mir der Kopf nicht mehr schwirrt. and make a decision when my head stops spinning.
頭の回転が止まったら決断を下します。
Mrs. Wilson könnte es schaffen, bis Sie bereit sind.
Mrs. Wilson could manage till you're ready.
あなたが準備ができるまで、ウィルソン夫人が対応します。
Oh ja, sie würde es schaffen. Machen wir uns darüber keine Sorgen.
Oh, yes, she could manage, alright.
Let's not worry about that.
ああ、そうだ、彼女はなんとかできるよ。そのことについては心配しないで。
Zweifellos wird sie die Gelegenheit nutzen, um die elende Mrs. Croft loszuwerden.
No doubt she'll seize the opportunity to get rid of the wretched Mrs. Croft.
彼女は間違いなく、この機会を利用して、この哀れなクロフト夫人を追い出すだろう。
- Warum sind die beiden solche Feinde? - Ich weiß es nicht.
- Why are those two such enemies?
- I don't know.
- なぜあの二人はそんなに敵対しているのですか？ - 分かりません。
Es hatte etwas damit zu tun, dass sie beide in einer von Williams Ausbeuterwerkstätten gearbeitet hatten.
Something to do with when they were both workers in one of William's sweatshops.
それは、彼らが二人ともウィリアムの劣悪な労働環境の工場で働いていた頃のことと関係があります。
Mrs. Croft war damals die Älteste. Sie war die Köchin.
Mrs. Croft was the senior then.
She was the cook.
クロフト夫人は当時上級生で、料理を担当していました。
Und Mrs. Wilson, eine einfache Fabrikarbeiterin.
And Mrs. Wilson, a lowly factory worker.
そして、低い地位の工場労働者であるウィルソン夫人。
Jetzt, wo sie es in die Welt geschafft hat, kann die arme alte Croftie es nicht mehr ertragen.
Now that she's got up in the world, poor old Croftie can't abide it.
今では彼女は社会に出て成功しているが、かわいそうなクロフティはそれに耐えられない。
Der übliche Blödsinn.
The usual rubbish.
いつものゴミ。
Gab es jemals einen Mr. Wilson? Ich kann es mir nicht vorstellen.
Was there ever a Mr. Wilson?
I can't imagine it.
ウィルソン氏なんて存在したのでしょうか？想像もつきません。
Ich konnte es auch nicht.
Nor could I.
私もそうでした。
Obwohl ich komischerweise glaube, dass es das gegeben haben muss.
Although, funnily enough,
I think there must've been.
でも、おかしなことに、そうだったに違いないと思う。
Wirklich? Du verblüffst mich.
Really? You amaze me.
本当ですか？驚きました。
Sie könnte ihren Namen geändert haben,
She might've changed her name,
彼女は名前を変えたかもしれない、
aber als sie mit William arbeitete, but when she was working with William,
しかし、彼女がウィリアムと一緒に働いていたとき、
sie wurde ganz anders genannt... she was called something quite different...
彼女はまったく違う名前で呼ばれていました...
Parks oder Parker oder Parkinson oder so ähnlich.
Parks or Parker or Parkinson, or something like that.
パークスとかパーカーとかパーキンソンとか、そんな感じ。
Komm herein!
Come in.
お入りください。
- Sie sind beschäftigt. - Nein, ich überprüfe nur den Wäschewechsel.
- You're busy.
- No, just checking the linen rotation.
- 忙しいのですね。 - いいえ、リネンのローテーションをチェックしているだけです。
Wenn ich es den Zimmermädchen überlassen hätte, wären dieselben zwanzig Laken verwendet worden
If I'd have left it to the maids, the same twenty sheets would be used
メイドに任せていたなら、同じ20枚のシートが使われていただろう
bis sie in Lumpen zerfielen. till they fell into rags.
ぼろぼろになるまで。
Warum hast du das getan?
Why did you do it?
なぜそれをしたのですか？
Woher wussten Sie, dass er es war?
How did you know it was him?
どうして彼だと分かったのですか？
War es der Name oder haben Sie das Foto in seinem Zimmer gesehen?
Was it the name, or did you see the photograph in his room?
それは名前ですか、それとも彼の部屋にあった写真を見たのですか?
Ah, ja, das Foto.
Ah, yes, the photograph.
ああ、そうそう、写真ね。
Es ist ein Wunder, dass es überlebt hat. Ich erinnere mich, wie seine Mutter es in seine Decke legte.
It's a miracle that survived. I remember his mother putting it into his blanket.
生き残ったのは奇跡です。お母さんが毛布の中に入れてくれたのを覚えています。
Ich nehme an, sie wollte, dass er etwas von ihr bekommt.
I suppose she wanted him to have something of hers.
彼女は彼に自分のものを少し与えたかったのだと思います。
Weiß er, was mit ihr passiert ist?
Does he know what happened to her?
彼は彼女に何が起こったのか知っていますか？
Sie sagten, sie sei kurz nach seiner Geburt gestorben.
They said she died just after he was born.
彼女は彼が生まれた直後に亡くなったそうです。
Nun, sie ist nicht gestorben. Sie hat ihn weggegeben.
Well, she didn't die.
She gave him away.
まあ、彼女は死んでいません。彼女は彼を手放したのです。
Er versprach, dass der Junge adoptiert würde. Er sagte, er kenne die Familie.
He promised the boy would be adopted.
He said he knew the family.
彼は少年を養子に出すと約束した。彼はその家族を知っていると言った。
Es stellte sich heraus, dass wir alle an diesem Traum festhielten, alle Mädchen.
Turns out we all clung to that dream, all us girls.
結局、私たち女の子全員がその夢にしがみついていたのです。
Ein besserer Start ins Leben für unsere Kinder.
A better start in life for our children.
子どもたちの人生のより良いスタート。
Und die ganze Zeit ließ er sie im Stich, seine eigenen Kinder,
And all the time, he was dumping them, his own children,
そして彼はずっと、自分の子供たちを捨てていたのです
an einem gottverlassenen Ort. in some godforsaken place.
どこか見捨てられた場所で。
Und ich habe ihm geglaubt. Ich schätze, so war es einfacher.
And I believed him.
I suppose it was easier that way.
そして私は彼を信じました。その方が簡単だったと思います。
Meine Schwester hat mir das jedenfalls nie verziehen.
My sister certainly never forgave me for it.
姉は絶対に私を許してくれなかった。
Deine Schwester?
Your sister?
あなたの妹？
Ja, Mrs. Croft. Sie ist meine Schwester. Wussten Sie das nicht?
Yes, Mrs. Croft. She's my sister.
Didn't you know?
はい、クロフト夫人。彼女は私の妹です。知らなかったのですか？
Sie hat ihres behalten, wissen Sie.
She kept hers, you see.
彼女は自分のものを保管していたのです。
Es war sehr hart für sie. Sie verlor ihren Job und dann starb das Baby trotzdem.
It was very hard for her. She lost her job, and then the baby died anyway.
彼女にとってそれはとてもつらいことでした。彼女は仕事を失い、その上赤ちゃんも亡くなってしまったのです。
Scharlach.
Scarlet fever.
猩紅熱。
Ich habe ihn dazu gebracht, sie zurückzunehmen. Auch das hat sie mir nie verziehen.
I made him take her back.
She never forgave me for that either.
私は彼に彼女を連れて帰るように言いました。彼女はそのことについても決して私を許しませんでした。
Aber selbst wenn Robert dein Sohn ist,
But even if Robert is your son,
しかし、ロバートがあなたの息子だとしても、
woher wussten Sie, dass er seinem Vater etwas antun wollte? how did you know that he meant to harm his father?
彼が父親を傷つけるつもりだったとどうして分かったのですか？
Welche Gabe hat Ihrer Meinung nach ein guter Diener, die ihn von den anderen unterscheidet?
What gift do you think a good servant has that separates them from the others?
良い召使いが他の召使いと異なる才能を持っているとあなたは思いますか。
Es ist das Geschenk der Vorfreude.
It's the gift of anticipation.
それは期待の賜物です。
Und ich bin ein guter Diener. Ich bin besser als gut, ich bin der Beste.
And I'm a good servant.
I'm better than good, I'm the best.
そして私は良い召使です。私は良いというより、最高です。
Ich bin der perfekte Diener.
I'm the perfect servant.
私は完璧な召使いです。
Ich weiß, wann sie hungrig sind und das Essen fertig ist.
I know when they'll be hungry, and the food is ready.
彼らがお腹が空くとすぐに食事の準備が整います。
Ich weiß, wann sie müde sind und das Bett aufgeschlagen wird.
I know when they'll be tired, and the bed is turned down.
彼らが疲れているときはベッドが倒されるのが分かります。
Ich weiß es, bevor sie es selbst wissen.
I know it before they know it themselves.
彼ら自身が知る前に、私は知っています。
Wirst du es ihm sagen?
Are you going to tell him?
彼に伝えるつもりですか？
Warum? Welchem ​​Zweck könnte es dienen?
Why? What purpose would it possibly serve?
なぜですか? それは一体何の役に立つのでしょうか?
Was ist, wenn sie herausfinden, was passiert ist?
What if they find out what happened?
何が起こったのかが分かったらどうしますか?
Es ist kein großes Verbrechen, einen Toten zu erstechen, oder?
Not much of a crime to stab a dead man, is it?
死んだ人を刺すのは大した犯罪ではないですよね？
Sie dürfen ihn niemals berühren. Das ist, was zählt: sein Leben.
They can never touch him.
That's what's important, his life.
彼らは決して彼に触れることはできない。大切なのは彼の命だ。
Und dein Leben?
And your life?
そしてあなたの人生は？
Hast du mich nicht gehört? Ich bin der perfekte Diener, ich habe kein Leben.
Didn't you hear me?
I'm the perfect servant, I have no life.
聞こえなかったのか？私は完璧な召使いだ、命はない。
- Ihre Ladyschaft geht jetzt, Miss. - Danke, George.
- Her Ladyship's leaving now, Miss.
- Thank you, George.
- 夫人は今出発されます、お嬢さん。 - ありがとう、ジョージ。
Nun, Sie sollten jetzt gehen, Miss Trentham.
Well, you should go now,
Miss Trentham.
さて、トレンサムさん、もう行ってください。
- Hier, Jennings. - Auf Wiedersehen, Sylvia.
- Here you are, Jennings.
- Goodbye, Sylvia.
- ジェニングスさん、いらっしゃいました。 - さようなら、シルビア。
Danke schön.
Thank you.
ありがとう。
Lassen Sie uns wissen, wenn wir Ihnen irgendwie helfen können.
Do let us know if there's anything that we can do to help.
何かお手伝いできることがありましたら、お知らせください。
Gehst du weg?
Are you going away?
どこかに行ってしまうんですか？
Nein, nicht wenn die Dreharbeiten beendet sind.
No, not once the shooting's finished.
いいえ、撮影が終わったらそうはなりません。
- Danke für Ihre Hilfe letzte Nacht. - Sie müssen mir nicht danken.
- Thank you for your help last night.
- You don't have to thank me.
- 昨晩は助けてくれてありがとう。 - 感謝しなくてもいいよ。
Sie wissen, dass ich für Mr. Jennings töten würde, wenn es sein müsste.
You know I'd kill for Mr. Jennings if I had to.
ジェニングス氏のためなら、私は殺人もいとわないでしょう。
Weine nicht, Jane. Sie werden dich hören.
Don't cry, Jane. They'll hear you.
泣かないで、ジェーン。みんなあなたの声が聞こえるよ。
Aufleuchten.
Come on.
来て。
Sie haben getan, was Ihrer Meinung nach zu diesem Zeitpunkt das Beste für ihn war.
You did what you felt was best for him at the time.
あなたはその時、彼にとって最善だと思ったことをしたのです。
Das sehe ich jetzt.
I see that now.
分かりました。
Lizzie...
リジー…
Ich habe ihn verloren.
I've lost him.
彼と会えなくなってしまった。
Ich habe ihn verloren. Er wird mich nie wieder kennen.
I've lost him.
He'll never know me now.
私は彼を失った。彼はもう私のことを知ることはないだろう。
Oh, mein Junge!
Oh, my boy!
ああ、私の息子よ！
Na ja, zumindest ist Ihr Junge am Leben.
Well, at least your boy's alive.
まあ、少なくとも君の息子は生きている。
Er lebt.
He's alive.
彼は生きている。
Das ist, was zählt.
That's what matters.
それが重要なのです。
Also, du gehst.
So, you're leaving.
それで、あなたは去るのです。
Ja.
Yes.
はい。
Dann auf Wiedersehen.
Goodbye, then.
それでは、さようなら。
Auf Wiedersehen.
Goodbye.
さようなら。
Parks...
公園...
- Steig ein, Bennett. - Kopf hoch, Kopf hoch.
- Get in, Bennett.
- Chin up, chin up.
- 乗れ、ベネット。 - 元気を出せ、元気を出せ。
Himmel! Was für eine Erleichterung, dass ich gehen kann. Ich werde einen Monat brauchen, um mich zu erholen.
Heavens! What a relief to be going.
It'll take me a month to recover.
ああ！もう行けてホッとしています。回復するには1ヶ月かかります。
Oh, Mary, Liebes,
Oh, Mary, dear,
ああ、メアリー、
glauben Sie, dass ich im Falle einer Verhandlung vor Gericht aussagen müsste? do you think if there's a trial,
I might have to testify in court?
裁判になったら、私は法廷で証言しなければならないと思いますか？
Oder du?
Or you?
それともあなた？
Ich kann mir nichts Schlimmeres vorstellen.
I can't think of anything worse.
これより悪いことは考えられません。
Stellen Sie sich vor, jemand wird gehängt, weil er vor Gericht etwas gesagt hat.
Imagine a person being hanged because of something one said in court.
法廷で何か言ったせいで絞首刑に処せられる人を想像してください。
Ich weiß. Und welchem ​​Zweck könnte es überhaupt dienen?
I know. And what purpose could it possibly serve anyway?
わかっています。そもそも、それが何の役に立つのでしょうか?
Auf Wiedersehen!
Goodbye!
さようなら！
♪ Irgendwo gibt es ein anderes Land
♪ Somewhere there's another land
♪ どこかに別の土地がある
♪ Anders als diese Welt unten
♪ Different from this world below
♪ 下界とは違う
♪ Weitaus gnädiger geplant
♪ Far more mercifully planned
♪ はるかに慈悲深く計画された
♪ Als der grausame Ort, den wir kennen
♪ Than the cruel place we know
♪私たちが知っている残酷な場所よりも
♪ Unschuld und Frieden sind da
♪ Innocence and peace are there
♪ そこには無邪気さと平和がある
♪ Alles ist gut, was gewünscht wird
♪ All is good that is desired
♪ 望まれるものはすべて良い
♪ Die Gesichter dort sind immer fair
♪ Faces there are always fair
♪ そこの顔はいつも美しい
♪ Die Liebe wird nie alt oder müde
♪ Love grows never old nor tired
♪ 愛は決して古びず、飽きることもない
♪ Wir werden nie finden
♪ We shall never find
♪私たちは決して見つけられない
♪ Dieses schöne Land des Was-wäre-wenn
♪ That lovely land of Might-Have-Been
♪ ありえたかもしれない素敵な国
♪ Ich kann niemals dein König sein
♪ I can never be your king
♪ 私はあなたの王にはなれない
♪ Du kannst auch nicht meine Königin sein
♪ Nor you can be my queen
♪ あなたは私の女王にはなれない
♪ Tage können vergehen und Jahre können vergehen
♪ Days may pass and years may pass
♪日が経ち、年が経つかもしれない
♪ Und Meere können zwischen
♪ And seas may lie between
♪そして海は
♪ Wir werden nie finden
♪ We shall never find
♪私たちは決して見つけられない
♪ Dieses schöne Land des Was-hätte-sein-könnens ... ♪
♪ That lovely land of Might-Have-Been... ♪
♪ あの素敵な「あったかもしれない国」… ♪